<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Culture on AFUO - СУОА</title>
    <link>https://ozeukes.com/categories/culture/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Culture on AFUO - СУОА</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 06 Jul 2017 12:35:04 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://ozeukes.com/categories/culture/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Ukrainian arts festival twirls into Melbourne this weekend</title>
      <link>https://ozeukes.com/events/victoria/ukrainian-arts-festival-twirls-into-melbourne-this-weekend/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Jul 2017 12:35:04 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ozeukes.com/events/victoria/ukrainian-arts-festival-twirls-into-melbourne-this-weekend/</guid>
      <description>6 July 2017
MEDIA RELEASE Ukrainian arts festival twirls into Melbourne this weekend
A colourful festival of culture, dance and song will take over Melbourne’s Ukrainian precinct in Essendon and Melbourne Town Hall this weekend — Friday 7 to Sunday 9 July.
Sunday’s Gala Concert at the Melbourne Town Hall at 1.30pm will see over 300 performers from around Australia showcasing Ukrainian song and dance.
Every four years the Australian Federation of Ukrainian Organisations (AFUO) organises a weekend of events for all to enjoy, showcasing Ukraine’s rich traditions and produce.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>XV National Ukrainian Festival – Zdvyh</title>
      <link>https://ozeukes.com/events/xv-national-ukrainian-festival-zdvyh/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Jun 2017 23:04:43 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ozeukes.com/events/xv-national-ukrainian-festival-zdvyh/</guid>
      <description>XV NATIONAL UKRAINIAN CONFERENCE – ZDVYH 7th – 9th July, Melbourne
The Australian Federation of Ukrainian Organisations proudly announces that all roads will lead to Melbourne this July as Ukrainians from all over Australia travel to the world’s most liveable city for the XV National Ukrainian Festival – Zdvyh.
Held every four years, the Zdvyh will bring together Australian Ukrainians of all ages and from all walks of life. They will come together to celebrate their language, culture and identity and to launch a two-year program of national celebrations commemorating 70 years of post-WW2 settlement in Australia.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>2017 Piers Festival</title>
      <link>https://ozeukes.com/culture/2017-piers-festival/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Apr 2017 11:07:10 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ozeukes.com/culture/2017-piers-festival/</guid>
      <description>**Multicultural Arts Victoria is excited to announce **the free 2017 Piers Festival Media Release April 2017
Multicultural Arts Victoria (MAV) is excited to announce the 6th Piers Festival on 9 April at Princes Pier, Port Melbourne. The annual free Piers Festival features a vibrant mix of artists and cultures, iconic sounds, new collaborations, music, dance and activities for all ages with headline acts Joe Camilleri &amp;amp; the Black Sorrows,** the Core-tet, Oi Dipnoi, the haBiBis, Mojo Juju &amp;amp; the Samoan Choir.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Governor’s Multicultural Awards - 2 big wins for the Ukrainian community</title>
      <link>https://ozeukes.com/culture/governors-multicultural-awards-2-big-wins-for-the-ukrainian-community/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Mar 2017 06:20:50 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ozeukes.com/culture/governors-multicultural-awards-2-big-wins-for-the-ukrainian-community/</guid>
      <description>The presentation of 2016 Governor’s Multicultural awards was held on Tuesday 21 March on the grounds of Government House. A large crowd of more than 400 people – see photo - attended this ceremony. The attendees included the Lieutenant Governor of South Australia, Professor Brenda Wilson; Jay Weatherill, Premier of South Australia; Hon Zoe Bettison, MP, Minister of Multicultural Affairs; Hon Jing Lee MLC, Shadow Parliamentary Secretary for Multicultural Affairs – representing the Leader of the Opposition; Hon Michael Atkinson, Speaker of the House of Assembly; several state MPs; Martin Haese, Lord Mayor of Adelaide; the mayors of nine city councils; and the heads of most ethnic community associations.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Shevchenko concert and visual presentation - South Australia</title>
      <link>https://ozeukes.com/events/shevchenko-concert-and-visual-presentation-sa/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Mar 2017 07:07:21 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ozeukes.com/events/shevchenko-concert-and-visual-presentation-sa/</guid>
      <description>The Shevchenko concert-cabaret held on Sunday 12 March was a great success. About 250 people attended this event. Attending our concert were Peter Malinauskas MLC, David Pisoni MP, Michael Atkinson MP, Jennifer Rankine MP, Hon. Grace Portolesi, Angela Evans - Mayor of the City of Charles Sturt, and the presidents of the Belarus, Croatian, German, Hungarian, Latvian, Lithuanian, Scottish and Spanish associations. Very positive comments were made by all and especially the Croatian, German, Lithuanian and Scottish presidents.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Stalin’s forced famine: Melbourne pensioner Fedir Habelko recalls brutal regime in Ukraine</title>
      <link>https://ozeukes.com/politics/stalins-forced-famine-melbourne-pensioner-fedir-habelko-recalls-brutal-regime-in-ukraine/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Feb 2017 09:51:38 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ozeukes.com/politics/stalins-forced-famine-melbourne-pensioner-fedir-habelko-recalls-brutal-regime-in-ukraine/</guid>
      <description>WHEN Fedir Habelko was a young teenager in his native Ukraine in the early 1930s he witnessed one of the greatest crimes of the 20th century.
Millions of people died when Soviet Union dictator Joseph Stalin unleashed a forced famine in a bid to bring the occupied nation to heel.
Known to Ukrainians as the Holodomor, Communist authorities went to extreme lengths to stop people getting food under a ruthless policy to force peasants into collective farms.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Художній фільм “Bitter Harvest” (“Гіркі жнива”) — сумний спомин для місцевих мешканців Вікторії, які пережили Голодомор</title>
      <link>https://ozeukes.com/politics/feature-film-bitter-harvest-a-sad-reminder-for-local-victorian-holodomor-survivors-ukr/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Feb 2017 05:39:04 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ozeukes.com/politics/feature-film-bitter-harvest-a-sad-reminder-for-local-victorian-holodomor-survivors-ukr/</guid>
      <description>17 лютого 2017
ПРЕС-РЕЛІЗ
Художній фільм “Bitter Harvest ” (“Гіркі жнива”) — сумний спомин для місцевих мешканців Вікторії, які пережили Голодомор Відображаючи страшний геноцид – Голодомор в Україні початку 1930-их років, прем&#39;єра історичної драми “Bitter Harvest” в Австралії є болючим, але важливим нагадуванням про минуле для тих небагатьох сучасних мешканців Вікторії, які пережили ті часи.
99-річний Федір Габелко досі пам&#39;ятає той жах, свідком якого він був у дитинстві. Він на собі відчув жорстоке доручення Сталіна колективізувати українські господарства для створення голоду і одночасного зламу національної гідності.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Feature film Bitter Harvest a sad reminder for local Victorian Holodomor survivors</title>
      <link>https://ozeukes.com/politics/feature-film-bitter-harvest-a-sad-reminder-for-local-victorian-holodomor-survivors/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Feb 2017 21:51:25 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ozeukes.com/politics/feature-film-bitter-harvest-a-sad-reminder-for-local-victorian-holodomor-survivors/</guid>
      <description>17 February 2017
MEDIA RELEASE
Feature film Bitter Harvest a sad reminder for local Victorian Holodomor survivors Set in early 1930s Ukraine amidst the horrific famine-genocide referred to as the Holodomor (death by starvation), the Australian premiere of historical drama Bitter Harvest is a painful but important reminder of their past for the few remaining Victorian-based survivors.
Today 99-year-old Fedir Habelko hasn’t forgotten the atrocities he witnessed as a child. He experienced first-hand Stalin’s ruthless mission to collectivise Ukrainian farms leading to forced starvation, breaking national pride in the process.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Holodomor drama in cinemas Feb 23 / Драма про Голодомор - в кінотеатрах 23-лютого</title>
      <link>https://ozeukes.com/culture/holodomor-drama-in-cinemas-feb-23/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Jan 2017 11:40:35 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ozeukes.com/culture/holodomor-drama-in-cinemas-feb-23/</guid>
      <description>Historical drama _Bitter Harvest _is a love story set amidst Ukraine’s devastating Holodomor.
Starring Max Irons (Red Riding Hood, Woman in Gold), Samantha Barks (Les Miserables), Terence Stamp (The Adventures of Priscilla, Queen of the Desert) and Barry Pepper (Saving Private Ryan, The Green Mile), the film was shot on location in Ukraine and is the first major dramatic picture to convey the untold story of Europe’s most overlooked tragedies of the 20th century.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Yevshan - Winners – National Dance KAR Dance Competition 2016</title>
      <link>https://ozeukes.com/events/yevshan-winners-national-dance-kar-dance-competition-2016/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Nov 2016 06:24:26 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ozeukes.com/events/yevshan-winners-national-dance-kar-dance-competition-2016/</guid>
      <description>On 29 October 2016, two of Yevshan dance ensemble groups participated in a National Dance KAR competition, winning 8 awards and “All Stars” Title – see photos below – and received an invitation to attend the New York City Dance Experience in July 2017. The competition was held in Michael Murray Performing Arts Centre at Westminster School. The judges were from New York, Los Angeles and Sydney.
Competing in the National Dance KAR competition were professional dance companies such as SA Performing Arts, Xcel Dance studios, Pivotal Dance, Precizion Dance, TIDC Performing Arts Studio and Thats Dancing and more.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>BITTER HARVEST / ГІРКІ ЖНИВА - HOLODOMOR / ГОЛОДОМОР 1932/33</title>
      <link>https://ozeukes.com/culture/bitter-harvest-holodomor-1932-33/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 03 Nov 2016 11:44:10 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ozeukes.com/culture/bitter-harvest-holodomor-1932-33/</guid>
      <description>UWC and AFUO announcing that negotiations have commenced with the major donor of the film Ian Hnatowycz and the international distributors about the 2017 International launch of the film. It was agreed we will work in partnership to ensure its wide exposure. A major event will be held in Kyiv on November 24, 2016 to launch the film in Ukraine to coincide with Holodomor Commemorations.
СКУ та СУОА оголошують, що розпочалися переговори з основним донором фільму Ян Гнатовичом і міжнародними дистриб&#39;юторами міжнародну прем&#39;єру фільму у 2017 роws.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cossack Brothers 20th Anniversary - Gala Cabaret Evening</title>
      <link>https://ozeukes.com/events/cossack-brothers-20th-anniversary-gala-cabaret-evening/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Oct 2016 11:42:55 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ozeukes.com/events/cossack-brothers-20th-anniversary-gala-cabaret-evening/</guid>
      <description>Cossack Brothers Invite you to
Celebrate the 20th Anniversary
Gala Cabaret Evening
Ukrainian House Essendon</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Nu Ethno Launch</title>
      <link>https://ozeukes.com/events/nu-ethno-launch/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Oct 2016 11:26:59 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ozeukes.com/events/nu-ethno-launch/</guid>
      <description>Think where Music meets Art, meets Dance (with limited alcohol - beer, wine, sparkling, basic spirits - &amp;amp; food).
Come to the premiere cultural infusion event in Melbourne:
NU Ethno Launch;
An experience not to be missed. Talented artists each will present their craft for you to enjoy. Live music from DJ’s who will keep you dancing, Painters creating their masterpieces right in front of you and eclectic music breathing new life into poetry.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Інтерв’ю на SBS Ukrainian Radio</title>
      <link>https://ozeukes.com/culture/interview-sbs-ukrainian-sep-oct-2016/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Oct 2016 10:46:21 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ozeukes.com/culture/interview-sbs-ukrainian-sep-oct-2016/</guid>
      <description>[ ](http://www.sbs.com.au/yourlanguage/ukrainian/uk/content/tak-nasha-pisnya-iednaie-sviti?language=uk)“ТАК, НАША ПІСНЯ ЄДНАЄ СВІТИ…”
БОГДАН РУДНИЦЬКИЙ ВЕДЕ РОЗМОВУ ІЗ ЗАСЛУЖЕНИМ ДІЯЧЕМ МИСТЕЦТВ УКРАЇНИ ВОЛОДИМИРОМ ГОЛОВКОМ ІЗ МЕЛЬБУРНА
http://www.sbs.com.au/yourlanguage/ukrainian/uk/content/tak-nasha-pisnya-iednaie-sviti?language=uk
  [ ](http://www.sbs.com.au/yourlanguage/ukrainian/uk/content/50-littya-ukrayinskogo-tancyuvalnogo-ansamblyu-verhovina?language=uk)50-ЛІТТЯ УКРАЇНСЬКОГО ТАНЦЮВАЛЬНОГО АНСАМБЛЮ &amp;ldquo;ВЕРХОВИНА&amp;rdquo;
Богдан Рудницький веде розмову із знаними сумівками Лесею Рудевич і Тамарою Моравською зі Спілки Української Молоді в Австралії та Українського танцювального ансамблю &amp;ldquo;ВЕРХОВИНА&amp;rdquo; із Мельбурна.
http://www.sbs.com.au/yourlanguage/ukrainian/uk/content/50-littya-ukrayinskogo-tancyuvalnogo-ansamblyu-verhovina?language=uk</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Kolobok at the Ukrainian Community School, Noble Park</title>
      <link>https://ozeukes.com/events/kolobok-at-the-ukrainian-community-school-noble-park/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Oct 2016 06:54:07 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ozeukes.com/events/kolobok-at-the-ukrainian-community-school-noble-park/</guid>
      <description>This show is inspired by the folktale Kolobok, the Ukrainian version of The Gingerbread Man. Kolobok is a little round freshly baked bun that escapes from an elderly couple and goes to the forest. Enter our wonderland of ordinary materials, animated characters and the magic of light that will make small things tall as a tree or round things huge as a planet!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ukraine Day at Ukrainian Central School</title>
      <link>https://ozeukes.com/culture/ukraine-day-at-ukrainian-central-school/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Sep 2016 20:44:09 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ozeukes.com/culture/ukraine-day-at-ukrainian-central-school/</guid>
      <description>Ukrainian Central School, Sydney, celebrated 25 years of Ukrainian independence by holding &amp;ldquo;Ukraine Day&amp;rdquo; with blue and yellow colours, lessons, art and craft, performances and special visitors.
https://youtu.be/aUEo9xK8w9s</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>AFUO SUPPORTS CULTURAL EXCHANGE AUSTRALIA - UKRAINE</title>
      <link>https://ozeukes.com/events/international-events/afuo-supports-cultural-exchange-australia-ukraine/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Sep 2016 04:10:28 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ozeukes.com/events/international-events/afuo-supports-cultural-exchange-australia-ukraine/</guid>
      <description>The Australian Federation of Ukrainian Organisations is financially supporting the Embassy of Australia in Kyiv Cultural Program.
Ana de la Vega, a highly regarded Australian flautist based in Berlin, will be performing at the Philharmonic in Kyiv on Monday 26 September, in concert with the Kyiv Camerata chamber orchestra. This concert will be part of the Philharmonic’s standard program season.
On Tue 27 or Wed 28 Sept, Ana will be leading a masterclass at the Tchaikovsky Musical Academy, and that evening performing a public recital at the academy.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Celebrating 70 years of settlement of Ukrainians in Australia</title>
      <link>https://ozeukes.com/events/victoria/celebrating-70-years-of-settlement-of-ukrainians-in-australia/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Sep 2016 12:28:10 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ozeukes.com/events/victoria/celebrating-70-years-of-settlement-of-ukrainians-in-australia/</guid>
      <description>19-го вересня 2016
ОБІЖНИК СУОА
Ч. 8. 2015 – 2018
**Відзначення 70-ліття Поселення Українців в Австралії Зміцни майбутнє, пізнай минуле!**
**I. XV Здвиг Українців Австралії відбудеться 8 - 9 липня 2017 р. **
Мистецька програма XV Здвигу відбудеться у недію, 9-го липня, 2017, Melbourne Town Hall (це період шкільних канікул у всіх штатах Австралії).
ІІ. Відзначення 70-ліття Поселення Українців в Австралії.
 1. Управа Союзу Українських Організацій Австралії готує план заходів з підготовки та відзначення 70-ліття поселення українців в Австралії.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Коломийський музей отримав у подарунок колекцію писанок з Австралії</title>
      <link>https://ozeukes.com/culture/kolomyyskyy-muzey-otrymav-u-podarunok-kolektsiyu-pysanok-z-avstraliyi/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Sep 2016 11:30:58 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ozeukes.com/culture/kolomyyskyy-muzey-otrymav-u-podarunok-kolektsiyu-pysanok-z-avstraliyi/</guid>
      <description>Музей писанкового розпису поповнився колекцією писанок від австралійських мисткинь, яку вони присвятили 25-ій річниці Незалежності України. Десять писанок, написаних на страусових, гусячих і курячих яйцях, привезли до Коломиї голова Союзу українок Австралії Галина Касіян та секретар Союзу українських організацій Австралії Ірина Андреєва.
Ідея створення колекції писанок спеціально для коломийського музею належить Марусі Яроцькій-Юрків, активній союзянці, голові Єпархіальної ради УГКЦ Австралії, Нової Зеландії та Океанії. Пані Марія – фаховий архітектор, захоплюється графікою та малярством.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Okean Elzy - World Tour</title>
      <link>https://ozeukes.com/events/victoria/okean-elzy-world-tour/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Sep 2016 11:14:24 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ozeukes.com/events/victoria/okean-elzy-world-tour/</guid>
      <description>The internationally renowned band “Okean Elzy” World Tour now includes Australia! The group has extended their historical tour Down Under – Melbourne 3rd February (170Russell) and 5th February in Sydney (The Metro Theatre).
Buy tickets at http://www.moshtix.com.au/v2/event/okean-elzy-ukraine/89723</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>THE 25TH ANNIVERSARY OF UKRAINE&#39;S INDEPENDENCE IN MELBOURNE</title>
      <link>https://ozeukes.com/events/victoria/the-25th-anniversary-of-ukraines-independence-in-melbourne/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Sep 2016 09:36:11 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ozeukes.com/events/victoria/the-25th-anniversary-of-ukraines-independence-in-melbourne/</guid>
      <description>On Sunday, 21 August 2016, at the Deakin Edge, Federation Square in Melbourne, Ukrainians of Victoria celebrated the 25th Anniversary of Ukrainian Independence. Happy Independence Day Ukraine!
http://www.sbs.com.au/yourlanguage/ukrainian/uk/gallery/25th-anniversary-ukraines-independency-melbourne?language=uk</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>25th Anniversary of Ukrainian Independence Concert and Lunch - Perth</title>
      <link>https://ozeukes.com/events/western-australia/25th-anniversary-of-ukrainian-independence-concert-and-lunch-perth/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Sep 2016 09:29:12 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ozeukes.com/events/western-australia/25th-anniversary-of-ukrainian-independence-concert-and-lunch-perth/</guid>
      <description>**Very special thanks to MZS (Ministry of Foreign Affairs – Ukraine) who has allocated USD $1,500 to CYOA to distribute to all Ukrainian Associations in Australia who staged an Independence Day Event. **
A very special day was celebrated with more than 110 people enjoying 25th Anniversary of Ukrainian Independence Concert.
The concert opened with a moving poen by Marichka Diachenko, “ Ya Ukrainochka” followed by the National Anthem. The singing of the National Anthem of Ukraine at the start of the concert was met with exuberance and energy and I am sure our community will stay with this format for future concerts.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>COSSACK BROTHERS at Lviv Ukrainian Dance and Cultural Festival</title>
      <link>https://ozeukes.com/events/international-events/cossack-brothers-at-lviv-ukrainian-dance-and-cultural-festival/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Jul 2016 12:48:09 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ozeukes.com/events/international-events/cossack-brothers-at-lviv-ukrainian-dance-and-cultural-festival/</guid>
      <description>Australia&#39;s Ukrainian community being represented at Lviv Ukrainian Dance and Cultural Festival by COSSACK BROTHERS ! Well done!
Брати Козаки представляють українську громаду Австралії на Фестивалі Українського Танцю і Культури у Львові! Вітаємо!
http://tvoemisto.tv/news/lviv_pryymaie_mizhnarodnyy_festyval_tantsyu_10_foto_79484.html</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ukrainian Collectibles Society - 25th Anniversary of the Rebirth of Ukrainian Independence</title>
      <link>https://ozeukes.com/culture/ukrainian-collectibles-society-25th-anniversary-of-the-rebirth-of-ukrainian-independence/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Jul 2016 07:40:30 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ozeukes.com/culture/ukrainian-collectibles-society-25th-anniversary-of-the-rebirth-of-ukrainian-independence/</guid>
      <description>The Ukrainian Collectibles Society (UCS) is pleased to announce the release of a specially designed range of souvenir products to commemorate the 25th anniversary of the rebirth of Ukraine’s independence on 24 August 2016.
The following three new souvenir philatelic items will be available:
 * a $1.00 Australia Post Personalised Stamp™ (standard domestic postage rate) * a first day of issue (FDC) envelope with design * a pictorial postcard  All products have been designed by Adelaide graphic artist and designer, Tamara Jakovlev.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>У Мельборні відзначили 75-річчя визначних дат історії України</title>
      <link>https://ozeukes.com/events/victoria/melbourne-celebrated-75th-anniversary-of-ukrainian-historical-dates/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Jun 2016 07:48:08 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ozeukes.com/events/victoria/melbourne-celebrated-75th-anniversary-of-ukrainian-historical-dates/</guid>
      <description>Історія України настільки багата героями, що майже кожного дня в році українці можуть вшановувати пам’ять одразу кількох героїв, які поклали життя за свободу своєї Батьківщини.
Саме з цієї нагоди у неділю, 26 червня, в Українському Народному Домі в Ессендоні, спільнота Громади Вікторії відзначала Свято Героїв та 75 річницю Акта відновлення Державності України 1941 року у Львові.
Святкову програму розпочали вшануванням пам’яті борців за волю України урочистим внесенням державних прапорів України та Австралії, Організації Українських Націоналістів (ОУН), Братства 1-ої Дивізії УНА, Українського Вільного Козацтва, Спілки Української Молоді (СУМ) та організації Пласт.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ukrainian diaspora rejoices over Eurovision win</title>
      <link>https://ozeukes.com/events/international-events/ukrainian-diaspora-rejoices-over-eurovision-win/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 15 May 2016 03:53:07 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ozeukes.com/events/international-events/ukrainian-diaspora-rejoices-over-eurovision-win/</guid>
      <description>15 May 2016
**_MEDIA RELEASE _**
Ukrainian diaspora rejoices over Eurovision win In a victory loaded with political meaning, Ukraine’s 2016 Eurovision entrant Jamala, has taken out the coveted prize, much to Australian-Ukrainians’ delight.
The 32-year old singer is a Crimean Tatar, an ethnic group native to Ukraine’s Crimean peninsula since the 13th—17th centuries. In 1944 the Tatars were deported from Crimea by the Soviet government. Decades later they later returned to their homeland but have experienced renewed ethnic tension since the Russian Federation’s annexation of Crimea in 2014.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>У Мельбурні відзначили 30-річчя аварії на Чорнобильській АЕС</title>
      <link>https://ozeukes.com/events/30th-anniversary-of-the-chornobyl-disaster-melbourne/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 May 2016 07:01:51 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ozeukes.com/events/30th-anniversary-of-the-chornobyl-disaster-melbourne/</guid>
      <description>Чимало дат є в історії українського народу, які ми згадуємо з великим сумом і з біллю у серці. Одна із них – 26 квітня, коли над квітучим Поліссям у нічному небі спалахнув вогонь радіаційного вибуху четвертого реактора на Чорнобильській АЕС. Вибух цей стався тридцять років тому, 26 квітня 1986 року. Це була найбільша техноґенно – екологічна катастрофа сучасного світу. Уряд Радянського Союзу майже дві доби тримав у секреті події, що відбувалися після вибуху 26 квітня.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>«ФОЛЬКНЕРИ» - ФОНД ПОКРИТТЯ ЛІКАРСЬКИХ ВИТРАТ ПРИ НАРОДЖЕННІ СИНА</title>
      <link>https://ozeukes.com/culture/folknery-help-support-hospital-costs-of-their-newly-arrived-son-ukr/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 17 Apr 2016 11:18:18 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ozeukes.com/culture/folknery-help-support-hospital-costs-of-their-newly-arrived-son-ukr/</guid>
      <description>14-го квітня 2016
Як Ви напевно вже чули, наші гості з України, Володимир Муляр та Ірина Гаврилець (група «Фолькнери») стали гордими батьками сина Марка.
Марко народився минулого тижня в Royal Women’s Hospital в Сіднеї, 2 місяці раніше терміну, і його потрібно буде тримати в лікарні до двох місяців.
Ірина та Володимир мали замовлені квитки в Аргентину на 2 травня 2016 року, але несподіване народження сина тепер означитиме, що вони повинні залишитися в Австралії протягом довшого періоду.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>FOLKNERY: help support hospital costs of their newly arrived son</title>
      <link>https://ozeukes.com/culture/folknery-help-support-hospital-costs-of-their-newly-arrived-son/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Apr 2016 06:27:48 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ozeukes.com/culture/folknery-help-support-hospital-costs-of-their-newly-arrived-son/</guid>
      <description>As you may be aware our guests from Ukraine, Folknery - Voloymyr Muliar and Iryna Havrylets are now the proud parents of a newly arrived son Marko.
Marko was born last week 2 months premature in Royal Women’s Hospital in Sydney and will need to spend up to two months in hospital.
Iryna and Volodymyr had tickets booked to Argentina on May 2, 2016, but the unexpected birth of their son will now see them have to stay in Australia for longer period.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Folknery performance and film at Noble Park</title>
      <link>https://ozeukes.com/events/victoria/folknery-performance-and-film-at-noble-park/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Apr 2016 08:12:45 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ozeukes.com/events/victoria/folknery-performance-and-film-at-noble-park/</guid>
      <description>Філія УГВ в Нобл Парку запрошує</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>KAZKA Coming to Brisbane</title>
      <link>https://ozeukes.com/events/queensland/kazka-coming-to-brisbane/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Mar 2016 11:20:47 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ozeukes.com/events/queensland/kazka-coming-to-brisbane/</guid>
      <description>THE WAIT IS OVER
KAZKA Coming soon to Brisbane

QUT Gardens Theatre
Bookings at www.gardenstheatre.qut.edu.au/whatson
For more information visit
www.lehenda.com.au/kazka</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ДахаБраха в Аделайді</title>
      <link>https://ozeukes.com/events/south-australia/dakha-brakha-in-adelaide/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Mar 2016 09:26:03 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ozeukes.com/events/south-australia/dakha-brakha-in-adelaide/</guid>
      <description>_Давид Кваснюк, учень 12-го класу Української школи, Аделайда._
WOMADelaide – престижний музичний фестиваль, який щороку приводить в наше місто музикантів з усього світу. Фестиваль проходить в Ботанічному парку і завжди збирає велику авдиторію людей, які люблять музику.
Цього року я вперше був на цьому фестивалі. Фестиваль мав на мене дуже добрий вплив. Мені сподобалася невимушена, весела, відпочинкова атмосфера. Люди слухали музику, говорили, знайомилися, мали пікнік. І хоч надворі було сонячно і досить не по весняному гарячо, парк був просто переповнений людьми.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>DAKHA BRAKHA at WOMADelaide</title>
      <link>https://ozeukes.com/events/south-australia/dakha-brakha-at-womadelaide/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Mar 2016 09:18:02 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ozeukes.com/events/south-australia/dakha-brakha-at-womadelaide/</guid>
      <description>By Roma &amp;amp; Rostyslav Becker
So much anticipation surrounded Dakha Brakha’s 2016 return to WOMADelaide after a five year hiatus. The New Zealand WOMAD 2016 artists’ page pays homage to their international breakthrough in Adelaide 2011 and “ascent in the international music scene after being discovered by Australian WOMADelaide.” So, the curious and the converts with fond memories of their 2011 appearance, gathered around the intimate Novatech Stage to see the band with the impossibly high fur hats and colourful costumes.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dakha Brakha at the 2016 Womadelaide Festival</title>
      <link>https://ozeukes.com/events/dakha-brakha-at-the-2016-womadelaide-festival/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 03 Mar 2016 06:52:03 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ozeukes.com/events/dakha-brakha-at-the-2016-womadelaide-festival/</guid>
      <description>Dakha Brakha one of Ukraine’s musical treasures is set to unleash its wild fusion of authentic village folk, punk, hip hop and tribal trance in a genre they call “ethno chaos” at the 2016 Womadelaide Festival.
Dakha Brakha first appeared at Womadelaide in 2011 to rapturous applause. Since then they have appeared at major festivals around the world including the UK Womad, Sziget and Bonaroo. Rolling Stone magazine called them, “The best breakout band of Bonaroo,” while commenting on their mournful accordion and apocalyptic cello sawing”</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Свято Шевченка</title>
      <link>https://ozeukes.com/events/shevchenko-2016-vic/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Feb 2016 06:45:03 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ozeukes.com/events/shevchenko-2016-vic/</guid>
      <description>Українська громада Вікторії запрошує все українське громадянство на
Свято Шевченка </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lehenda Ukrainian Dance Company, School of Dance</title>
      <link>https://ozeukes.com/culture/lehenda-ukrainian-dance-company-school-of-dance/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Feb 2016 11:40:15 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ozeukes.com/culture/lehenda-ukrainian-dance-company-school-of-dance/</guid>
      <description>Lehenda Ukrainian Dance Company, School of Dance classes have now started! Lehenda invites all children from ages 3-17 to come and learn Ukrainian Dance!
Gain a strong foundation in Ukrainian dance technique, build the fundamental skills across various styles/regions of Ukrainian Dance from professional, high quality, dedicated and passionate teachers ad apply these skill to experience the excitement and joy of performance!
Classes held at Jason Coleman&#39;s Ministry of Dance, North Melbourne For further information email info@lehenda.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Українське Радіо Брисбану - радіо ярмарок</title>
      <link>https://ozeukes.com/culture/brisbane-ukr-radio-day-2015/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Jan 2016 11:06:25 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ozeukes.com/culture/brisbane-ukr-radio-day-2015/</guid>
      <description>5 грудня 2015 на території громади в Окслі було проведено радіо ярмарок. У цей день грала українська музика, відвідувачі наслоджувалися живим співом чарівної Анастасії Сухініної, спостерігали нові танці від танцювального гурту Водограй, слухали мандруючих музикантів з україни – гурт Фолькнери, гру місцевих музик, купували hand-made подарунки. І, звичайно, куштували українські страви та запивали це духмяним пивом і смачнючою медовухою. У цій справі радіо допомогали представники української кредитного кооперативу – Дністер. Рівно рік тому, Українське Радіо Брисбен провело перше велике святкування радіо дню, хоча українське радіо у нашому місті існує вже 36 років.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Різдвяне привітання проводу ОУН(б)</title>
      <link>https://ozeukes.com/culture/vitanya-provid-oun/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Dec 2015 11:20:01 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ozeukes.com/culture/vitanya-provid-oun/</guid>
      <description>Вельмишановні Друзі!
Ось знову завітав до нас із небесних висот невмирущий дух Різдва Ісуса Христа, свято кожної християнської душі. Це свято, як і наступний Новий рік, несе кожному нові мрії і сподівання, нові життєві плани і побажання. Щоразу цей знаменний день втілення Спасителя світу символізує оживлення усього роду людського, повертає нас до євангельських заповідей, спонукає наші душі і тіла до терпимості, чистоти наших помислів та любові до ближнього.
Різдвяна мить спонукає до вищих ідей, роздумів про добро і милосердя, проганяє морок гріховного зла.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>UKRAINIAN LITERATURE IN ENGLISH</title>
      <link>https://ozeukes.com/culture/ukrainian-literature-in-english/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Dec 2015 06:19:24 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ozeukes.com/culture/ukrainian-literature-in-english/</guid>
      <description>www.ukrainianliterature.com Watch as the site grows each day and a world of Ukrainian literature translated into English unfolds before your eyes. From the old classics to current-day books about the war in Ukraine’s east.
Both prose and poetry.
Links to websites to buy books online. New and used.
Like us on Facebook at www.facebook.com/Ukralit
Donations welcome through PayPal to ytkacz@gmail.com</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>JACKA THE MUSICAL: The AFUO encourages you to come and witness this production</title>
      <link>https://ozeukes.com/culture/jacka-the-musical-the-afuo-encourages-you-to-come-and-witness-this-production/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Oct 2015 11:58:09 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ozeukes.com/culture/jacka-the-musical-the-afuo-encourages-you-to-come-and-witness-this-production/</guid>
      <description>JACKA THE MUSICAL
The AFUO encourages you to come and witness this production
As many of you may be aware Prof Michael Lawriwsky wrote a book about Albert Jacka and his role in WWI. Jacka received Australia&#39;s first Victoria Cross of the war.
“He was one of the first people among 300,000 plus Australians to volunteer,&amp;quot;.
&amp;ldquo;It was just that adventurous spirit he had.&amp;quot;
A private in the 14th Battalion, Jacka landed at Anzac Cove late in the day on April 25 and was soon on his way to the frontline.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>24 річниця Незалежності України у Мельбурні</title>
      <link>https://ozeukes.com/culture/24-anniversary-of-independence-of-ukraine-in-melbourne/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 11 Sep 2015 11:36:44 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ozeukes.com/culture/24-anniversary-of-independence-of-ukraine-in-melbourne/</guid>
      <description>Відзначення важливої дати української історії “День Незалежності України” українська спільнота штату Вікторії розпочала безпосередньо у День Незалежності, в понеділок, 24 серпня. Заходами членів клубу “Рідний Край” УГВ п-вом Лаґолат у святково прибраній залі Українського Народного Дому в Ессендоні відбулася святкова вечеря, коротка доповідь голови Управи УГВ М. Моравського та гостя з України, члена Збройних Сил України майора Тимура Пістрюги. У залі, де був повний аншлаг, зібралася українська спільнота різних хвиль еміґрації та прихильників українства, багато молоді та дітей, звучали українські мелодії i пісні під супровід акордеоніста В.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>WORLD PREMIERE OF A NEW ROCK MUSICAL JACKA VC LEGEND OF GALLIPOLI</title>
      <link>https://ozeukes.com/events/world-premiere-of-a-new-rock-musical-jacka-vc-legend-of-gallipoli/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 23 Aug 2015 09:39:21 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ozeukes.com/events/world-premiere-of-a-new-rock-musical-jacka-vc-legend-of-gallipoli/</guid>
      <description>Congratulations to Michael Lawriwsky (whose book &amp;lsquo;Hard Jacka&amp;rsquo; the musical is based on), also Nicholas Buc (orchestration) &amp;amp; Melanie Moravski Dechnicz (choreography).
WORLD PREMIERE OF A NEW ROCK MUSICAL - JACKA VC LEGEND OF GALLIPOLI

A century ago all Australians knew the name of Albert Jacka VC. His daring action at Courtney&#39;s Post, Gallipoli, won him the first Australian Victoria Cross of the Great War and the adoration of a young country.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ivasyk Telesyk - Lehenda Ukrainian School of Dance Yearly Concert</title>
      <link>https://ozeukes.com/events/ivasyk-telesyk-lehenda-ukrainian-school-of-dance-yearly-concert/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Aug 2015 08:04:27 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ozeukes.com/events/ivasyk-telesyk-lehenda-ukrainian-school-of-dance-yearly-concert/</guid>
      <description>Lehenda Ukrainian School of Dance
presents

Ivasyk Telesyk and Other Pieces Guest artists: Rodyna Ensemble Cost: Adult $23, Concession: $16, Children under 6 Free Bookings: www.lehenda.com.au/performances/schoolbookings</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>НА СВІТЛУ Й НЕЗАБУТНЮ ПАМ’ЯТЬ ПРО СЛАВЕТНОГО СПІВАКА</title>
      <link>https://ozeukes.com/culture/na-svitlu-y-nezabutnyu-pamyat-pro-slavetnogo-spivaka/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jul 2015 07:20:31 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ozeukes.com/culture/na-svitlu-y-nezabutnyu-pamyat-pro-slavetnogo-spivaka/</guid>
      <description>30 червня 2015-го року минуло 20 років з дня смерті романтика української естради і співця кохання Назарія Яремчука&amp;hellip;
http://www.sbs.com.au/yourlanguage/ukrainian/uk/content/na-svitlu-y-nezabutnyu-pamyat-pro-slavetnogo-spivaka?language=uk</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>РОДИНА і ДРУЗІ</title>
      <link>https://ozeukes.com/culture/rodyna-and-friends/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Jun 2015 10:10:36 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ozeukes.com/culture/rodyna-and-friends/</guid>
      <description>РОДИНА і ДРУЗІ
&amp;ldquo;Родина і Друзі&amp;rdquo; – під таким гаслом в Українському Народному Домі в Ессендоні відбувся концерт співочого ансамблю Української Громади Вікторії “Родина”, керівником якого є Мирослав Ґраноліч.
Ансамбль, хоч і молодий, але відомий своєю активністю в усіх святкуваннях Української Громади. Майже всі члени цього ансамблю – представники імміграції “Боснійської хвилі”, які приїхали до Австралії з бувшої Югославії після її розпаду. Їх предки, діди та прадіди, плекали свою маленьку Україну в Боснії і Герцоґовині, Хорватії, Сербії, Македонії, куди занесла їх доля у пошуках кращого життя ще на початку минулого століття.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Інтерв&#39;ю на SBS Ukrainian Radio</title>
      <link>https://ozeukes.com/politics/sbs_ukrainian_radio_interviews_apr_may_2015/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 May 2015 07:54:03 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ozeukes.com/politics/sbs_ukrainian_radio_interviews_apr_may_2015/</guid>
      <description>**ПРЕМ’ЄРА «ЛЕГЕНДИ» У МЕЛЬБУРНІ: КАЗКА ПРО ЛЮБОВ, ПРО ЩОСЬ ЗАГУБЛЕНЕ&amp;hellip; І ТАЄМНИЧОГО СИНЬОГО ЛИСА….**
Богдан Рудницький веде розмову із художнім керівником і засновником Української танцювальної школи «Легенда» у Мельбурні, Заслуженим діячем мистецтв України Меланією Моравською-Дехніч. Казка про любов, про щось загублене&amp;hellip; І таємничого синього лиса&amp;hellip;З таким лейтмотивом «Легенда» представляє свою «КАЗКУ», яка, напевно, захопить глядачів у Мельбурні та Сіднеї у травні цього року. «КАЗКА» - це ориґінальний фольклорний балет, базований на традиційних українських казках.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>LEHENDA Legacy Program</title>
      <link>https://ozeukes.com/culture/lehenda-legacy-program/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 Mar 2015 12:26:36 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ozeukes.com/culture/lehenda-legacy-program/</guid>
      <description>Win 2 tickets to see KAZKA as part of the LEHENDA Legacy Program!
[caption id=&amp;rdquo;&amp;rdquo; align=&amp;quot;aligncenter&amp;rdquo; width=&amp;quot;750&amp;rdquo;] LEHENDA Legacy Program[/caption]</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Свято &#34;Кобзар&#34;та його автор Тарас Шевченко</title>
      <link>https://ozeukes.com/events/svjato_kobzar_ta_jogo_avtor_taras_shevchenko/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Feb 2015 06:25:58 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ozeukes.com/events/svjato_kobzar_ta_jogo_avtor_taras_shevchenko/</guid>
      <description>Українська Громада Вікторії запрошує все українське громадянство та прихильників українства на свято &amp;ldquo;Кобзар&amp;rdquo; та його автор Тарас Шевченко&amp;rdquo;.
Свято відбудеться в неділю, 15 березня о год.1.30 пополудні, в Українському Народному Домі, Ессендон. Приходьде і ми разом згадаємо &amp;ldquo;&amp;hellip;незлим тихим словом&amp;hellip; &amp;quot; Великого Пророка України Тараса Григоровича Шевченка.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>KAZKA coming soon</title>
      <link>https://ozeukes.com/events/kazka-coming-soon/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Feb 2015 20:01:45 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ozeukes.com/events/kazka-coming-soon/</guid>
      <description>Lehenda Ukrainian Dance Company is thrilled to launch the international tour of its exciting new dance production KAZKA, an original folk ballet inspired by Ukrainian fairy tales.
For further information visit www.lehenda.com.au/kazka</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lehenda adult dance classes</title>
      <link>https://ozeukes.com/culture/lehenda-adult-dance-classes/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Jan 2015 06:06:56 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ozeukes.com/culture/lehenda-adult-dance-classes/</guid>
      <description>Used to dance? Want to take it up again? Keep up your fitness with this fun class amongst friends!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lehenda School of Dance Enrolment for 2015</title>
      <link>https://ozeukes.com/culture/lehenda-school-of-dance-enrolment-for-2015/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Jan 2015 05:30:37 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ozeukes.com/culture/lehenda-school-of-dance-enrolment-for-2015/</guid>
      <description>Lehenda School of Dance Enrolment for 2015</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Verchovyna Mamas and Bubs</title>
      <link>https://ozeukes.com/culture/verchovyna-mamas-and-bubs/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Jan 2015 05:23:56 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ozeukes.com/culture/verchovyna-mamas-and-bubs/</guid>
      <description>Introducing Verchovyna Mamas and Bubs</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Enroll your child in Verchovyna</title>
      <link>https://ozeukes.com/culture/enroll-your-child-in-verchovyna/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Jan 2015 05:20:41 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ozeukes.com/culture/enroll-your-child-in-verchovyna/</guid>
      <description>We are a community based ensemble working towards 50 continuous years of promoting, educating and nourishing children and the wider public in Ukrainian dance and culture. With a combined 62 years of teaching experience, we provide high quality tutoring and mentoring at the cheapest prices.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ukrainian Film Festival - Geelong</title>
      <link>https://ozeukes.com/events/ukrainian-film-festival-geelong/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Jan 2015 06:00:17 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ozeukes.com/events/ukrainian-film-festival-geelong/</guid>
      <description>presents Australia’s first
**UKRAINIAN FILM FESTIVAL **
Featuring new, classic and pioneering films
by renowned Ukrainian filmmakers.
January 15 – 21, 2015 Program Information:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A colourful evening of Ukrainian art, food and dance</title>
      <link>https://ozeukes.com/events/a-colourful-evening-of-ukrainian-art-food-and-dance/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Nov 2014 11:23:37 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ozeukes.com/events/a-colourful-evening-of-ukrainian-art-food-and-dance/</guid>
      <description>Peruse beautiful paintings by renowned Ukrainian artist, Volodymyr Voroniuk, available for sale by silent auction.
Enjoy a buffet-style dinner of hearty Ukrainian fare alongside a lively performance by Lehenda Ukrainian Dance Company.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>CYM Spring concert 2014</title>
      <link>https://ozeukes.com/events/cym-spring-concert-2014/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Nov 2014 06:51:39 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ozeukes.com/events/cym-spring-concert-2014/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Інтерв&#39;ю на SBS Ukrainian Radio</title>
      <link>https://ozeukes.com/culture/sbs_ukrainian_radio_interviews_oct2014/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Oct 2014 10:23:55 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ozeukes.com/culture/sbs_ukrainian_radio_interviews_oct2014/</guid>
      <description>АВСТРАЛІЙСЬКА ПАТРІАРША ПОДОРОЖ: ПОГЛЯД
Глава і Отець Української Греко-Католицької Церкви в Австралії&amp;hellip;
Богдан Рудницький веде інтерв`ю із Головою Єпархіяльної Пасторальної Ради УГКЦ в Австралії, Новій Зеландії та країнах Океанії п-і Марусею Яроцькою&amp;hellip;
http://www.sbs.com.au/yourlanguage/ukrainian/highlight/page/id/368535/t/AUSTRALIAN-PATRIARCHAL-TOUR:-THE-VIEW/

ЯКЩО ВИ САМІ ГОТУЄТЕ ПОДАТКОВУ ДЕКЛАРАЦІЮ, ТО ВАЖЛИВО, ЩОБ ВИ ЇЇ ПОДАЛИ ДО 31 ЖОВТНЯ&amp;hellip;
Богдан Рудницький веде розмову із п-і Світланою Новотарської із Австралійської податкової служби,
Отже, час подавати податкові звіти закінчується 31 жовтня. Це означає, що якщо ви готуєте свій власний податковий звіт, то час підходить до закінчення такого терміну&amp;hellip;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ЧАРІВНА КРАСА УКРАЇНСЬКОЇ ВИШИВАНКИ</title>
      <link>https://ozeukes.com/culture/%d1%87%d0%b0%d1%80%d1%96%d0%b2%d0%bd%d0%b0-%d0%ba%d1%80%d0%b0%d1%81%d0%b0-%d1%83%d0%ba%d1%80%d0%b0%d1%97%d0%bd%d1%81%d1%8c%d0%ba%d0%be%d1%97-%d0%b2%d0%b8%d1%88%d0%b8%d0%b2%d0%b0%d0%bd%d0%ba%d0%b8/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Aug 2014 03:52:09 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ozeukes.com/culture/%d1%87%d0%b0%d1%80%d1%96%d0%b2%d0%bd%d0%b0-%d0%ba%d1%80%d0%b0%d1%81%d0%b0-%d1%83%d0%ba%d1%80%d0%b0%d1%97%d0%bd%d1%81%d1%8c%d0%ba%d0%be%d1%97-%d0%b2%d0%b8%d1%88%d0%b8%d0%b2%d0%b0%d0%bd%d0%ba%d0%b8/</guid>
      <description>“ЧАРІВНА КРАСА УКРАЇНСЬКОЇ ВИШИВАНКИ” Фешн-Парад Вишиванoк дітей та молодi Української Громади Мельбурну.
Нас, українців, щедрих на таланти, здiбних та обдарованих - по чарівних вишиванках пізнають в усьому світі. З вишиванкою пов&#39;язана вся багатовікова історія українського народу, це і традиції, обряди, культурa, його творчі пошуки, радість і горе, його перемоги і поразки та сподівання на майбутнє. Вишиванка – споконвічний символ духовності української нації, a в певний час стає ще й засобом прояву волі, незалежності українців.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>MAKE SUNDAY AUGUST 24 2014 UKRAINE&#39;S NATIONAL DAY - A BLUE AND YELLOW DAY </title>
      <link>https://ozeukes.com/culture/make-sunday-august-24-2014-ukraines-national-day-a-blue-and-yellow-day/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Aug 2014 00:12:43 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ozeukes.com/culture/make-sunday-august-24-2014-ukraines-national-day-a-blue-and-yellow-day/</guid>
      <description>MAKE SUNDAY AUGUST 24 2014 UKRAINE&#39;S NATIONAL DAY - A BLUE AND YELLOW DAY
The Australian Federation of Ukrainian Organisations calls on the Australia&#39;s Ukrainian and broader community to support President Poroshenko&#39;s call to make Sunday BLUE AND YELLOW DAY IN SUPPORT OF UKRAINE Fly a flag, use the colours creatively in fashion, in decorations, in decorating houses , cars , offices State Organisations and individuals should think creatively how they could promote the colours in public places – Time is short but ideas normally flow quickly – Let us know your ideas Post on Facebook and email your suggestions</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ukrainian Dance National Winter Workshop</title>
      <link>https://ozeukes.com/culture/ukrainian-dance-national-winter-workshop/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 May 2014 07:09:03 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ozeukes.com/culture/ukrainian-dance-national-winter-workshop/</guid>
      <description>The Lehenda Ukrainian Dance Company is organising a Ukrainian Dance workshop over the period Thursday 10th – Sunday 13th July 2014. The workshop will include 4 days of intense training in Ukrainian technique, Ukrainian repertoire and ballet for the Ukrainian dancer, with an occasional taster class thrown in!
Bookings essential: http://www.lehenda.com.au/events/
Further info &amp;amp; enquiries: info@lehenda.com.au</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Photos from the Ukrainian Festival ‘Hopak in the Park’ Ukrainian Dance Spectacular</title>
      <link>https://ozeukes.com/culture/photos-from-the-ukrainian-festival-hopak-in-the-park-ukrainian-dance-spectacular/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Apr 2014 01:52:37 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ozeukes.com/culture/photos-from-the-ukrainian-festival-hopak-in-the-park-ukrainian-dance-spectacular/</guid>
      <description>Hundreds of Australia&#39;s best Ukrainian dancers took part in the Ukrainian Dance Festival on Saturday 26th April 2014 at the Sidney Myer Music Bowl in Melbourne. Supporting this show were dance ensembles from the Irish, Spanish and Greek communities, and the highly acclaimed Ukrainian band “Zirka” from Toronto, Canada.
A full album of photos, courtesy of Taras and Sonja Moravski, can be viewed at: https://www.flickr.com/photos/moravski/sets/72157644354135471/
A small selection is presented here</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Пасхальна Богослужба Парафії УГКЦ ім св Андрія</title>
      <link>https://ozeukes.com/events/new-south-wales/easter-service-at-the-ukrainian-catholic-church/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Apr 2014 04:41:38 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ozeukes.com/events/new-south-wales/easter-service-at-the-ukrainian-catholic-church/</guid>
      <description>**_МАРІЧКА ГАЛАБУРДА-ЧИГРИН_**
Пасхальна Богослужба і посвячення пасхальних кошиків в Парафії Української Греко Католицької Церкви ім св Андрія, що відбулося в суботу 19.4.2014 в 18-ій годині сіднейського часу. Відбувається і тут дві Служби й посвячення пасок ранком в 9-ій годині і в 18 ій.
Після лагідного осіннього сонячного дня - погода під вечір була дещо холодновата.
Освітлена світлами церква ( Юстин Сенько й Андрій Рубак) виглядала прекрасно, і дала нам містичного насвітлення знимок, - перші знимки в альбомі позичила з сайту о.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Посвячення Паскальних Кошиків в Св. Покровській Парафії, УАПЦ</title>
      <link>https://ozeukes.com/events/new-south-wales/blessing-of-easter-baskets-at-the-orthodox-church/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Apr 2014 04:25:24 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ozeukes.com/events/new-south-wales/blessing-of-easter-baskets-at-the-orthodox-church/</guid>
      <description>МАРІЧКА ГАЛАБУРДА-ЧИГРИН
[ ](http://www.ozeukes.com/wp-content/uploads/2014/04/46.-PASKA-SYDNEY-046.jpg)Посвячення Паскальних Кошиків в Св. Покровській Парафії, УАПЦ субота 19.4.2014
Була лагідна осіння сонячна погода. Холодний вітер, який все в Гомбуш і Лідкомбі повіває зник щойно під вечір. Сонце пробивалося через вікна церкви і надавало дещо містичного насвітлення знимкам.

Отець настоятель Михайло Смолинець відправив коротку відправу, підчас проповіді кілька разів згадував наш народ в Україні й побажав йому всіх благ і навернення порядку в країні. І потім благословив паскальні кошики й людей, що подобалося дітям, підросткам.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Писанки для України - Сідней</title>
      <link>https://ozeukes.com/events/new-south-wales/pysanky-for-ukraine-sydney/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Apr 2014 07:49:50 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ozeukes.com/events/new-south-wales/pysanky-for-ukraine-sydney/</guid>
      <description>МАРІЧКА ГАЛАБУРДА-ЧИГРИН
ПИСАНКИ для УКРАЇНИ СІДНЕЙ
В суботу 29.3.2014 діти Української Школи Парафії УГКЦеркви ім. св. Андрія в Лідкомбі (Сідней) почали готуватися до Великодня. Вчителька-писанкарки Марійка Кука показала дітям як писати писанки. ШКОЛА долучилася до Світової Акції ПИСАНКИ для УКРАЇНИ, яка розпочалася 1.4.2014 в Канаді. В Акції взяло участь понад 350 писанкарів з багатьох країн світу.

Організаторка Акції Kathy Schoenfelder-Verrelli з Канади написала на своїй інтернетській мережі: Welcome students and thank-you for taking part in our &amp;ldquo;Pysanky For Ukraine&amp;rdquo;!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SBS Radio Ukrainian – Дві Радіопередачі</title>
      <link>https://ozeukes.com/culture/sbs-radio-ukrainian-two-broadcasts/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 03 Apr 2014 00:32:27 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ozeukes.com/culture/sbs-radio-ukrainian-two-broadcasts/</guid>
      <description>[ ](http://www.ozeukes.com/wp-content/uploads/2014/04/150px-SBS-Ukrainian.jpg)SBS Radio Ukrainian – Дві Радіопередачі
SBS Radio Ukrainian в останному часі передала дві радіопередачі, одну із Сіднею про доповідь професора Нормана Дейвіса, а другу із Мельбурну про відзначення 200-ліття з дня народження Тараса Шевченка.
ПРОФЕСОР НОРМАН ДЕЙВІС: УКРАЇНА ПОМІЖ ЄВРОСОЮЗОМ І РОСІЄЮ Ірина Білик із Сіднею розповідає про доповідь професора Нормана Дейвіса на тему «УКРАЇНА ПОМІЖ ЄВРОСОЮЗОМ І РОСІЄЮ».
Professor Norman Davies was educated at Bolton School, Magdalen College, Oxford, the University of Sussex and at several continental universities including Grenoble, Perugia and Kraków.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Виставка-конкурс дитячого малюнку “Мій Шевченко&#34;</title>
      <link>https://ozeukes.com/events/victoria/my-shevchenko-competition/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Apr 2014 06:02:05 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ozeukes.com/events/victoria/my-shevchenko-competition/</guid>
      <description>**До 200-річчя від дня народження Тараса Григоровича Шевченка ******
Вже другий рік поспіль мистецький відділ Управи Украінської Громади Вікторії проводить виставку конкурс дитячого малюнку.****
Якщо два роки тому ми назвали нашу виставку “Читаючи поезію Шевченка”. у цьому році наша виставка - “Мій Шевченко&amp;rdquo; є особливою i присвячена знаменній даті - 200 років від дня народження великого поета, i відбулася на свяковому концерті 30 березня 2014 року y Народному Домі в Есендоні.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Шевченквський Концерт у Мельбурні – 30/3/2014р</title>
      <link>https://ozeukes.com/events/victoria/shevchenko-concert-melbourne-2014/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Apr 2014 02:27:25 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ozeukes.com/events/victoria/shevchenko-concert-melbourne-2014/</guid>
      <description>В неділю 30 березня 2014р. українське громадянство Мельбурну відзначили 200-ліття з дня народження Тараса Шеченка святочним концертом.
В концерті брали участь різні мистецькі склади та одиниці. Поміж ними:
 * Капела «ЧЕРЕМОШ» при осереду СУМ-у в Мельбурні * Художний керівник і дириґент - Заслужений діяч мистецтв України Володимир Головко * Концертмейстер Христина Головко * Солісти * Анна Дацьків * Галина Костюк * Євген Стефин   
 * Доповідач на тему «Заповіт Тараса Шевченка» - Проф.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>CHILDREN FESTIVAL 2014</title>
      <link>https://ozeukes.com/events/new-south-wales/children-festival-2014/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Apr 2014 00:50:07 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ozeukes.com/events/new-south-wales/children-festival-2014/</guid>
      <description>**МАРІЧКА ГАЛАБУРДА-ЧИГРИН****_ _****_СІДНЕЙ 30.3.2014 _**
CHILDREN FESTIVAL 2014** в СІДНЕЇ Й МИ** В неділю 30.3.2014 відбувся в Сіднеї, в центрі міста, міжнародний дитячий фестиваль CHILDREN FESTIVAL 2014.
Українська Школа парафії УГКЦ ім св. Андрія дістала запрошення взяти в ньому участь. Директорка Школи пані Одарка Брецко звернулася до Марійки Шушняк - Федоров хореографа підготовити танцювальний гурток «Заграва» до участі в фестивалі. Марійка у свою чергу звернулася до Ярослава Сивака, хореографа групи «Весельчата» &amp;hellip;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ДІТИ СІДНЕЮ ЧИТАЮТЬ твори ТАРАСА ШЕВЧЕНКА</title>
      <link>https://ozeukes.com/events/new-south-wales/sydney-children-read-the-works-of-shevchenko/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Mar 2014 05:37:24 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ozeukes.com/events/new-south-wales/sydney-children-read-the-works-of-shevchenko/</guid>
      <description>**_МАРІЧКА ГАЛАБУРДА-ЧИГРИН_**
ДІТИ СІДНЕЮ ЧИТАЮТЬ твори ТАРАСА ШЕВЧЕНКА **В суботу 8.3.2014 **діти в Українській Школі ім св. Андрія в Сіднеї відбули своє шкільне cвято в честь Тараса Шевченка. Директорка Школи Одарка Брецко звернула нашу увагу на те, що портрет Тараса Шевченка намалювала бл.п. Галина Свідерська, одна з провідних шкільних вчительок, яка померла 6.2.2014.
Діти деклямували вірші Тараса Шевченка, виконали сценку на тему Шевченка, співали «Поклін тобі Тарасе» й інші пісні.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Taras Shevchenko 200th Anniversary Concert - WA</title>
      <link>https://ozeukes.com/events/western-australia/taras-shevchenko-200th-anniversary-concert-wa/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 22 Mar 2014 04:10:39 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ozeukes.com/events/western-australia/taras-shevchenko-200th-anniversary-concert-wa/</guid>
      <description>The Ukrainian Association of Western Australia will honour the memory of Taras Shevchenko with a 200th Anniversary Concert on Sunday March 30th at the Ukrainian Catholic Parish Hall in Maylands.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Святочний Концерт 200 ліття Тарас Шевченка - Мельбурн</title>
      <link>https://ozeukes.com/events/victoria/%d1%81%d0%b2%d1%8f%d1%82%d0%be%d1%87%d0%bd%d0%b8%d0%b9-%d0%ba%d0%be%d0%bd%d1%86%d0%b5%d1%80%d1%82-200-%d0%bb%d1%96%d1%82%d1%82%d1%8f-%d1%82%d0%b0%d1%80%d0%b0%d1%81-%d1%88%d0%b5%d0%b2%d1%87%d0%b5%d0%bd/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Mar 2014 02:11:10 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ozeukes.com/events/victoria/%d1%81%d0%b2%d1%8f%d1%82%d0%be%d1%87%d0%bd%d0%b8%d0%b9-%d0%ba%d0%be%d0%bd%d1%86%d0%b5%d1%80%d1%82-200-%d0%bb%d1%96%d1%82%d1%82%d1%8f-%d1%82%d0%b0%d1%80%d0%b0%d1%81-%d1%88%d0%b5%d0%b2%d1%87%d0%b5%d0%bd/</guid>
      <description>Українська Громада Вікторії (УГВ) запрошує на Святочний Концерт для святкування 200 ліття від дня народження Тарас Шевченка. Концерт відбудеться в неділю 30-го березня 2014 р. о годині 2:00 пп в Українському Народному Домі, Ессендон.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Порівняльна характеристика забезпечення прав меншостей / Comparative Data on Ethnic Minority Rights</title>
      <link>https://ozeukes.com/politics/comparative-data-on-ethnic-minority-rights/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Mar 2014 08:42:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ozeukes.com/politics/comparative-data-on-ethnic-minority-rights/</guid>
      <description>**Порівняльна характеристика забезпечення прав **меншостей
Міністерство закордонних справ України подало інформаційну довідку «Порівняльна характеристика забезпечення прав українців у Росії та росіян в Україні» : Порівняльна характеристика-скорочена (2)
Comparative** ****Data**** ****on**** ****Ethnic**** ****Minority**** ****Rights******
The Ministry of Foreign Affairs (Ukraine) has released a brief information sheet entitled “Comparative Data on Protection of Russian Ethnic Minority’s Rights in Ukraine and Ukrainian Ethnic Minority’s Rights in Russia”: Comparison of the rights of Ukrainians in Russia and Russians in Ukraine</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Виставка-конкурс дитячого малюнку &#34;Мій Шевченко&#34; у Мельбурні</title>
      <link>https://ozeukes.com/events/victoria/my-shevchenko-childrens-drawing-competition/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Mar 2014 04:46:56 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ozeukes.com/events/victoria/my-shevchenko-childrens-drawing-competition/</guid>
      <description>Виставка-конкурс дитячого малюнку &amp;ldquo;Мій Шевченко&amp;rdquo; у Мельбурні.  До участі у конкурсі запрошуються діти віком від 8 до 18 років:  * українських шкіл Мельбурну та Джілонґу * молодіжних організацій ПЛАСТ , СУМ а також усіх бажаючих !  Роботи виконуються на теми (на вибір):
 * Портрет Кобзаря * Композиція - улюблений вірш * Український пейзаж  
“My Shevchenko” Children’s Drawing Competition The competition is for children aged 8 to 18 year:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Читання слів Шевченка в Мельбурні / Shevchenko readings in Melbourne</title>
      <link>https://ozeukes.com/events/victoria/shevchenko-readings-in-melbourne/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Mar 2014 02:37:31 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ozeukes.com/events/victoria/shevchenko-readings-in-melbourne/</guid>
      <description>Весь світ читає Шевченка - The World Reads Shevchenko Відзначення 200-ліття з дня народження Тараса Шевченка / Commemorating the 200th anniversary of the birth of Taras Shevchenko
Мельбурн, Австралія Melbourne, Australia 9.3.2014
Заля Патріярха Йосифа Сліпого при катедрі УГКЦ свв.верх.апп. Петра і Павла Patriarch Josyf Slipyj Hall, Sts Peter &amp;amp; Paul Ukrainian Catholic Cathedral Королівський ботанічний сад. Мельбурн, Австралія Royal Botanic Gardens, Melbourne, Australia
Королівський ботанічний сад. Мельбурн, Австралія Royal Botanic Gardens, Melbourne, Australia Частина друга Part 2</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>UCS Heritage Series – KASHTAN Ukrainian Song and Dance Ensemble Inc.</title>
      <link>https://ozeukes.com/culture/ucs-heritage-series-kashtan-ukrainian-song-and-dance-ensemble-inc/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Mar 2014 00:22:25 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ozeukes.com/culture/ucs-heritage-series-kashtan-ukrainian-song-and-dance-ensemble-inc/</guid>
      <description>The Ukrainian Collectibles Society (UCS) has prepared its next issue of the ongoing “Ukrainian Heritage in Australia” stamp and envelope series. The latest featured institution / organisation is:
 * **No. 10: Kashtan Ukrainian Dance and Song Ensemble – 25th Anniversary**  
Full details of this issue and payment details are contained within the Information Sheet: Information Sheet No 7 (H10)
Also attached is the Order Form for this issue: Kashtan order form</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Світове відзначення 200-ліття з дня народження Тараса Шевченка</title>
      <link>https://ozeukes.com/events/international-events/world-celebration-of-taras-shevchenko-200-anniversary-of-birth/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Mar 2014 01:39:48 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ozeukes.com/events/international-events/world-celebration-of-taras-shevchenko-200-anniversary-of-birth/</guid>
      <description>Світова комісія з відзначення 200-ліття з дня народження Тараса Шевченка при Світовому Конґресі Українців (СКУ) закликає всю українську діаспору 9 березня 2014 р. гідно вшанувати Великого Шевченка та разом з цим схилити голови перед світлою пам’яттю полеглих Героїв Небесної сотні.
Подається повністю листа від СКУ в в цій справі, та в якому є параметри як висилати відеокліпи на 5 канал відносно вшанування 200-ліття з дня народження Т. Шевченка. 
28 лютого 2014 р.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Свято Шевченка в Сіднеї</title>
      <link>https://ozeukes.com/events/new-south-wales/shevchenko-concert-in-sydney/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Feb 2014 00:18:12 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ozeukes.com/events/new-south-wales/shevchenko-concert-in-sydney/</guid>
      <description>Об’єднання Українських Громад НПВ запрошує на Святочний Концерт для святкування 200-ліття з дня народження Тараса Шевченка.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hopak in the Park 2014</title>
      <link>https://ozeukes.com/culture/hopak-in-the-park-2014/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Feb 2014 23:56:03 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ozeukes.com/culture/hopak-in-the-park-2014/</guid>
      <description>The Australian Federation of Ukrainian Organisations presents
UKRAINIAN FESTIVAL ‘Hopak in the Park’ Ukrainian Cossack Dance Spectacular 
Due to matters beyond the control of AFUO Virsky Ensemble is unable to perform at HITP
MELBOURNE will spring into action in spectacular style when an army of Ukrainian Cossack dancers hit the Sidney Myer Music Bowl on April 26th, 2014 from 12:30pm to 6.00pm.
Witness a cast of more than 300 Ukrainian dancers from across Australia kick up a storm as they showcase centuries of dazzling dance moves in the outdoor extravaganza Hopak In the Park.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Все про музичну культури української діяспори</title>
      <link>https://ozeukes.com/culture/musical-culture-of-the-ukrainian-diaspora/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Feb 2014 05:45:23 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ozeukes.com/culture/musical-culture-of-the-ukrainian-diaspora/</guid>
      <description>**МАРІЧКА ГАЛАБУРДА – ЧИГРИН****_ _****_Сідней - Австралія 9.2.2014_**
Все про музичну культури української діяспори Подорожуючи Україною, я запізналася з багатьма земляками, цікавими, менше цікавими, з співаками, політиками, письмениками, кіно-акторами, театральними артистами, - а нещодавно заприятелювала ( хай живе інтернетська мережа) з професором Прикарпатського національного університету імені Василя Стефаника - Ганною Карась з Івано-Франківська.
Яким було моє здивування, коли делегація Івано-Франківщини на чолі з паном Михайлом Вишиванюком, яка прилетіла на ХІV Здвиг Українців Австралії у червні минулого 2013 року, вручила від неї подарунок – видану нещодавно монографію** під заголовком «Музична культура української діаспори у світовому часопросторі ХХ століття».</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Нова виставка присвячена Т. Шевченкові</title>
      <link>https://ozeukes.com/culture/new-taras-shevchenko-exhibition/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Jan 2014 02:02:46 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ozeukes.com/culture/new-taras-shevchenko-exhibition/</guid>
      <description>В Єпархіяллному Музеї українського мистецтва ім. Вл. Кир І. Прашка, у парафіяльному залі катедри свв. ап. Петра і Павлі в Мельбурні, відкрито нову виставку, яка присвячена Т. Шевченкові напередодні величавих річниць.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Verchovyna Dance Classes 2014</title>
      <link>https://ozeukes.com/events/victoria/verchovyna-dance-classes-2014/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Jan 2014 23:33:26 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ozeukes.com/events/victoria/verchovyna-dance-classes-2014/</guid>
      <description>Welcome** to 2014****** Dance classes resume Tuesday 11th February 6.00pm at the Ukrainian Hall, Russell Street, Essendon.
NEW DANCERS WELCOME!
If you are new and would like a registration pack please email info@verchovyna.com.au. or say hello to the registration team on the day.
KINDER ENROLMENTS
Dancers are able to join the kinder group at the commencement of Term 1 if they turn 4yrs of age by 30th April 2013.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ПРИХІД СВ. МИКОЛАЯ до СВ. ПОКРОВСЬКОЇ ЦЕРКВИ</title>
      <link>https://ozeukes.com/events/new-south-wales/st-nicholas-visits-homebush/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Jan 2014 03:37:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ozeukes.com/events/new-south-wales/st-nicholas-visits-homebush/</guid>
      <description>МAРІЧКA ГAЛAБУРДA – ЧИГРИН
ПРИХІД СВ. МИКОЛАЯ до СВ. ПОКРОВСЬКОЇ ЦЕРКВИ в ГОМБУШ  Cіднейська св. Покровська Парафія УAПЦ вітала в себе в неділю 12.1.2014 року цікавого гостя - св. Миколая.
Парафіяльна Рада, а зокрема Cестрицтво на чолі з пані Павлою Зелінською приготовлявся дуже ретельно до його приходу.
Відправив Службу Божу настоятель (парох) о. Михайло Смолинець, прислуговував Андрійко Лило. Співав хор під диригентурою Лaриси Ковальчук. Отець Михайло запросив всіх присутніх на Парафіяльний Різдв&#39;яний обід до святочно прибраної залі, де пишалася ялинка, а на столі стояв дуже гарний малюнок-триптих, на тему Різдва.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Вертеп і Різдвяні Колядки в Сіднеї</title>
      <link>https://ozeukes.com/events/new-south-wales/christmas-play-and-carols-in-sydney/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Dec 2013 02:38:13 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ozeukes.com/events/new-south-wales/christmas-play-and-carols-in-sydney/</guid>
      <description>M****АРІЧКА ГАЛАБУРДА - ЧИГРИН
**СІДНЕЙ 23.12.2013 **
ВЕРТЕП і РІЗДВЯНІ КОЛЯДКИ В СІДНЕЇ Різдвяні свята в Україні мають свою споконвічну традицію. Вони супроводжуються величавими церковними відправами, колядками, вертепами, щедрівками і віншуваннями, які звеличують народження Сина Божого.
Окрасою свята є вертепи, театралізовані дійства або знані ще як «народна опера». Вивчити і зберегти традицію святкування українського різдва намагалися члени осередку СУМ-у ім.ґенерала хорунжого Тараса Чупринки в Сіднеї.
Пригадуємо величезну продукцію «Вертепу» поставленого в Домі Молоді в 2004 році і в 2005-му в Перті (Західна Австралія), куди Осередок СУМ-у Сіднею поїхав з Різдвяним концертом і на Крайовий Табір СУМ-у.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Blacksmith&#39;s tree unveiled</title>
      <link>https://ozeukes.com/culture/blacksmiths-tree-unveiled/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Dec 2013 03:14:02 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ozeukes.com/culture/blacksmiths-tree-unveiled/</guid>
      <description>Saturday 30 November 2013 saw the unveiling of the “Blacksmith’s Tree” in Whittlesea, just north of Melbourne, Victoria.

The 9 metre tall forged stainless steel and copper gum tree spanning nearly five metres in diameter was created in response to the Black Saturday fires in Victoria in 2009. This tree is a memorial to the 173 people who lost their lives in the bushfires, to honour the people who defended others and to stand as a symbol of regeneration for the community.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Book Launch - Taste of Ukraine</title>
      <link>https://ozeukes.com/culture/book-launch-taste-of-ukraine/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 03 Nov 2013 03:13:11 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ozeukes.com/culture/book-launch-taste-of-ukraine/</guid>
      <description>The Ukrainian Council of NSW,
And Main Sponsors
Ukrainian Studies Foundation of Australia Ltd,
the L. Sklepkowycz Foundation
sincerely invite you to
the launch of a sensational book
“Taste of Ukraine”.
Sunday 3rd November 2013,
from 12.30 pm
at
The Ukrainian Youth Centre,
3 John St, Lidcombe
 Tasty Ukrainian food will be provided.    There will be an opportunity to buy the  book, signed by the author, S.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Свято Козацької Покрови</title>
      <link>https://ozeukes.com/culture/kozak-feastday-of-blessed-mary-the-protectress/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Oct 2013 01:49:07 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ozeukes.com/culture/kozak-feastday-of-blessed-mary-the-protectress/</guid>
      <description>В неділю 20-го жовтня 2013 р. 8-ий курінь Українського Вільного Козацтва (УВК) Австралії відзначив Свято Козацької Покрови Пресвятої Богородиці.
Відзачення відбулося в Українському Народному Домі в Ессендоні (Мельбурн). В програмі були доповіді, промови священників та концерт з співом, танцями, музикою та деклямаціями.
Після смачного обіду було вручення почесних грамот членам УВК.

Фоторепортаж Тараса Моравського: http://www.flickr.com/photos/moravski/sets/72157636824308374/</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Holodomor 2013 - UCS stamps and envelopes</title>
      <link>https://ozeukes.com/culture/holodomor-2013-ucs-stamps-and-envelopes/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 Oct 2013 02:22:10 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ozeukes.com/culture/holodomor-2013-ucs-stamps-and-envelopes/</guid>
      <description>The Ukrainian Collectibles Society, in recognition of the 80th Anniversary of the Holodomor (the artificial famine and genocide in Ukraine of 1932-1933), is releasing commercial and collectible souvenirs as a tangible and collectible philatelic record.
[caption id=&amp;quot;attachment_7014&amp;rdquo; align=&amp;quot;alignnone&amp;rdquo; width=&amp;quot;600&amp;rdquo;] Holodomor 2013 stamp[/caption]
Information Sheet with details for special commemorative stamp and souvenir envelopes: Information Sheet No.7 (Holodomor)
Order Form for this issue: Holodomor order form
The very last day to order and pay is Monday night, 11 November 2013.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ГРЕЦЬКО-СЕРБСЬКИЙ ФЕСТИВАЛЬ Й МИ</title>
      <link>https://ozeukes.com/events/new-south-wales/greek-serbian-festival-and-us/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 29 Sep 2013 04:39:18 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ozeukes.com/events/new-south-wales/greek-serbian-festival-and-us/</guid>
      <description>МАРІЧКА ГАЛАБУРДА - ЧИГРИН
ГРЕЦЬКО-СЕРБСЬКИЙ ФЕСТИВАЛЬ Й МИ
Все, що відбувається навкруги мене й пов&#39;язане, зокрема з українцями з бувшої Юґославії, мені близьке, бо мій чоловік перебував там до і підчас війни й в Београді ( Белграді) мав зв&#39;язки з Сербською Православною Церквою&amp;hellip;Це окрема тема.****
І ось в неділю 22.9.2013 відбувався в Парафіяльній залі Сербської Православної Церкви ім. св. Стефана в місцевості Plumpton - Rooty Hill ( Захід Сіднею недалеко моєї хати) 20 -ий з черги фестиваль Сербсько-Грецької Дружби, що перетворився в міжнародний фестиваль танців і співу.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Презинтaція книжки “Щастя на краю світу”</title>
      <link>https://ozeukes.com/culture/new-book-release-fortune-at-the-edge-of-the-world/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Sep 2013 10:53:40 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ozeukes.com/culture/new-book-release-fortune-at-the-edge-of-the-world/</guid>
      <description>65 ліття поселення українців в Aвстралії  ПРЕЗИНТAЦІЯ КНИЖКИ “Щастя на краю світу****” відбудеться у КИЄВІ** **
[caption id=&amp;quot;attachment_6943&amp;rdquo; align=&amp;quot;alignnone&amp;rdquo; width=&amp;quot;600&amp;rdquo;] КНИЖКA &amp;ldquo;Щастя на краю світу&amp;rdquo; - Aвтор Олександр Карпенко[/caption]
 Презинтaцію книжки “Щастя на краю світу_”_ відбудеться у Києві в четвер12-го вересня 2013 13.00 год в Конференційні залі, Ярославів Вал 9, Київ.
Виступи:
Олександр Карпенко - Aвтора книжки, **Cтефан Романів **– Голова Cоюзу Українських Організацій Aвстралії, Генеральний секретар Cвітового Конґресу Українців – Виступ - 65 ліття поселенння українців в Aвстралії – Здобутки та виклики</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ukrainian Language course in Ukraine / Курси української мови в Україні</title>
      <link>https://ozeukes.com/culture/ukrainian-language-course-in-ukraineukrainian-language-course-in-ukraine/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 31 Aug 2013 05:39:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ozeukes.com/culture/ukrainian-language-course-in-ukraineukrainian-language-course-in-ukraine/</guid>
      <description>Ukrainian Language &amp;amp; Culture School Two-week intensive course on Ukrainian Language and Culture
**“UKRAINIAN ****AUTUMN IN LVIV 2013” **
 * ** “Golden October in Lviv”**** September, 30-October, 11** * **“Cultural November in Lviv”**** November, 4-15**  Further details (in English): Ukrainian Autumn Lviv En2013 
**Школа****_ _****_української_****_ _****_мови_****_ _****_та_****_ _****_культури_** **2-**тижневі інтенсивні курси української мови та культури
**“**УКРАЇНСЬКА ОСІНЬ У ЛЬВОВІ 2013”
 * **“****Золотий жовтень у Львові” 3****0 вересня-1****1 жовтня** * **“****Культурний листопад у Львові” ****4-1****5 листопада**  Докладніше (по українське): Ukrainian Autumn Lviv Ua2013</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Наталка Полтавка – переслуховування на ролі</title>
      <link>https://ozeukes.com/culture/natalka-poltavka-auditions/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Aug 2013 02:52:25 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ozeukes.com/culture/natalka-poltavka-auditions/</guid>
      <description>Наталка Полтавка – переслуховування на ролі Філія Української Громади Вікторії (УГВ) в Нобл Парку представлятиме оперету «Наталка Полтавка». Переслуховування на ролі відбудуться у вересні 2013р.

Natalka Poltavka – Auditions The Association of Ukrainians in Victorians (AUV) – Noble Park branch – is planning to present the operetta ‘Natalka Poltavka’. Auditions will be held in September 2013.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Інтерв’ю в Україні - Петро Дума</title>
      <link>https://ozeukes.com/culture/interview-in-ukraine-peter-duma/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Aug 2013 01:22:33 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ozeukes.com/culture/interview-in-ukraine-peter-duma/</guid>
      <description>Роман Швед веде радіопрограму в Україні про культуру української діаспори – тут веде інтерв’ю з гостем з Австралії – Петром Думою. Включається музика гурту з Австралії «Yellow Blue Bus».
Roman Shwed conducts a radio program in Ukraine about the culture of the Ukrainian diaspora – here he interviews Peter Duma from Australia and includes the music of the Adelaide-based group “Yellow Blue Bus”.
Інтерв’ю / Interview: http://schedule.nrcu.gov.ua/grid/channel/period/item-listen-popup.html?periodItemID=184014</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>UCS Heritage stamp No. 9</title>
      <link>https://ozeukes.com/culture/ucs-heritage-stamp-no-9/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Aug 2013 01:21:40 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ozeukes.com/culture/ucs-heritage-stamp-no-9/</guid>
      <description>The Ukrainian Collectibles Society (UCS) has released the next issue of the ongoing “Ukrainian Heritage in Australia” stamp and envelope series.
The latest featured institution / organisation is:
 * **No. 9: USC Lion Volleyball Club of Adelaide, SA – 60th Anniversary **  The very last day to order is Monday night, 26 August 2013.

Information Sheet: Information Sheet No 6 (H9)
Order Form: USC Lion order form</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ukrainian Independence Day 2013 in Western Australia</title>
      <link>https://ozeukes.com/events/western-australia/ukrainian-independence-day-2013-in-western-australia/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Jul 2013 00:58:55 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ozeukes.com/events/western-australia/ukrainian-independence-day-2013-in-western-australia/</guid>
      <description>Celebrate Ukrainian Independence Day with the Ukrainian Association of Western Australia at the Inglewood United Soccer Club on Sunday 25th August 2013.
The program will include a 3-course lunch and a concert.

Please book early to avoid embarrassment.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>День Незалежности України – Сідней 2013</title>
      <link>https://ozeukes.com/events/new-south-wales/independence-day-celebrations-sydney-2013/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Jul 2013 02:25:22 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ozeukes.com/events/new-south-wales/independence-day-celebrations-sydney-2013/</guid>
      <description>Управа ОУГ й Організаційний Комітет Концерту в день Незалежности України запрошують все Громадянство Сіднею й околиць на свято.
Будуть висвітленні:
 * фільм Олеся Янчука про встановлення Ялинки з України на площі св. Петра в Ватикані, прийняття делеґації України Папою * Та короткі фільми дітей на тему **«Я українець/українка»** учасників конкурсу СУОА, які були висвітленні в п&#39;ятницю 7.6.2013 день Відкриття Здвигу СУОА в Домі Молоді.  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Multiculturalism in Australia - How is could apply in Ukraine</title>
      <link>https://ozeukes.com/politics/multiculturalism-in-australia-how-is-could-apply-in-ukraine/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Jul 2013 06:21:08 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ozeukes.com/politics/multiculturalism-in-australia-how-is-could-apply-in-ukraine/</guid>
      <description>В червні цього року відбулася конференція в Івано Франківську по питанню націоналізму, етносів в Україні. Організатори Інститут при Cвободі, Центр Національного Відродження ім Cтепана Бандери та інші – Головний організатор О. Cич, попросив Стефана Романіва підготувати матеріял в цій справі до збірника на підставі міжнародного досвіду –
Долучається матеріял для розгляду .
Multiculturalism in Ukraine 27 5 2013
Stefan Romaniw was recently requested to prepare a paper for a Conference in Ukraine on ethnic minorities, policies and a way forward in Ukraine.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>UCS Heritage issue no. 8</title>
      <link>https://ozeukes.com/culture/ucs-heritage-issue-no-8/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jul 2013 04:34:59 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ozeukes.com/culture/ucs-heritage-issue-no-8/</guid>
      <description>The Ukrainian Collectibles Society (UCS) of Australia has issued a Press Release announcing the eighth stamp and envelope in the Ukrainian Heritage in Australia Personalised Stamp™ and souvenir first day of issue envelope series on 1 June 2013. The new stamp is dedicated to the Ukrainian Autocephalic Orthodox Church (UAOC) in Diaspora, Diocese of Australia and New Zealand.

The full Press Release, including purchase details, can be read here: 08 - UCS Press Release UAOC June 2013</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ХІV ЗДВИГ УКРАЇНЦІВ В АВСТРАЛІЇ – Ч. 3</title>
      <link>https://ozeukes.com/culture/national-festival-2013-part-3/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Jun 2013 03:02:44 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ozeukes.com/culture/national-festival-2013-part-3/</guid>
      <description>МАРІЧКА ГАЛАБУРДА-ЧИГРИН
ЗДВИГ СУОА СІДНЕЙ 7, 8, 9 червня 2013 - частина 3 **НЕДІЛЯ: 9.6.2013 **
СЛУЖБА БОЖА Подяка за всі Богом надані нашому суспільтву ласки
В українських церквах УАПЦ і УГКЦ в Сіднеї та всіх містах Австралії, де проживає українське поселення відправлялися з ранку в 9 - годині урочисті Богослужби.
В Свято Покровській Церкві УАПЦ в Гомбуш Богослужбу відправляли о. архипресвітер Володимир Люлька, настоятель Свято-Афанасійської Парафії в Ґренвілі, о. митрофорний протоієрей **о.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ХІV ЗДВИГ УКРАЇНЦІВ В АВСТРАЛІЇ – Ч. 2a</title>
      <link>https://ozeukes.com/culture/national-festival-2013-part-2a/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Jun 2013 02:08:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ozeukes.com/culture/national-festival-2013-part-2a/</guid>
      <description>ДРУГИЙ ДЕНЬ ЗДВИГУ** ****– ****ПРОДОВЖЕННЯ******
МАРІЧКА ГАЛАБУРДА – ЧИГРИН__
СУБОТА 8.6.2013_:_
Тому, що Здвиг тривав лише 3 дні, треба було якось в один день відбути якнайбільше сесій, майстерень, доповідей. Я вже згадувала про те, що фізично було майже неможливо бути всюди, оскільки в один час відбувалися події&amp;hellip;
В будинку **Дому Молоді **на другому поверсі СУМ і ПЛАСТ провели виставку своїх історичних матеріялів.
**А Відділ Союзу Українок ім. Оьги Басараб **має там свою кімнату, де постійно знаходиться виставка прикладного народного мистецьтва, яка дуже популярна серед відвідувачів.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ХІV ЗДВИГ УКРАЇНЦІВ В АВСТРАЛІЇ – Ч. 2</title>
      <link>https://ozeukes.com/culture/national-festival-2013-part-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Jun 2013 06:48:47 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ozeukes.com/culture/national-festival-2013-part-2/</guid>
      <description>ДРУГИЙ ДЕНЬ ЗДВИГУ
 МАРІЧКА ГАЛАБУРДА – ЧИГРИН
****СУБОТА 8.6.2013_:_
ПЕРЕДАЧА ПОЖЕРТВИ &amp;quot;ФОНДУ КАРПАТИ&amp;quot; УКРАЇНСЬКІЙ ШКОЛІ ім.св. Андрія
**У суботу 8.6.2013 у 10****-****ій годині** ранку в програмі Здвигу Українців в приміщенні братської школи ім св. Андрія в Лідкомбі відбулося вручення грошей, пожертви Фундації &amp;ldquo;КАРПАТИ&amp;rdquo;, головного спонзора Здвигу учителям і дітям, які 22.6.ц.р. збираються Києві, столиці України, щоби розпочати прогульку в батьківщині своїх батьків.
Присутніми були: Голова Союзу Українських Організацій Стефан Романів, Голова Фундації Володмир Войтович та секретар Ярослав Дума, батьки дітей та кілька гостей.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ХІV ЗДВИГ УКРАЇНЦІВ В АВСТРАЛІЇ - Ч. 1</title>
      <link>https://ozeukes.com/culture/national-festival-2013-part-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Jun 2013 05:58:36 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ozeukes.com/culture/national-festival-2013-part-1/</guid>
      <description>МАРІЧКА ГАЛАБУРДА – ЧИГРИН
СІДНЕЙ 12.6.2009** **
ХІV ЗДВИГ УКРАЇНЦІВ В АВСТРАЛІЇ** **
В днях від 7 – 9 червня 2013 року в Сіднеї з великим успіхом пройшов Здвиг Українців Австралії. Здвиг був ювілейним, бо українці відзначали 65 – ти ліття свого побуту в цій країні.
Українська діяспора в Австралії є одна з наймолодших українських поселень в світі. В 1947 - му році прибуло до Австралії кількадесятків українських родин. В 1948 і в 1949 - му році українці, тзв політичні еміґранти (displaced persons) масово прибули до Австралії — початок української діяспори в цій країні датується 1948 - 1949 - го року.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Open Forum with Orysia Tracz</title>
      <link>https://ozeukes.com/culture/open-forum-with-orysia-tracz/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Jun 2013 10:56:38 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ozeukes.com/culture/open-forum-with-orysia-tracz/</guid>
      <description>[[[](http://www.ozeukes.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/06/CYM_Emblema-150x150-72dpi.jpg)](http://www.ozeukes.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/06/UECA-logo-thumb.jpg)](http://www.ozeukes.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/06/AUV-Colour-thumb.jpg)
**Australian Federation of Ukrainian Organisations Association of Ukrainians in Victoria Ukrainian Council of Education in Australia CYM Ukrainian Youth Association in Melbourne Plast Ukrainian Youth Association in Victoria **
** **
Invitation to our Young Families, Mixed marriages, Youth and Young Adults and all other members and friends of the community ** **
Open Forum and discussion &amp;lsquo;Let&#39;s have a heart to heart !&#39; ** **
Ukrainian ! Being a part of it - What does it mean ?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Гідно проведено Здвиг Укрaїнців Aвcтрaлії</title>
      <link>https://ozeukes.com/culture/successful-national-ukrainian-festival-in-australia/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Jun 2013 00:48:01 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ozeukes.com/culture/successful-national-ukrainian-festival-in-australia/</guid>
      <description>[ ](http://www.ozeukes.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/06/ZdvyhLogoFinal-ENG-thumb.jpg)Successful National Ukrainian Festival in Australia
The Australian Federation of Ukrainian Organisations (AFUO) has announced that an extremely successful and enjoyable XIV National Festival of Ukrainians in Australia has come to a close.
The full text of the press release (in English) can be read here: UKRAINIAN NATIONAL FESTIVAL IN AUSTRALIA A HUGE SUCCESS Eng
Photos of the events may be viewed on the following sites: http://zdvyh2013.shutterfly.com/ http://www.flickr.com/photos/moravski/sets/72157634053852860/
[ ](http://www.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ukrainian Youth Short Film Festival 2013 - Results</title>
      <link>https://ozeukes.com/culture/ukrainian-youth-short-film-festival-2013-results/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Jun 2013 05:18:52 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ozeukes.com/culture/ukrainian-youth-short-film-festival-2013-results/</guid>
      <description>[ ](http://www.ozeukes.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/06/Film-Poster-thumb.jpg)Inaugural Ukrainian Youth Short Film Festival
“I am Ukrainian” Young people were invited to interpret this phrase by making a short film to express how they saw their Ukrainian identity and heritage.
The films had to be original and can be realistic, experimental, digital manipulations, humorous, animations or serious: above all, personal, creative and entertaining, opening our eyes to the way young people see what &amp;ldquo;being Ukrainian&amp;rdquo; means to them.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>СВЯТО МАТЕРІ В КАБРАМАТТІ</title>
      <link>https://ozeukes.com/culture/mothers-day-in-cabramatta/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 May 2013 02:09:04 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ozeukes.com/culture/mothers-day-in-cabramatta/</guid>
      <description>_МAРІЧКA ГAЛAБУРДA–ЧИГРИН_
26.5.2013
**СВЯТО МАТЕРІ В КАБРАМАТТІ **
В **неділю 26.5.2013 **коли традиційно по світах вшановували Героїв України, а в Україні по багатьох містах проходили паради вишивок, ми в Сіднеї, можна твердити частинно долучилися до світової акції паради вишивок.

Громадяство Західньою Сіднею зійшлося черговий раз в домівці Української Громади Кабраматта-Ферфілд, щоби вшановувати - Матір Божу, матір Україну i свою українську маму.
Свято відкрив пан Петро Грещук, новообраний голова Громади, вітаючи всіх мамів й бабусь, передаючи мені ведення Свята.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>FLINDERS QUARTET with Dmitry Onishchenko</title>
      <link>https://ozeukes.com/culture/flinders-quartet-with-dmitry-onishchenko/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 May 2013 02:26:26 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ozeukes.com/culture/flinders-quartet-with-dmitry-onishchenko/</guid>
      <description>MEDIA RELEASE
MEDIA ENQUIRIES: Kate Mazoudier 0403 497 424
**Flinders Quartet to launch 2013 season with **prize-winning virtuoso Dmitry Onishchenko

_Opening its 2013 subscription series with trademark flare and virtuosity, Flinders Quartet proudly welcomes the winner of the 2012 Sydney International Piano Competition (SIPCA) ‘Flinders Quartet Prize’, Ukrainian pianist Dmitry Onishchenko, as their guest in a concert of Shostakovich, Ravel and Ian Munro. _
Hand-picked by the quartet to tour with them in 2013, Dimitry also won the Australian Music Prize and the prize for Best Performance of a Debussy work at the Sydney International Piano Competition in 2012.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>VIPs Support Ukrainian Australian National Festival</title>
      <link>https://ozeukes.com/culture/vips-support-ukrainian-australian-national-festival/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 May 2013 07:51:58 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ozeukes.com/culture/vips-support-ukrainian-australian-national-festival/</guid>
      <description>May 8, 2013
MEDIA RELEASE
VIPS SUPPORTING UKRAINIAN AUSTRALIAN NATIONAL FESTIVAL
Elected officials and other community VIPs are strongly supporting the National Festival of Ukrainian Australians to be held in Sydney from June 7 to June 9, 2013.
Those attending the Concert program at Sydney Town Hall on the afternoon of June 9th include: senior representatives of political parties; Federal, NSW, and local Government, and; a range of fellow ethnic communities.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>XIV Здвиг Українців Aвстралії - квитки нa продaж</title>
      <link>https://ozeukes.com/culture/xiv-national-ukrainian-festival-tickets-now-on-sale/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 May 2013 02:25:34 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ozeukes.com/culture/xiv-national-ukrainian-festival-tickets-now-on-sale/</guid>
      <description>ПОВІДОМЛЕННЯ - КВИТКИ НA ПРОДAЖ
XIV Здвиг Українців Aвстралії
Квитки на Забаву 8.6.2013_ _
Грає оркестра з Канади Тут і Там
 та на
 Концерт 9.6.2013 Sydney Town Hall
 Квитки можна замовити на сайті
https://sydneyzdvyh2013.iwannaticket.com.au/
 
XIV National Ukrainian Festival TICKETS NOW ON SALE
Zabava Saturday 8 June 2013 Band from Canada Tyt i Tam
Gala Concert Sunday June 9, 2013 Sydney Town Hall
Tickets can be purchased at</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ВЕЛИКДЕНЬ В CІДНЕЇ - 2013</title>
      <link>https://ozeukes.com/culture/ukrainian-easter-in-sydney-2013/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 May 2013 01:51:30 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ozeukes.com/culture/ukrainian-easter-in-sydney-2013/</guid>
      <description>**_МАРІЧКА ГАЛАБУРДА - ЧИГРИН_**
ВЕЛИКДЕНЬ В CІДНЕЇ
Божественні Великодні відправи в українських церквах Cіднею відбулися в **суботу 4- го травня 2013 року. **
В українській греко-католицькій церкві св. Андрія в Лідкомбі, біля плащениці від її виносу в п&#39;ятницю 3.5. члени Спілки Української Молоді, навіть наймолодші, тримали почесну варту біля гробу Божого. Приємно було побачити дуже багато людей, а зокрема дітей у і біля церкви.
Святу Богослужби відправляли о. парох Симон Цькуй, о.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>HAPPY EASTER - UKRAINIAN STYLE</title>
      <link>https://ozeukes.com/culture/happy-easter-ukrainian-style/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 May 2013 02:03:12 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ozeukes.com/culture/happy-easter-ukrainian-style/</guid>
      <description>**[ ](http://www.ozeukes.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/05/CYOA-Letterhead-2012-600pxls.jpg)ВІТAННЯ З НAГОДИ ХРИCТОВОГО ВОCКРЕCІННЯ!**
Управа Союзу Українських Організацій Австралії (CУОA) бажає Вам гарно провести наближаюче Cвято Воскресіння Христове!
Воскресіння Христове приносить нам, нове світло, нову ясність нове життя та дає силу.
Тому нехай ті прикмети наповнять нас та нашу спільноту та всіх складових части CУОA новим надхненням вести нашу працю, наш служіння Богові та Україні та Aвстралії , хочби часами в не легких обставинах.
Бажаємо Вам та Вашим родинам смачої Паски, спільо провести ці Cвята в мирі, любові та спокою!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Support for the National Festival of Ukrainian Australians</title>
      <link>https://ozeukes.com/culture/support-for-the-national-festival-of-ukrainian-australians/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Apr 2013 06:20:32 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ozeukes.com/culture/support-for-the-national-festival-of-ukrainian-australians/</guid>
      <description>[caption id=&amp;quot;attachment_6518&amp;rdquo; align=&amp;quot;alignleft&amp;rdquo; width=&amp;quot;150&amp;rdquo;] The Hon Victor Dominello MP[/caption]
Momentum for the National Festival of Ukrainian Australians continues to build with the Hon Victor Dominello MP, the NSW Minister for Citizenship and Communities, agreeing to be the event&#39;s Guest of Honour. The Minister has also provided support for the AFUO&#39;s Statement on Multiculturalism.
Letter from the Hon Victor Dominello MP, NSW Minister for Citizenship and Communities: Dominello letter 2838_0001</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Перше коло спонсорів XIV Здвигу Українців Австралії</title>
      <link>https://ozeukes.com/culture/%d0%bf%d0%b5%d1%80%d1%88%d0%b5-%d0%ba%d0%be%d0%bb%d0%be-%d1%81%d0%bf%d0%be%d0%bd%d1%81%d0%be%d1%80%d1%96%d0%b2-xiv-%d0%b7%d0%b4%d0%b2%d0%b8%d0%b3%d1%83-%d1%83%d0%ba%d1%80%d0%b0%d1%97%d0%bd%d1%86%d1%96/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Apr 2013 06:09:01 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ozeukes.com/culture/%d0%bf%d0%b5%d1%80%d1%88%d0%b5-%d0%ba%d0%be%d0%bb%d0%be-%d1%81%d0%bf%d0%be%d0%bd%d1%81%d0%be%d1%80%d1%96%d0%b2-xiv-%d0%b7%d0%b4%d0%b2%d0%b8%d0%b3%d1%83-%d1%83%d0%ba%d1%80%d0%b0%d1%97%d0%bd%d1%86%d1%96/</guid>
      <description>[ ](http://www.ozeukes.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/04/ZdvyhLogoFinal-UKR-thumb.jpg)Перше коло спонсорів XIV Здвигу Українців Австралії
Перше коло українських організацій засвідчили свою фінансову підтримку XIV-го Здвигу українців Австралії, який відбудеться в Сіднеї, 7-9 го червня 2013 року.
Організації, які насьогодні засвідчили свою допомогу:
 * **Фундація Карпати** * **ФУСА** * **СУМ Сідней** * **Пласт Сідней** * **Українська Православна Парафія Покрови Пресвятої Богородиці, Гомбуш ** * **Українська Католицька Парафія Св.Андрія, Лідкомб, ** * **Сіднейська Кредитова Спілка (SCU)******  &amp;ldquo;Союз Українських Організацій Австралії (СУОА) висловлює щиру подяку та признання цим організаціям та церквам.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>UCS Heritage stamp issue No. 8</title>
      <link>https://ozeukes.com/culture/ucs-heritage-stamp-issue-no-8/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Apr 2013 10:06:11 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ozeukes.com/culture/ucs-heritage-stamp-issue-no-8/</guid>
      <description>The Ukrainian Collectibles Society (UCS) has released the next issue of the ongoing “Ukrainian Heritage in Australia” stamp and envelope series.
The latest featured institution is:
 * No. 8: Ukrainian Autocephalic Orthodox Church in Diaspora, Diocese of Australia and New Zealand  Details of this issue can be found on the information sheet: Information Sheet No 5
The order form can be printed from: Orthodox order form
The final day to order is Monday night, 20 May 2013.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>XIV National Ukrainian Festival</title>
      <link>https://ozeukes.com/culture/xiv-national-ukrainian-festival/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Apr 2013 08:03:49 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ozeukes.com/culture/xiv-national-ukrainian-festival/</guid>
      <description>The XIV National Ukrainian Festival will be held in Sydney on 7th – 9th June 2013.
The Festival will be held under the auspice of the Australian Federation of Ukrainian Organisations and hosted by the Ukrainian Council of NSW.
This year&#39;s theme: 65th Anniversary of Ukrainian Settlement in Australia. Past, Present, Future!
XIV National Ukrainian Festival New Website Launched! For up-to-date and extended information visit website zdvyh.ozeukes.com 
The three day festival has a fantastic program of events catering to a wide-ranging audience</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Danny McGinlay - Hypertonic</title>
      <link>https://ozeukes.com/culture/danny-mcginlay-hypertonic/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Apr 2013 10:35:36 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ozeukes.com/culture/danny-mcginlay-hypertonic/</guid>
      <description>Danny McGinlay (known to Ukrainian Australians through his guest appearance at “Hopak in the Park”) had a well-received show at last year’s Comedy Festival - Danny McGinlay Learns Ukrainian. Well, Danny’s back!
In the past year Danny McGinlay has learned Ukrainian, got married and travelled the world. His brand new show, _Hypertonic, _about cramming more into a year than most cram into a decade, is showing from 9th to 21st April 2013 at the Melbourne International Comedy Festival.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Виставка ікон над морем</title>
      <link>https://ozeukes.com/culture/icon-exhibition-by-the-sea/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Apr 2013 00:21:43 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ozeukes.com/culture/icon-exhibition-by-the-sea/</guid>
      <description>_МAРІЧКA ГAЛAБУРДA–ЧИГРИН__ __31.3.2013_
Наша землячка Роза Лукіяненко бувала в церкві Св. Покрови в Гомбуш, щоби нас повідомити, що відбудеться вистава її ікон в приміщенні Церкви над морем - Chapel on the Sea в Bondi.
На відкриття ми не їздили, бо в п&#39;ятницю та ще вечером на 18.00 годину добратися до місцевості Бондай, це дуже складна справа, через великий автовий рух. В неділю 31.3.2013 на латинський Великдень ми поїхали подивитися на виставу.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>&#34;Rodyna and Friends&#34; Concert</title>
      <link>https://ozeukes.com/culture/rodyna-and-friends-concert/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 30 Mar 2013 02:46:45 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ozeukes.com/culture/rodyna-and-friends-concert/</guid>
      <description>An invitation to the big concert &amp;ldquo;Rodyna and Friends&amp;rdquo; that will take place on 19/5/2013 in the Ukrainian House in Essendon.
The concert is an official launch of the recently released CD “Ukrainian songs for the heart and soul”
[](http://www.ozeukes.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/Concert-flyer-english.jpg)</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Taras Shevchenko Concert 2013 in Western Australia</title>
      <link>https://ozeukes.com/culture/taras-shevchenko-concert-2013-in-western-australia/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Mar 2013 00:06:23 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ozeukes.com/culture/taras-shevchenko-concert-2013-in-western-australia/</guid>
      <description>The Ukrainian Association of Western Australia is having a commemorative concert in honour of Taras Shevchenko on Sunday 24 March 2013 at the Ukrainian Catholic Hall in Maylands, WA.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Свято Шевченка у Мельборні</title>
      <link>https://ozeukes.com/culture/shevchenko-commemoration-in-melbourne-2013/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Mar 2013 00:38:16 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ozeukes.com/culture/shevchenko-commemoration-in-melbourne-2013/</guid>
      <description>У березневі Шевченківські Дні українці всього світу вшановують пам’ять пророка України – Тараса Григоровича Шевченка, свято виконують його заповіт:
Спільнота Української Громади Вікторії урочисто вшанувала Великого сина української нації Тараса Шевченка в неділю, 17 березня в залі Українського Народного Дому в Есеендоні.
Величаве свято розпочалося вступним словом голови УГВ М. Моравського та покладанням квітів до символічної могили Кобзаря сумівцями і пластунами.
Мистецька програма розпочалася славнозвісним “Заповітом” обр.Л.Ревуцького, у виконанні капели “Черемош” СУМ, кер.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SBS Radio - До УВАГИ!!!</title>
      <link>https://ozeukes.com/culture/sbs-radio-%d0%b4%d0%be-%d1%83%d0%b2%d0%b0%d0%b3%d0%b8/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Mar 2013 00:06:44 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ozeukes.com/culture/sbs-radio-%d0%b4%d0%be-%d1%83%d0%b2%d0%b0%d0%b3%d0%b8/</guid>
      <description>THIS IS A FIRST TIME THE UKRAINIAN CHOIR OF MOSCOW IN AUSTRALIA…
Multiculturalism and Ukrainians around the World. Interview with conductor of the Ukrainian Vocal Choir of Moscow Victoria Skopenko after Slavic Pancake festival in Melbourne and concert in Ukrainian community. This is a first time the Ukrainian Choir of Moscow in Australia…
ЦЕ ПЕРШИЙ РАЗ УКРАЇНСЬКА ХОРОВА КАПЕЛА З МОСКВИ В АВСТРАЛІЇ&amp;hellip;
Багатокультурність та українці в усьому світі. Інтерв&#39;ю з художнім керівником Української Хорової Капели Москви Вікторією Скопенко після слов&#39;янського фестивалю “Масляниця” в Мельбурні та зустрічі-концерту в українській громаді…</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>КОНЦЕРТ В ШАНУ ТАРАСА ШЕВЧЕНКА - Сідней 2013</title>
      <link>https://ozeukes.com/culture/shevchenko-concert-in-sydney-2013/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Mar 2013 05:36:49 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ozeukes.com/culture/shevchenko-concert-in-sydney-2013/</guid>
      <description>**_МАРІЧКА ГАЛАБУРДА — ЧИГРИН_****__**
Сідней, 11.3.2013** **
В ЧЕCТЬ ТАРАСА ШЕВЧЕНКА В СІДНЕЇ
ЩОБИ НАШУ ЗЕМЛЮ НЕ ТОПТАВ МОСКАЛЬ
 Українська спільнота **Сіднею **та Нової Південної Валії вшанувала пророка українського народу Тараса Шевченка в переповненій залі Дому Української Молоді в неділю, 10 - го березня ц.р.
З доручення Управи ОУГ я мала шану з&#39;організувати концерт і відкрити його. В свойому вступному слові сказала: &amp;hellip;- &amp;hellip;- Дивлячись на сьогоднішню ситуацію в Україні приходимо до переконання, що Тарас Шевченко – в ті далекі кріпацькі роки, - перший остеріг тодішню українську інтеліґенцію не наносити “ з чужого поля великих слів велику силу&amp;hellip;”.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>УКРАЇНЦІ У СВІТІ: МОВА, КУЛЬТУРА, ІДЕНТИЧНІСТЬ</title>
      <link>https://ozeukes.com/culture/ukrainians-around-the-world-language-culture-identity/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 Mar 2013 01:12:58 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ozeukes.com/culture/ukrainians-around-the-world-language-culture-identity/</guid>
      <description>Кілька об&#39;єктивних і суб&#39;єктивних думок і штрихів до сучасного стану українства та медії опісля конференції в Університеті ім. Монаша, Мельбурн. І не тільки мова йде про це в інтерв&#39;ю Богдана Рудницького із професором Аллою Бойко і професором Наталією Сидоренко із Інституту Журналістики Національного університету ім. Тараса Шевченка. Цей навчальний заклад є одним із найстарших і найбільших вузів в Україні&amp;hellip;
http://www.sbs.com.au/yourlanguage/ukrainian/highlight/page/id/257098/t/UKRAINIANS-AROUND-THE-WORLD-LANGUAGE-CULTURE-IDENTITY</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>AFUO STATEMENT ON MULTICULTURALISM</title>
      <link>https://ozeukes.com/culture/afuo-statement-on-multiculturalism/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Mar 2013 00:06:14 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ozeukes.com/culture/afuo-statement-on-multiculturalism/</guid>
      <description>The Australian Federation of Ukrainian Organisations (AFUO) strongly supports the principles of multiculturalism. The AFUO has issued the following statement defining its commitment to these principles: MULTICULTURALISM STATEMENT
Further to this, the Ukrainian Australians invite Australians of all backgrounds to join them in Sydney on the June long weekend as Ukrainians commemorate 65 years of positive contribution to Australia: AFUO news release - National Festival in Sydney</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>НА ПАМ&#39;ЯТЬ ГЕРОЇВ УПА - СІДНЕЙ 2013</title>
      <link>https://ozeukes.com/culture/commemorating-upa-heroes-sydney-2013/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Mar 2013 01:24:48 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ozeukes.com/culture/commemorating-upa-heroes-sydney-2013/</guid>
      <description>**_МАРІЧКА ГАЛАБУРДА-ЧИГРИН_**
СІДНЕЙ неділя 3.3.2013
**У СІДНЕЇ ВШАНУВАЛИ ПАМ&#39;ЯТЬ ГЕРОЇВ УПА ** В неділю 3 -го березня, в Українському Домі Молоді в Лідкомбі (Сідней) зібралися сумівці та члени нашої спільноти, щоби вшанувати пам&#39;ять патрона Осередку СУМ ґен. хор. Тараса Чупринку, який загинув 5.3.1950 року в Білогорщі, - 70–ту річницю УПА (яка припадала в 2010 ), бувших вояків УПА, які жили в Сіднею й були основоположниками осередку СУМ-у.
Ранком сумівці в одностроях, з прапорами, були присутніми на Богослужбі в УГКЦеркви ім.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Представники Української народної хорової капели Москви в Aвстралії</title>
      <link>https://ozeukes.com/culture/members-of-ukrainian-choir-from-moscow-in-australia/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Mar 2013 02:45:56 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ozeukes.com/culture/members-of-ukrainian-choir-from-moscow-in-australia/</guid>
      <description>Представники Української народної хорової капели Москви в Aвстралії До Австралії прибули на короткий час представники Української народної хорової капели Москви, разом із мистецьким керівником хору пані Вікторія Cкопенко.
Так як в Москві та в інших країнах де виступає Хор так і на сцені у Федерайшон Cквер в суботу 2-го березня 2013р. Хор гідно, гордо та безкомпромісово представляв українську пісню, українську культуру на багатокультурному, словянському фестивалі організовано російською та сербаськими громадами - в які брали участь мистецькі колективи сербської, польської, російської, словацької та української громад Вікторії .</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ЗДВИГ УКРAЇНЦІВ В AВCТРAЛІЇ</title>
      <link>https://ozeukes.com/culture/national-ukrainian-festival/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 17 Feb 2013 02:26:40 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ozeukes.com/culture/national-ukrainian-festival/</guid>
      <description>**ЗДВИГ УКРAЇНЦІВ В AВCТРAЛІЇ **- сідней 7-9 червня 2013
65 ліття посe_лення українців в Aвстралії _,
Шанувати минуле – **** Зміцнювати майбутнє! Вчора, Cьогодні, Завтра!
Управа Cоюзу Українських Організацій Aвстралії підтверджує попередні повідомлення, що в рамках програми 2013 програми - Відзнaчення 65 ліття посe_лення українців в Aвстралії _, _в днях 7-9 червня 2013 в Cіднею відбудеться ___Здвиг Українців Aвстралії.
Наші святкування проходитимуть під гаслом ;
_Шанувати минуле – **** Зміцнювати майбутнє!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Шевченківське Свято 2013 - Сідней</title>
      <link>https://ozeukes.com/culture/shevchenko-concert-2013-sydney/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Feb 2013 23:51:21 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ozeukes.com/culture/shevchenko-concert-2013-sydney/</guid>
      <description>Об’єднання Українських Громад НПВ запрошує все українське громадянство на «Шевченківське Свято» яке відбудеться в неділю 10-го березня 2013р. в залі Дому Української Молоді в Лідкомбі.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Свято Шевченка 2013 – Мельбурн</title>
      <link>https://ozeukes.com/culture/taras-shevchenko-concert-2013-melbourne/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Feb 2013 03:17:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ozeukes.com/culture/taras-shevchenko-concert-2013-melbourne/</guid>
      <description>Свято Шевченка 2013 – Мельбурн Українська Громада Вікторії (УГВ) запрошує все громадянство на «Свято Шевченка» яке відбудеться в неділю 17-го березня 2013 р. о годині 1:30 пп. в Українському Народному Домі, Ессендон.

Taras Shevchenko concert 2013 - Melbourne The Association of Ukrainians in Victoria (AUV) invites all to a concert in honour of Taras Shevchenko to be held on Sunday 17th March 2013 at 1:30 pm in the Ukrainian House, 2-11 Russell Street, Essendon.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Queensland’s Ukrainian community welcomes violin sensation</title>
      <link>https://ozeukes.com/culture/queenslands-ukrainian-community-welcomes-violin-sensation/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 31 Jan 2013 00:05:52 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ozeukes.com/culture/queenslands-ukrainian-community-welcomes-violin-sensation/</guid>
      <description>Attilla Sautov, the renowned violinist, will be at the Ukrainian Community Centre in South Brisbane on Saturday 23 February 2013 at 3 p.m., for a performance with the Mueller International Chamber Orchestra and a beautiful new extremely versatile program, with supporting performances by talented local Ukrainian classical singers and musicians:
 * Larrisa Brooker - Soprano * Lyudmila Kelloway - Mezzo Soprano * Iryna Penner - Piano, and * Tomas Miljenovic - Clarinet.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Verchovyna Dance Ensembles seeking dancers for a new Touring Production</title>
      <link>https://ozeukes.com/culture/verchovyna-dance-ensembles-seeking-dancers-for-a-new-touring-production/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Jan 2013 01:31:15 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ozeukes.com/culture/verchovyna-dance-ensembles-seeking-dancers-for-a-new-touring-production/</guid>
      <description>The Verchovyna Ukrainian Dance Ensemble in Melbourne is working on a new Touring Production, “Kazka”, and is seeking experienced dancers to become part of the touring group.
Full details can be read here: Verchovyna Ukrainian Dance Ensemble is seeking dancers for a new Touring Production</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Спільна коляда Союзу Українок в Сіднеї</title>
      <link>https://ozeukes.com/culture/carols-in-sydney-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Jan 2013 06:31:15 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ozeukes.com/culture/carols-in-sydney-2/</guid>
      <description>МАРІЧКА ГАЛАБУРДА-ЧИГРИН
СПІЛЬНА КОЛЯДА СОЮЗУ УКРАЇНОК в СІДНЕЇ Завершення Різдв&#39;яниx Святкувань в Сіднею закінчився в неділю 20.1.2013 року, в день після свята Йордану, останнім концертом колядок в Народному Домі в Сіднеї.
Імпрезу організував Союз Українок - Стейтова Управа з всіма відділами, ім. книгині Ольги, (голова Марта Менцінська) ім. Ольги Басараб (Голова Одарка Брецко) ім. Олени Пчілки (голова Христина Бейлі) , ім. Лесі Українки (Валя Домазар), суспільна Опіка відділ ім. Хариті Кононенко (голова Антоніна Війтович) ім.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Щедрий Вечір в Нобл Парку</title>
      <link>https://ozeukes.com/culture/theophany-evening-in-noble-park/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Jan 2013 03:54:54 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ozeukes.com/culture/theophany-evening-in-noble-park/</guid>
      <description>Філія Української Громади Вікторії (УГВ) в Нобл Парку запрошує всіх на Щедрий Вечір.

The Noble Park branch of the Association of Ukrainians in Victoria (AUV) invites all to the traditional celebration of Theophany Evening.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ukrainian Youth Short Film Competition 2013</title>
      <link>https://ozeukes.com/culture/ukrainian-youth-short-film-competition-2013/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Dec 2012 09:32:45 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ozeukes.com/culture/ukrainian-youth-short-film-competition-2013/</guid>
      <description>Оновлення інформації! Updated information!  Thank you to all those who submitted entries into the inaugural “Ukrainian Youth Short Film Festival”.   As it is an innovation that has caught some unprepared for all the work that has to go into producing and submitting, in order to include those who are still making an effort to participate, the deadline has been extended to MONDAY 20th May 5 pm.   There will be no further extensions.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Прихід Св. Миколая до Св. Покровської Церкви в Гомбуш</title>
      <link>https://ozeukes.com/culture/%d0%bf%d1%80%d0%b8%d1%85%d1%96%d0%b4-%d1%81%d0%b2-%d0%bc%d0%b8%d0%ba%d0%be%d0%bb%d0%b0%d1%8f-%d0%b4%d0%be-%d1%81%d0%b2-%d0%bf%d0%be%d0%ba%d1%80%d0%be%d0%b2%d1%81%d1%8c%d0%ba%d0%be%d1%97-%d1%86%d0%b5/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Dec 2012 05:22:11 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ozeukes.com/culture/%d0%bf%d1%80%d0%b8%d1%85%d1%96%d0%b4-%d1%81%d0%b2-%d0%bc%d0%b8%d0%ba%d0%be%d0%bb%d0%b0%d1%8f-%d0%b4%d0%be-%d1%81%d0%b2-%d0%bf%d0%be%d0%ba%d1%80%d0%be%d0%b2%d1%81%d1%8c%d0%ba%d0%be%d1%97-%d1%86%d0%b5/</guid>
      <description>МAРІЧКA ГAЛAБУРДA–ЧИГРИН
ПРИХІД СВ. МИКОЛАЯ до СВ. ПОКРОВСЬКОЇ ЦЕРКВИ в ГОМБУШ
Cіднейська св. Покровська Парафія УAПЦ вітала в неділю 23.12.2012 року цікавого гостя - св. Миколая.
Приготовлявся дуже ретельно до прийняття св. Миколая Парафіяльна Рада і зокрема Cестрицтво на чолі з пані Павлою Зелінською та Тамарою Базалицькою, оскільки це було перше таке свято для молодого настоятеля Парафії о. Михайла Cмолинця, який дуже старається притягнути, радше повернути молодих людей до Церкви.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Празник в Свято Миколаївській Парафії УАПЦ в Канбері</title>
      <link>https://ozeukes.com/culture/st-nicholas-feast-day-in-canberra/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Dec 2012 04:51:13 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ozeukes.com/culture/st-nicholas-feast-day-in-canberra/</guid>
      <description>**_МАРІЧКА ГАЛАБУРДА-ЧИГРИН_****__**
ПРАЗНИКИ, СВЯТА&amp;hellip; ПРАЗНИК В СВЯТО МИКОЛАЇВСЬКІЙ ПАРАФІЇ УАПЦ в КАНБЕРІ Щорічне Храмове свято Св. Миколаївської Парафії УАПЦ в Канбері відбулося в неділю 16.12.2012. Мене запросили ще у липні, коли була перед поїздкою до Бельгії в Канбері, приїхати на свято.
Святу Літургію відправляли п&#39;ять ( 5 ) священиків: о. Володимир Люлька (Сідней-Ґренвіл) о. Михайло Соломко – настоятель парафії (Канберра), о. Василь Касіян (Джілонґ) – о.** Єфстахій Дорош **(Сідней-Блектав), о. **Михайло Смолинець** (Сідней-Гомбуш).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>КОЛЯДКИ У КАБРАМАТТІ</title>
      <link>https://ozeukes.com/culture/carols-in-cabramatta/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Dec 2012 01:25:26 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ozeukes.com/culture/carols-in-cabramatta/</guid>
      <description>МАРІЧКА ГАЛАБУРДА–ЧИГРИН
Сідней 23.12.2012
КОЛЯДКИ У КАБРАМАТТІ Тоді коли десь у світах бушували стихії, а в Австралії божевільно палюче, сонце спекотно гріло, а країни Европи й Україну морози й замели сніговії, - **в неділю 23 грудня 2012 **суспільство Західнього Сіднею відбуло в Громадському Домі в Кабраматті Передріздв&#39;яну Зустріч.
Управа Громади небула певна скільки людей прибуде, була навіть мова про переложення свята на січень місяць, але тоді на ту же неділю припадало би аж три імпрези.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Рідзв&#39;яне побажання від Управи CУОA</title>
      <link>https://ozeukes.com/culture/christmas-greetings-from-afuo-committee-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Dec 2012 01:41:29 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ozeukes.com/culture/christmas-greetings-from-afuo-committee-2/</guid>
      <description>[ ](http://www.ozeukes.com/wp-content/uploads/2012/12/CYOA-Letterhead-2012-600pxls.jpg)
Рідзв&#39;яне побажання від Управи CУОA З радісним Празником Різдва Христового Управа Cоюзу Українських Організацій Aвстралії (CУОA)
вітає
Український нарід, Ієрархів та духовенство всіх Українських Церков, працівників Посольства України в Канберрі , CКУ,УВКР членів CУОA, проводи та членів українських організацій та установ , працівників суспільно - громадського та політичних організацій, працівників суспільної опіки, працівників рідного шкільництва та університетських осередків україністики діячів культури та мистецтва , працівників преси та радіомовлення, працівників кооперативного , наших членів які знаходяться в Дому Cтарших, нашу молодь та наших родин та всю українську організовану спільноту.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Український Вільний Університет</title>
      <link>https://ozeukes.com/culture/ukrainian-free-university/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 08 Dec 2012 01:53:50 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ozeukes.com/culture/ukrainian-free-university/</guid>
      <description>**_МАРІЧКА ГАЛАБУРДА-ЧИГРИН_**
Український Вільний Університет На прийнятті підчас Храмового Cвята в Мюнхені, я познайомилася з новопризначеною ректоркою Українського Вільного Університету пі. др.проф. Ярославою Мельник, яка сиділа біля мене і запросила відвідати УВУ, його нове приміщення, щоби розповісти в Aвстралії про зміни, які настали.
Ще в 2008 му році появилися були в Інтернеті вістки про те, що найстарший український університет за кордоном опинився на межі виживання. Український Вільний Університет, що був заснований у 1921 році й майже 90 років він підтримував і розвивав українську науку у вільному світі переживав серйозні фінансові труднощі.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Prepare for the XIV National Ukrainian Festival</title>
      <link>https://ozeukes.com/culture/prepare-for-the-xiv-national-ukrainian-festival/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Nov 2012 11:05:21 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ozeukes.com/culture/prepare-for-the-xiv-national-ukrainian-festival/</guid>
      <description>XIV National Ukrainian Festival The next National Ukrainian Festival is being planned for the weekend of 7th-9th June 2013 in Sydney.
Under consideration for the weekend are friendly sports events, exhibitions, a zabava-dance and a concert. Cultural ensembles (dance, choral, etc) are encouraged to consider putting forward their best acts to take part in this festival to showcase the best of Ukraine culture and talent.
All Ukrainians and their friends should pencil in this weekend as a not-to-be-missed occasion.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>МОГИЛА ГЕТЬМАНА ПАВЛА СКОРОПАДСЬКОГО В НІМЕЧЧИНІ</title>
      <link>https://ozeukes.com/politics/skoropadskyi-grave/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Nov 2012 09:55:27 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ozeukes.com/politics/skoropadskyi-grave/</guid>
      <description>МАРІЧКА ГАЛАБУРДА - ЧИГРИН
БІЛЯ МОГИЛИ ГЕТЬМАНА ПАВЛА СКОРОПАДСЬКОГО
1 листопада в церковному календарі в багатьох країнах Европи, в Україні зокрема, в Німеччині в Баварії, в Бельгії, Люксембурзі, Італії, Еспанії, ітд - це день ВСІХ СВЯТИХ, ( можливо таке свято відзначається й в інших континентах світу). В цей день вшановується пам’ять всіх померлих знаних і незнаних мучеників за християнську віру, а в Україні зокрема тих, хто поляг в боротьбі за волю своєї держави й взагалі відвідують могили.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cultural lesson learned well</title>
      <link>https://ozeukes.com/culture/cultural-lesson-learned-well/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Nov 2012 07:04:06 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ozeukes.com/culture/cultural-lesson-learned-well/</guid>
      <description>The local community newspaper, Hume Weekly, has published an article featuring Stefan Romaniw, the recently appointed state chairman of the Australia Day committee, expressing his views regarding the role of multiculturalism during celebrations of Australia Day.
Read the full article here: http://www.humeweekly.com.au/story/904149/cultural-lesson-learned-well/?cs=1834</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ukrainian band from Canada to perform in Sydney</title>
      <link>https://ozeukes.com/culture/ukrainian-band-from-canada-to-perform-in-sydney/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 02 Nov 2012 00:12:27 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ozeukes.com/culture/ukrainian-band-from-canada-to-perform-in-sydney/</guid>
      <description>The Ukrainian Rock n&amp;rsquo; roll band &amp;lsquo;KLOOCH&amp;rsquo; from Toronto, Canada will be performing in Sydney in December.

Tickets are available for purchase online at: http://brewhouse.eventix.com.au/2/display_show_details.asp?uid=5696672&amp;amp;acl=24914&amp;amp;guid=9966726b9898a4&amp;amp;url=%2F2%2Fdisplay_show_details.asp&amp;amp;eventid=5057</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>У Мельборні вшанували пам’ять героїв УПА</title>
      <link>https://ozeukes.com/culture/melbourne-honours-upa-heroes/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Oct 2012 00:24:48 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ozeukes.com/culture/melbourne-honours-upa-heroes/</guid>
      <description>**[ ](http://www.ozeukes.com/wp-content/uploads/2012/10/Posters.jpg)У Мельборні вшанували пам’ять героїв УПА**** **
В неділю 28 жовтня, в Українському Народному Домі в Ессендоні зібралася українська громадськість, щоб відзначити
 * 70–ту річницю УПА, * 71–шу річницю відновлення Української Держави Актом 30–го червня 1941 року та * 100–ліття від дня народження Ярослава Стецька.  Свято розпочалося урочистим та емоційним вшануванням пам’яті борців за волю України – внесенням державних прапорів України та Австралії, ОУН, Дивізійників, Українського Вільного Козацтва, СУМу та Пласту.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>70th Anniversary of the Ukrainian Insurgent Army - Commemorative Christmas Cards</title>
      <link>https://ozeukes.com/culture/70th-anniversary-of-the-ukrainian-insurgent-army-commemorative-christmas-cards/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Oct 2012 06:54:47 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ozeukes.com/culture/70th-anniversary-of-the-ukrainian-insurgent-army-commemorative-christmas-cards/</guid>
      <description>On behalf of the
CYM - Ukrainian Youth Association
OUN - Organisation of Ukrainian Nationalists and
LVU - Australian League for a free Ukraine.
The Ukrainian Youth Association National Executive is co-ordinating the release of Christmas cards commemorating the 70th Anniversary of the Ukrainian Insurgent Army.
The launch of the cards will be available for purchase at the commemorative concert being held in Melbourne on Sunday 28th October 2012, and will be distributed to each state for further sales and awareness.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ВІДЗНAЧЕННЯ 120 ліття з дня народження бл. ПAТРІЯРХA ЙОCИПA CЛІПОГО</title>
      <link>https://ozeukes.com/culture/120-anniversary-yosyf-slipyi/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Oct 2012 06:34:22 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ozeukes.com/culture/120-anniversary-yosyf-slipyi/</guid>
      <description>**МAРІЧКA ГAЛAБУРДA – ЧИГРИН**
Мюнхен 17-25-го жовтня 2012
Власний репортаж й дані Рaдіо Ватикану - української редакції
В ІТAЛІЇ
12 - 15 жовтня 2012 року
ВІДЗНAЧЕННЯ 120 ліття з дня народження бл. ПAТРІЯРХA ЙОCИПA CЛІПОГО та
ПОCВЯЧЕННЯ ВІДНОВЛЕНОГО CОБОРУ ім. св. CОФІЇ ВCТУП
Людина живе не тільки мріями, але і спогадами. Вони залишають у людській душі часами радісний, а часами сумний слід. У мене спогади про Італію особливо добрі та є й гіркі&amp;hellip; Рим став для мене життєвою школою.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Золотий ювілей філії УГВ в Нобл Парку</title>
      <link>https://ozeukes.com/events/victoria/auv-noble-park-golden-jubilee/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Aug 2012 01:23:14 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ozeukes.com/events/victoria/auv-noble-park-golden-jubilee/</guid>
      <description>**Ласкаво просимо_ __всіх__ __на__ __наш__ __золотий ювілей__!_** 
Лист Голови філії УГВ в Нобл Парку AUV NP 50th President&#39;s Letter Ukr
**You are cordially invited to our Golden Jubilee_!_** 
Letter from the President AUV Noble Park AUV NP 50th President&#39;s Letter Eng</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Святкування 21 річниці Незалежності України в Мельбурні</title>
      <link>https://ozeukes.com/events/victoria/celebrations-in-melbourne-ukrainian-independence-day/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Aug 2012 01:17:35 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ozeukes.com/events/victoria/celebrations-in-melbourne-ukrainian-independence-day/</guid>
      <description>[ ](http://www.ozeukes.com/wp-content/uploads/2012/08/Melb-flag.jpg)21 річниця Незалежності України
Цю визначну подію української історії спільнота Української Громади Вікторії святкувала в неділю 19 серпня, у залі BMW Edge, що на Площі Федерації.
В цей святковий день у центрі Мельборна поруч з національним прапором Австралії майоріли синьо–жовті прапори України, а в залі відбувався справжній фестиваль українського мистецтва та культури.
Велике Національне Свято відкрив Т.Ґалас, культ.–освіт. реф.СУОА, а цього дня – ведучий мистецької програми.
Урочисто прозвучали гимни Австралії та України.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Book Launch in Perth</title>
      <link>https://ozeukes.com/events/western-australia/book-launch-in-perth/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Aug 2012 00:14:23 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ozeukes.com/events/western-australia/book-launch-in-perth/</guid>
      <description>Book Launch in Perth: Silent Memories, Traumatic Lives Ukrainian Migrant Refugees in Western Australia****__ by Dr Lesa Melnyczuk ** **&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;-
 This is the first work to tell the story of the Ukrainian survivors who were accepted as migrant refugees to Western Australia after World War II. The experience of these people was one of enormous struggle where only the strongest survived, to now finally share their story. By bringing their stories together for the first time we begin to understand the refugee experience of post-war migrant Ukrainians who settled in Western Australia.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Інтерв’ю із Ларисою Лозинською-Кий про книгу «Каміння під косою»</title>
      <link>https://ozeukes.com/culture/interview-about-the-book-stones-under-the-scythe/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Jun 2012 06:48:04 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ozeukes.com/culture/interview-about-the-book-stones-under-the-scythe/</guid>
      <description>КАМІННЯ ПІД КОСОЮ&amp;hellip;
Кілька років тому, на Конвенції Об’єднання Жінок Оборони Чотирьох Свобід України (ОЖ ОЧСУ), делеґати приняли рішення провести проєкт в пам’ять жертв Голодомору 1932-1933 років - переклад відомої книги англійською мовою Ольги Мак “Stones Under the Scythe” (“Каміння під косою”) - історичний роман про голодомор-ґеноцид в Україні.
Інтерв’ю із Ларисою Лозинською-Кий, керівником проєкту ОЖ ОЧСУ: КАМІННЯ ПІД КОСОЮ&amp;hellip;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>UEFA EURO 2012 Information</title>
      <link>https://ozeukes.com/events/international-events/uefa-euro-2012-information/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 31 May 2012 02:46:14 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ozeukes.com/events/international-events/uefa-euro-2012-information/</guid>
      <description>UEFA EURO 2012 – Video Clips
In the build up to the EURO 2012 European Football Championship, which will take place in Poland and Ukraine from June 8 to July 1, a number of video clips have been released which can be viewed on the internet.
У підготовці до чемпіонату Європи 2012 року (Євро 2012), який відбудеться в Польщі та Україні від 8-го червня до 1-го липня, випущено декілька відеокліпів почерез інтернет.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Song of Ukraine</title>
      <link>https://ozeukes.com/events/new-south-wales/the-song-of-ukraine/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 May 2012 00:24:20 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ozeukes.com/events/new-south-wales/the-song-of-ukraine/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hopak in the Park 2012</title>
      <link>https://ozeukes.com/events/victoria/hopak-in-the-park-2012-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 May 2012 06:24:38 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ozeukes.com/events/victoria/hopak-in-the-park-2012-2/</guid>
      <description>[ ](http://www.ozeukes.com/wp-content/uploads/2012/05/HIPT-Welcome1.jpg)Hopak in the Park 2012
A pleasant autumnal day was on hand to welcome over 1,400 attendees to the Sidney Myer Music Bowl in Melbourne, Australia for the second Hopak in the Park on Saturday 28 April 2012.
Proceedings commenced with the singing of the National Anthems of Australia and Ukraine, followed by the Welcome _(Pryvit) _Dance performed by the Veselka and Zaharava Ensembles from Sydney.
The show was ably compered by Kristie Carter, a TV presenter from Newcastle, NSW.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Свято Шевченка у Мельборні</title>
      <link>https://ozeukes.com/events/victoria/shevchenko-commemoration-2012-melbourne/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Mar 2012 09:47:25 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ozeukes.com/events/victoria/shevchenko-commemoration-2012-melbourne/</guid>
      <description>Свято Шевченка у Мельборні. Свято Шевченка в Австралії або Шевченківські Дні в Україні – це традиційне щорічне вшанування генія нашого народу у місяці березні.
Традиція Української Громади Вікторії вшанувати пам’ять тараса Шевченка має давню історію. Центром святкування є Український Народний Дім в Ессендоні, де збираються представники української спільноти різних ґенерацій, які виховувалися на творах Великого Кобзаря, де звучать його поезії та пісні, де згадують Великого Пророка “незлим тихим словом” і де пам’ятають його слова “І чужому научайтесь й свого не цурайтесь”.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Виставка-конкурс дитячого малюнку &#34;Читаючи поезію Шевченка&#34;</title>
      <link>https://ozeukes.com/events/victoria/shevchenko-art-competition-melbourne/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Mar 2012 01:35:10 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ozeukes.com/events/victoria/shevchenko-art-competition-melbourne/</guid>
      <description>Виставка-конкурс дитячого малюнку &amp;ldquo;Читаючи поезію Шевченка&amp;rdquo;.  У цьому році Шевченківське свято у Мельбурні вперше прикрасила залю Українського Народного Дому Виставка-Конкурс дитячого малюнку &amp;ldquo;Читаючи поезію Шевченка&amp;rdquo;. У цій мистецькій акції взяли участь 30 дітей українських шкіл Мельбурну школи імені Лесі Українки та Братської школи імені Митрополита Андрея Шептицького. Мета нашого конкурсу - через власний малюнок проявити креативність та уяву, допомогти дітям відчути та глибше пізнати красу поезії Великого Кобзаря. Такий конкурс дає змогу знайти нові таланти і показати нам дорослим як діти відчувають поезію і тим самим любов до України.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Karpaty Foundation Press Release</title>
      <link>https://ozeukes.com/culture/karpaty-foundation-press-release/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 24 Mar 2012 03:32:02 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ozeukes.com/culture/karpaty-foundation-press-release/</guid>
      <description>The Board &amp;amp; Trustees of The Karpaty Foundation recently held its fourth meeting to review applications for grants and scholarships submitted within the scope of the purpose for which the Foundation was established.
A Press Release announcing scholarships and grants has been provided: The Karpaty Foundation PRelease March 2012 (3)</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>UCS Heritage series - PLAST</title>
      <link>https://ozeukes.com/culture/ucs-heritage-series-plast/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Mar 2012 00:20:05 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ozeukes.com/culture/ucs-heritage-series-plast/</guid>
      <description>The Ukrainian Collectibles Society UCS) has issued an Information Sheet for the next issue of the ongoing “Ukrainian Heritage in Australia” stamp and envelope series.
The latest featured organisation is:
 * · **No. 7: Ukrainian Scouting Organisation PLAST**   Information sheet: Information Sheet No. 4
Order form: UCS - PLAST order form</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ПРЕЗЕНТAЦІЯ КНИЖОЧОК ДИТЯЧИХ КAЗОК</title>
      <link>https://ozeukes.com/events/new-south-wales/ukrainian-childrens-books-launch/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Mar 2012 03:27:10 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ozeukes.com/events/new-south-wales/ukrainian-childrens-books-launch/</guid>
      <description>МAРІЧКA ГAЛAБУРДA–ЧИГРИН
Cідней 3.3.2012
ПРЕЗЕНТAЦІЯ КНИЖОЧОК ДИТЯЧИХ КAЗОК
В суботу 3.3.2012 в **Нaродному Домі в **CІДНЕЇ відбулася презентація дитячих ілюстрованих книжок - «КАВУНИ» – Watermelons та «ПОТЯГ» - Train, авторства Ганни та Ірини Білик. Книжки видані в в Cіднею в Австралії видавництвом «Юаланг» українською та англійською мовами.
Діти Української Центральної Школи ім. княгині Ольги разом з директоркою Марійкою Яніш привітали Ганну та Ірину Білик хлібом і сіллю.
Підчас презентації автори розповіли про створення книжок, про включення історичних відомостей про вбрання та побут українського села, відновлення забутих слів.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Intercultural understanding with Ukraine - Victorian education (DEECD)  and Ukraine Build bridges</title>
      <link>https://ozeukes.com/culture/intercultural-understanding-with-ukraine/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Feb 2012 08:21:05 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ozeukes.com/culture/intercultural-understanding-with-ukraine/</guid>
      <description>February 24, 2012
 For Immediate release
MEDIA RELEASE
INTERCULTURAL UNDERSTANDING WITH UKRAINE. Victoria&#39;s Department of Education and Early Childhood Development connects with Ukraine Let&#39;s build the education bridges  Victorian Department of Education and Early Childhood Development&#39;s Multicultural Education Senior Project Officer Gary Shaw recently presented at a conference in Ukraine on intercultural understanding and global citizenship.
 His brief report was recently published in the DEECD publication Inspire titled Intercultural understanding with Ukraine.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>UCS Press Release - PLAST Centenary</title>
      <link>https://ozeukes.com/culture/ucs-press-release-plast-centenary/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Feb 2012 23:43:48 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ozeukes.com/culture/ucs-press-release-plast-centenary/</guid>
      <description>The Ukrainian Collectibles Society (UCS) has issued a Press Release related to information about the recently issued stamp and first day cover commemorating the Centenary of the formation of Plast.
The Plast Museum is still holding some stock of stamps, first day covers and blank (pre-printed) envelopes.
Press release: 05 - PLAST CENTENARY PRESS RELEASE Feb12</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>2012 International Mother Language Day</title>
      <link>https://ozeukes.com/events/international-events/2012-international-mother-language-day/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Feb 2012 01:56:05 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ozeukes.com/events/international-events/2012-international-mother-language-day/</guid>
      <description>**** **COMMUNITY LANGUAGES AUSTRALIA ****_Where language and culture come together _**185 Faraday Street Carlton. Victoria 3053 Tel (03) 9347 0379 Fax: (03) 9347 0297 Email: afesa@netsol.net.au www.communitylanguagesaustralia.org.au
 Languages Australia sends it heartiest greetings on the occasion of the 2012 International Mother Language Day:
 This is good time for us to reflect on the importance of language, the processes of maintaining and promoting languages education.
 To our all students, teacher, parents, community workers and policy makers we trust you will have a wonderful day- feeling positive about the fact that you are the custodians of your mother tongue and you have in sense a responsibility to pass on the baton in the future.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Свято Шевченка - Melbourne 2012</title>
      <link>https://ozeukes.com/events/victoria/shevchenko-melbourne-2012/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Feb 2012 23:08:59 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ozeukes.com/events/victoria/shevchenko-melbourne-2012/</guid>
      <description>Українська Громада Вікторії (УГВ) запрошує все громадянство на Свято Шевченка.
The Association of Ukrainians in Victoria (AUV) invites the whole community to the Shevchenko Commemoration Day to be held on Sunday 25th March 2012 at 1:30 pm in the Ukrainian House, Essendon.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Melbourne Accordion Orchestra</title>
      <link>https://ozeukes.com/culture/melbourne-accordion-orchestra/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Feb 2012 00:12:53 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ozeukes.com/culture/melbourne-accordion-orchestra/</guid>
      <description>The Melbourne Accordion Orchestra, formed in 2002, consists of musicians who play not only accordions but also drums, bass guitar, xylophone, guitar, keyboard and percussion. The orchestra, conducted by Iryna Stepko, has a repertoire which includes classical, popular, ethnic and traditional music. Its musicians can play solo and have an extensive range of pieces including tangos, waltzes, polkas and marches. They also cater for different ethnic backgrounds: Italian, French, Scandinavian, German, Ukrainian, Brazilian, Argentinean and others.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>HOPAK IN THE PARK 2012</title>
      <link>https://ozeukes.com/events/victoria/hopak-in-the-park-2012/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 31 Jan 2012 00:43:17 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ozeukes.com/events/victoria/hopak-in-the-park-2012/</guid>
      <description>[ ](http://www.ozeukes.com/wp-content/uploads/2012/01/FINAL-Hopak-in-the-park-2012-thumb.jpg)
 UKRAINIAN COSSACK DANCE SPECTACULAR HOPAK IN THE PARK! 28 April 2012 – Melbourne Australia  The Australian Federation of Ukrainian Organisations (AFUO) which represents over 20 Ukrainian Organisations in Australia, invites you to this year&#39;s &amp;ldquo;Hopak in the Park&amp;rdquo;, which will be presented on Saturday 28 April 2012 at the Sidney Myer Music Bowl in Melbourne.
See our YouTube promotion for “Hopak in the Park”. Click here : http://www.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>«Нань Тянь» Будистська святиня</title>
      <link>https://ozeukes.com/culture/nan-tien-temple/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Jan 2012 01:29:45 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ozeukes.com/culture/nan-tien-temple/</guid>
      <description>_Мaрічкa Гaлaбурдa-Чигрин _19.1.2012__
«Нань Тянь» Будистська святиня  В житті людини бувають дні й події, яким важко знайти вияснення, тимбільше коли вони трапляються несподівано, незапляновано.
Отак сталося зі мною. Cкладаю винесені підчас ремонту речі, горнятка, склянки, книжки. Воно не робиться швидко, бо не все пляную ставити назад на місце. Переглядаю тонни паперів. Руки болять від ношення всячини. І несподівано тебе від тої роботи відтягують друзі Aдам і його мама Мaрія, яка приїхала з Польщі, пропонуючи поїздку до &amp;ldquo;Нань Тянь» Будистської святині, про існування якої чула не раз, але ще там не бувала.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ukrainian Foundations and Institutions Offering Grants or Sponsorships</title>
      <link>https://ozeukes.com/culture/ukrainian-foundations-institutions-offering-grants-or-sponsorships/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 17 Dec 2011 04:33:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ozeukes.com/culture/ukrainian-foundations-institutions-offering-grants-or-sponsorships/</guid>
      <description>There are a small number of Ukrainian Foundations and Institutions in Australia who offer grants to organisations and individuals for various purposes, generally related to improving knowledge or awareness of things Ukrainian. To assist potential applicants in being aware of which such Foundations / Institutions currently exist and to whom they may apply for a grant/sponsorship, please refer to the list below.
 В Австралії є декілька українських фундацій і установ які дарують дотації та стипендії організаціям і одиницям на різні потреби, переважно пов&#39;язані з удосконаленням українознавства.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Передріздвяна зустріч відділу Союзу Українок у Нобл Парку</title>
      <link>https://ozeukes.com/events/%d0%9f%d0%b5%d1%80%d0%b5%d0%b4%d1%80%d1%96%d0%b7%d0%b4%d0%b2%d1%8f%d0%bd%d0%b0-%d0%b7%d1%83%d1%81%d1%82%d1%80%d1%96%d1%87-%d0%b2%d1%96%d0%b4%d0%b4%d1%96%d0%bb%d1%83-%d0%a1%d0%be%d1%8e%d0%b7%d1%83/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Dec 2011 11:04:09 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ozeukes.com/events/%d0%9f%d0%b5%d1%80%d0%b5%d0%b4%d1%80%d1%96%d0%b7%d0%b4%d0%b2%d1%8f%d0%bd%d0%b0-%d0%b7%d1%83%d1%81%d1%82%d1%80%d1%96%d1%87-%d0%b2%d1%96%d0%b4%d0%b4%d1%96%d0%bb%d1%83-%d0%a1%d0%be%d1%8e%d0%b7%d1%83/</guid>
      <description>Відділ Союзу Українок ім. Лесі Українки запрошує Союзянок з родинами та шановне громадянство на
ПЕРЕДРІЗДВЯНУ ЗУСТРІЧ
в неділю 18–го грудня 2011, о 12–ій годині
в Народньому Домі – 26 Chandler Rd., Noble Park.
Вас чекатимуть : смачний обід, святочне печиво, несподіванки
Вступ безкоштовний! Всім раді! До зустрічі!
Управа відділу СУВ Нобл Парк</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lucy Yurkiv-Nicolson in concert Sat Nov 19th</title>
      <link>https://ozeukes.com/events/lucy-yurkiv-nicolson-in-concert-sat-nov-19th/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 Nov 2011 11:34:28 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ozeukes.com/events/lucy-yurkiv-nicolson-in-concert-sat-nov-19th/</guid>
      <description>Divas join voices for cause in peninsula concert BY JO WINTERBOTTOM
08 Nov, 2011 01:00 AM
[caption id=&amp;quot;attachment_4222&amp;rdquo; align=&amp;quot;alignleft&amp;rdquo; width=&amp;quot;300&amp;rdquo; caption=&amp;quot;One night only: Opera singers Liane Keegan, rear, and Lucy Nicolson, with Jack Nicolson, will sing at Tanglewood Estate winery. Picture: Yanni&amp;rdquo;][/caption]
ONE of Australia&#39;s most distinguished opera singers will sing at a benefit concert in Merricks next weekend.Dramatic contralto Liane Keegan, who is staying in Mornington with her mother Yvonne Morrison while on a sabbatical from the Deutsche Oper in Berlin, will perform with her long-time friend, Frankston soprano Lucy Nicolson in a once-only concert, Nightsong at Tanglewood.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Official Plast Personalised Stamp and Commemorative Envelope Release</title>
      <link>https://ozeukes.com/culture/official-plast-personalised-stamp-and-commemorative-envelope-release/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 13 Nov 2011 07:28:12 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ozeukes.com/culture/official-plast-personalised-stamp-and-commemorative-envelope-release/</guid>
      <description>During 2011-2012 the Ukrainian Scouting Organisation Plast is commemorating the centenary of its formation in 1911-1912. The Supreme Plast Council “Holovna Plastova Bulava (HPB)” has released both an official centenary logo (for camp badges) and an official postage stamp design that will be released by many of the international Plast Federal Executives around the world.
The Plast Federal Executive (KPS) in Australia is releasing an Australian commemorative Personalised Stamp and first day of issue envelope (FDC) for the International Centenary Jamboree (UMPZ) to be held in Canberra, ACT, from 26 December 2011 to 3 January 2012.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>HRIM – Debut Album</title>
      <link>https://ozeukes.com/culture/hrim-%e2%80%93-debut-album/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Aug 2011 01:31:50 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ozeukes.com/culture/hrim-%e2%80%93-debut-album/</guid>
      <description>Hrim, the Ukrainian band from New York City that performed at the Hopak in the Park festival in April 2011 is happy to announce the online release of their debut album. To purchase the album, please visit www.CDBaby.com/hrim or search &amp;ldquo;Hrim&amp;rdquo; on the iTunes store.
For more information about Hrim, go to http://www.reverbnation.com/hrim or search them on Facebook, Twitter, and MySpace.
The band is excited to be coming back to Melbourne in April of 2012!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Film &#34;Genocide Revealed&#34; wins multiple awards</title>
      <link>https://ozeukes.com/culture/film-genocide-revealed-wins-multiple-awards/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Aug 2011 10:13:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ozeukes.com/culture/film-genocide-revealed-wins-multiple-awards/</guid>
      <description>Genocide Revealed, a feature documentary produced and directed by YURIJ LUHOVY has won a series of awards in 2011 including Best Historical Film and Best Documentary.
The documentary is about the Ukrainian terror-famine of 1932-1933, the genocide against the Ukrainian nation known as the Holodomor.
The film is available in two languages, Ukrainian and English, and is narrated by Oscar-nominated actor Graham Greene and voice-overs are by actress Jill Hennessy and actor Lubomir Mykytiuk.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>20th Anniversary of Ukraine&#39;s Independence stamp</title>
      <link>https://ozeukes.com/culture/20th-anniversary-of-ukraines-independence-stamp/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Jul 2011 05:25:13 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ozeukes.com/culture/20th-anniversary-of-ukraines-independence-stamp/</guid>
      <description>The Ukrainian Collectibles Society has issued a Press Release, Information Sheet and Order Form for the release of a unique and specially commissioned Personalised Stamp and First Day of Issue envelope that will be released at the 3rd National Ukrainian Collectibles Exhibition UCSPEX-2011 in Sydney on 27 August to commemorate the 20th anniversary of Ukraine’s independence.
Interested persons can place orders for stamps and FDC by completing and returning the attached Order Form and make payment as outlined in the Information Sheet.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>UCS Heritage Stampe Issues 5 and 6</title>
      <link>https://ozeukes.com/culture/ucs-heritage-stampe-issues-5-and-6/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Jun 2011 08:14:14 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ozeukes.com/culture/ucs-heritage-stampe-issues-5-and-6/</guid>
      <description>The Ukrainian Collectibles Society (UCS) has released an Information Sheet for the next two issues of the ongoing “Ukrainian Heritage in Australia” stamp and envelope series.
The two new featured organisations are:
 * No. 5: Ukrainian Association of Western Australia * No. 4: Ukrainian Community Radio in South Australia  Also attached are the new individual Order Forms for these two issues. Completed Order Forms should be e-mailed to: bandura@ozemail.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>КОНЦЕРТ В ПОШAНУ ТAРACA ШЕВЧЕНКA в Cіднею</title>
      <link>https://ozeukes.com/events/new-south-wales/shevchenko-concert-sydney-2011/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Mar 2011 03:58:10 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ozeukes.com/events/new-south-wales/shevchenko-concert-sydney-2011/</guid>
      <description>[](http://www.ozeukes.com/wp-content/uploads/2011/03/DSCF0332-small.jpg)[![](http://www.ozeukes.com/wp-content/uploads/2011/03/thumbnail-taras-shevchenko.jpg) ](http://www.ozeukes.com/wp-content/uploads/2011/03/thumbnail-taras-shevchenko.jpg)
МAРІЧКA ГAЛAБУРДA - ЧИГРИН
КОНЦЕРТ В ПОШAНУ ТAРACA ШЕВЧЕНКA в Cіднею
Цьогорічний концерт в 150 ту річницю смерти Тараса Шевченка в Cіднею відбувся в неділю 13.3.2011 в Залі Дому Молоді.
Гостем на концерті був Посол України – вельмишановний пан Валентин Aдомайтіс, який приїхав на концерт з Канбери.
Мала я шану відкрити концерт коротким вступним словом, після чого слідував безсмертний “Заповіт” Шевченка. Cпівав Новий Громадський хор під дириґентурою Лaриси Ковальчук.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ukrainian Collectibles Society - Heritage Issues 3 and 4</title>
      <link>https://ozeukes.com/culture/ukrainian-collectibles-society-heritage-issues-3-and-4/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Feb 2011 05:55:37 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ozeukes.com/culture/ukrainian-collectibles-society-heritage-issues-3-and-4/</guid>
      <description>The Ukrainian Collectibles Society (UCS) has two new issues of its Ukrainian Heritage Series.
The Ukrainian Heritage Personalised Stamp and souvenir envelope series is designed to provide a tangible and collectible philatelic record of the history of various Ukrainian organisations in Australia since 1948, recognising and commemorating their respective unique contributions to Australia’s Ukrainian and wider communities.
Full details of the latest issues can be read here: UCS Information Sheet No 2</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Support for Hopak in the Park</title>
      <link>https://ozeukes.com/culture/support-for-hopak-in-the-park/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Feb 2011 11:40:16 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ozeukes.com/culture/support-for-hopak-in-the-park/</guid>
      <description>The Australian Federation of Ukrainian Organisations presents
**Hopak in the Park - Ukrainian Cossack Dance Spectacular **
MELBOURNE will spring into action in spectacular style when an army of Ukrainian Cossack dancers hit the Sidney Myer Music Bowl on April 30, 2011 from 1.00pm to 6.00pm.
Witness a cast of more than 300 Ukrainian dancers from across Australia kick up a storm as they showcase centuries of dazzling dance moves in the outdoor extravaganza Hopak In the Park.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Український гурт ДахаБраха виступатиме на Фестивалю WOMAD 2011 / Ukrainian Group DakhaBrakha From Ukraine аt WOMAD Festival 2011</title>
      <link>https://ozeukes.com/events/international-events/%d0%a3%d0%ba%d1%80%d0%b0%d1%97%d0%bd%d1%81%d1%8c%d0%ba%d0%b8%d0%b9-%d0%b3%d1%83%d1%80%d1%82-%d0%94%d0%b0%d0%b4%d1%85%d0%b0%d0%91%d1%80%d0%b0%d1%85%d0%b0-%d0%b2%d0%b8%d1%81%d1%82%d1%83%d0%bf%d0%b0/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Jan 2011 00:14:11 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ozeukes.com/events/international-events/%d0%a3%d0%ba%d1%80%d0%b0%d1%97%d0%bd%d1%81%d1%8c%d0%ba%d0%b8%d0%b9-%d0%b3%d1%83%d1%80%d1%82-%d0%94%d0%b0%d0%b4%d1%85%d0%b0%d0%91%d1%80%d0%b0%d1%85%d0%b0-%d0%b2%d0%b8%d1%81%d1%82%d1%83%d0%bf%d0%b0/</guid>
      <description>[](http://www.ozeukes.com/wp-content/uploads/2011/01/2011-web-tile_smal-72dpi.jpg)[![](http://www.ozeukes.com/wp-content/uploads/2011/01/2011-web-tile_smal-72dpi1.jpg) ](http://www.ozeukes.com/wp-content/uploads/2011/01/2011-web-tile_smal-72dpi1.jpg)Подаємо до відома, що до Aвстралії приїде група з України ДахаБраха. Група приїзджає на запрошення Міжнародного Фестивалю WOMAD в Aделайді між 11-14 березня 2011.
 DakhaBrakha, a music group from Ukraine, will perform at the WOMAD Festival in Adelaide between 11-14 March 2011.
 http://womad.org/ http://dakhabrakha.com.ua/
http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=ivIICD9_4Vg&amp;amp;feature=related
http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=qOJjUjGs2xA
http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=SWnao7yGu0I</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hopak in the Park - Tickets on Sale</title>
      <link>https://ozeukes.com/culture/hopak-in-the-park-tickets-on-sale/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Jan 2011 11:48:34 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ozeukes.com/culture/hopak-in-the-park-tickets-on-sale/</guid>
      <description>30 April 2011 – Melbourne Australia
Sidney Myer Music Bowl
YouTube promotion for “Hopak in the Park”. Click here : http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=k9aBB5JRO7M
To book your tickets online, click here: http://events.theartscentre.com.au/tickets/reserve.aspx?performanceNumber=5974
For condition of entry to the Sidney Myer Music Bowl. please read the following: Conditions of entry MSO 2011 (2)</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Виставка &#34;Symphony of Light and Flowers&#34;</title>
      <link>https://ozeukes.com/events/vystavka-symphony-of-light-and-flowers/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Nov 2010 23:13:27 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ozeukes.com/events/vystavka-symphony-of-light-and-flowers/</guid>
      <description>Ласкаво запрошуємо Вас на нашу художню виставку: &amp;ldquo;Symphony of Light and Flowers&amp;rdquo;, яка відбудеться з 18/11/2010 - 29/11/2010 в приміщенні Gallery Kinross House, Uniting Art Toorak, за адресою: 603 Toorak Rd, Toorak(opposite Irving road), Parking is available at the back of the Toorak Uniting Church.
Відкриття відбудеться 18 листопада 2010 р. о 19 год.
З повагою,
Лілія й Валентин Вареца</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Peter Shirt launches his book, Among the Ukrainians</title>
      <link>https://ozeukes.com/culture/peter-shirt-launches-his-book-among-the-ukrainians/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Nov 2010 22:44:52 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ozeukes.com/culture/peter-shirt-launches-his-book-among-the-ukrainians/</guid>
      <description>_Ukraine has more than a thousand years of history, but it is still a nation under construction. With global interest in Ukraine near an all time high, Peter’s book is a timely addition to the sparse library of books about this fascinating country. Bursting with anecdotes and information not found elsewhere Among the Ukrainians educates, entertains, and constantly surprises the reader._
Ukraine - February 22, 2010 - Largely unknown to outsiders, Ukraine is the largest country entirely within Europe and the richest in natural resources.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>“Ukrainian Heritage” Personalised Stamp™ - ORDERS CLOSE MONDAY 11TH OCTOBER</title>
      <link>https://ozeukes.com/culture/%e2%80%9cukrainian-heritage%e2%80%9d-personalised-stamp%e2%84%a2-orders-close-monday-11th-october/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 Oct 2010 11:07:53 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ozeukes.com/culture/%e2%80%9cukrainian-heritage%e2%80%9d-personalised-stamp%e2%84%a2-orders-close-monday-11th-october/</guid>
      <description>[ ](http://www.ozeukes.com/wp-content/uploads/2010/10/ucs-logo.jpg)Ukrainian Heritage Personalised Stamp orders close Monday 11th October.
Click here to view details and order forms</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Yuliya Rai - our Ukrainian singer appeared on X Factor!!!!!!</title>
      <link>https://ozeukes.com/culture/yuliya-rai-our-ukrainian-singer-appeared-on-x-factor/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 04 Sep 2010 12:13:11 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ozeukes.com/culture/yuliya-rai-our-ukrainian-singer-appeared-on-x-factor/</guid>
      <description>Click on the link below to watch our Yuliya performing on X FACTOR on Channel 7 (There might be some advertising shown first).
Well done Yuliya!!!!!
http://au.tv.yahoo.com/x-factor/video/-/watch/21707451/yuliya-rai/
Yuliya has performed a number of times at the Ukrainian Community Centre in Brisbane.
In fact Yuliya just performed at the Ukrainian Independence day concert in Brisbane on 22 August 2010.
We already know she is great.
Lets hope the judges see her at her best.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Golden October in Lviv</title>
      <link>https://ozeukes.com/events/golden-october-in-lviv/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Sep 2010 13:32:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ozeukes.com/events/golden-october-in-lviv/</guid>
      <description>Yкраїнська - цікаво, весело, ефективно! Інтенсивний курс української мови та культури для іноземців &amp;ldquo;ЗОЛОТИЙ ЖОВТЕНЬ У ЛЬВОВІ 2010&amp;rdquo; (Львів, 4-15 ЖОВТНЯ).
Протягом курсу учасники будуть мати можливість:
 * відвідати найцікавіші місця Львова та цілої України * приготувати та спробувати українські страви * вивчити українські сучасні та народні пісні * брати участь в українських звичаях і традиціях * грати у сучасні та народні українські ігри  і це ще не все!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>&#34;Lunar Pain&#34; Book Review</title>
      <link>https://ozeukes.com/culture/lunar-pain-book-review/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Aug 2010 20:40:36 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ozeukes.com/culture/lunar-pain-book-review/</guid>
      <description>Back in the 1980s Bayda Books published some 20 books, many of them novels translated from Ukrainian into English. Once Ukraine became independent we figured that interest in the country would lead mainstream publishers to translate the best authors Ukraine had to offer. But alas this proved not to be so. With perhaps the exception of Andrei Kurkov, who wrote in Russian. Even the efforts of the Open Ukraine Foundation have produced nothing in English.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Learn Ukrainian in Ukraine and Experience &#34;Warm September in Lviv&#34;</title>
      <link>https://ozeukes.com/events/learn-ukrainian-in-ukraine-and-experience-warm-september-in-lviv/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 19 Aug 2010 20:42:56 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ozeukes.com/events/learn-ukrainian-in-ukraine-and-experience-warm-september-in-lviv/</guid>
      <description>Українська - цікаво, весело, ефективно! Інтенсивний курс української мови та культури для іноземців &amp;ldquo;ТЕПЛИЙ ВЕРЕСЕНЬ У ЛЬВОВІ 2010&amp;rdquo; (Львів, 30 серпня-10 вересня).
Протягом курсу учасники будуть мати можливість:
 * відвідати найцікавіші місця Львова та цілої України * приготувати та спробувати українські страви * вивчити українські сучасні та народні пісні * брати участь в українських звичаях і традиціях * грати у сучасні та народні українські ігри  і це ще не все!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Inaugural Ukrainian Dance Festival “Hopak in the Park” April 2011</title>
      <link>https://ozeukes.com/events/inaugural-hopak-in-the-park/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Jun 2010 13:39:14 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ozeukes.com/events/inaugural-hopak-in-the-park/</guid>
      <description>The Australian Federation of Ukrainian Organisations are hosting the inaugural Ukrainian Dance Festival “Hopak in the Park” at the Sidney Myer Music Bowl in April 2011.
The name hopak is derived from the verb hopaty which means “to jump,” as well as the corresponding exclamation hop! which can be uttered during a jump as an expression of surprise or amazement.
The concept is based on a very successful festival that takes place in Canada for a number of years.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Movie Review - &#34;Farewell&#34;</title>
      <link>https://ozeukes.com/culture/movie-review-farewell/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 05 Jun 2010 14:46:15 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ozeukes.com/culture/movie-review-farewell/</guid>
      <description>This thrilling piece of cinema is based on a remarkable true story and tells the tale of a disenchanted KGB agent who at the height of the Cold War passed classified information out of Moscow.
FAREWELL is a thriller in the mould of &amp;lsquo;The Lives of Others&amp;rsquo; set during the Cold War. Directed by Christian Carion (Joyeux Noel)and starring two of Europe&#39;s most respected actors/directors Emir Kusturica and Guillaume Canet, Kusturica stars as Colonel Grigoriev of the KGB.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>