<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>National Events on AFUO - СУОА</title>
    <link>https://ukrainians.org.au/categories/national-events/</link>
    <description>Recent content in National Events on AFUO - СУОА</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-au</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 03 Oct 2018 10:26:45 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://ukrainians.org.au/categories/national-events/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Invictus Games | Your Guide to Team Ukraine Activities</title>
      <link>https://ukrainians.org.au/events/invictus-games-ukraine-guide/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Oct 2018 10:26:45 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ukrainians.org.au/events/invictus-games-ukraine-guide/</guid>
      <description>Invictus Games is only 2 weeks away in Sydney. There are some fantastic opportunities for you, the community, to not only see Team Ukraine compete, but also meet the team members and hear their stories. **COMMUNITY EVENTS | ** **_ Інформація українською мовою | VIEW INFORMATION IN UKRAINIAN HERE_**
TEAM UKRAINE ARRIVAL SYDNEY INTERNATIONAL AIRPORT –_ 7 am THURSDAY 18.10.2018 _
Meeting place will be in forecourt outside the arrival terminal and marked by a Ukrainian flag.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>AFUO participates in 70th Anniversary Celebrations in Canberra |  Святкування 70-річчя в Канберрі</title>
      <link>https://ukrainians.org.au/events/70-anniversary-canberra/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 29 Sep 2018 12:40:54 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ukrainians.org.au/events/70-anniversary-canberra/</guid>
      <description>This weekend in Canberra, 70th Anniversary celebrations are in progress, honouring 70 years of Ukrainian Settlement, and 70 years of the Ukrainian Autocephalic Orthodox Church in Australia.
[caption id=&amp;quot;attachment_11964&amp;rdquo; align=&amp;quot;aligncenter&amp;rdquo; width=&amp;quot;480&amp;rdquo;] AFUO gifted a plaque to honour the occasion[/caption]
Beginning the proceedings, a service was held today St. John the Baptist Anglican Church - where exactly 70 years ago, Ukrainian Orthodox Christians served the very first Divine Liturgy in Australia. Leaders from all Ukrainian clergies in Australia were present.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Team Ukraine Meet &amp; Greet |  Зустріч з командою Україна</title>
      <link>https://ukrainians.org.au/events/team-ukraine-meet-invictus/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Sep 2018 09:53:15 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ukrainians.org.au/events/team-ukraine-meet-invictus/</guid>
      <description>В жовтні розпочнуться Ігри Нескорених в Сіднеї, де виступатимуть 15 українських військовослужбовців та ветеранів. Спілка Української Молоді в Австралії запрошує членів Української спільноти на зустріч &amp;ldquo;Meet &amp;amp; Greet&amp;rdquo;, яке відбудеться у четвер, 25 жовтня, о 6 годині вечора в Gallon Wine Bar (117 Harris St, Pyrmont, NSW), де буде можливість зустріти наших Нескорених Героїв. Квитки $65+BF від особи. **Всі кошти йдуть на “Ukraine Crisis Appeal”. Квитки можна придбати через лінк: sydinvictusgamesukraine.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Holodomor Commemoration Service in Sydney</title>
      <link>https://ukrainians.org.au/events/new-south-wales/holodomor-commemoration-service-in-sydney/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Sep 2018 01:59:59 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ukrainians.org.au/events/new-south-wales/holodomor-commemoration-service-in-sydney/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Invictus Games tickets now on sale!</title>
      <link>https://ukrainians.org.au/events/invictus-games-tickets-now-on-sale/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Aug 2018 12:27:36 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ukrainians.org.au/events/invictus-games-tickets-now-on-sale/</guid>
      <description>Support Team Ukraine at the Invictus Games in Sydney!
Tickets have now gone on sale for events. See in the image below all the events Ukraine is participating in.
Click here to buy tickets. 
[caption id=&amp;quot;attachment_11895&amp;rdquo; align=&amp;quot;alignnone&amp;rdquo; width=&amp;quot;772&amp;rdquo;] Invictus Games 2018[/caption]</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ukrainian Protest Rally in Canberra - Media coverage</title>
      <link>https://ukrainians.org.au/events/act/ukrainian-protest-rally-in-canberra-media-coverage/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 May 2014 01:49:07 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ukrainians.org.au/events/act/ukrainian-protest-rally-in-canberra-media-coverage/</guid>
      <description>Scores of cars from Brisbane, Melbourne and Sydney carrying Ukrainian flags drove to Canberra to take part in an AutoMaidan round the streets of Australia’s capital city on Sunday May 25th 2014, the day of Presidential elections in Ukraine. The AutoMaidan terminated in front of the Russian embassy where hundreds of peaceful protesters expressed their support for Ukraine and strong opposition to Putin’s aggression in Ukraine.
Earlier in the day many of the protesters who had Ukrainian citizenship had taken the opportunity to vote at the Ukrainian Embassy.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>National Rally in Support of Ukraine - from Sydney</title>
      <link>https://ukrainians.org.au/events/new-south-wales/national-rally-in-support-of-ukraine-from-sydney/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 18 May 2014 04:18:07 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ukrainians.org.au/events/new-south-wales/national-rally-in-support-of-ukraine-from-sydney/</guid>
      <description>AFUO-UCNSW Canberra Rally Sydney Bus May 25th 
Bookings for Sydney Bus to Canberra Rally and Ukrainian Elections Sunday May 25th 8.00am, St Andrew&amp;rsquo;s Ukrainian Catholic Church, 57 Church St, Lidcombe. $25 Employed Adults, $10 pensioners/ students/ children + $1.50 booking fee each. Bus will also be picking up from Cabramatta Ukrainian Hall. Queries 0410 866 820.
Замовлення на автобус з Сіднею на акцію і на украінські вибори в Канберрі 25-го травня.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>National Rally in Support of Ukraine</title>
      <link>https://ukrainians.org.au/events/national-rally-in-support-of-ukraine/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 May 2014 01:18:23 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ukrainians.org.au/events/national-rally-in-support-of-ukraine/</guid>
      <description>The Australian Federation of Ukrainian Organisations (AFUO) calls on all concerned Australians to participate in a National Rally in Support of Ukraine.
The rally will express its strong opposition to Putin’s aggression in Ukraine.
The final stage of the rally will be culminate at the Embassy of the Russian Federation in Australia in Canberra on Sunday May 25, 2014 at 1.00pm, the day of the Presidential elections in Ukraine.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Зaклик до дії - Крaйовa Мaніфеcтaція</title>
      <link>https://ukrainians.org.au/events/national-events/call-to-action-a-national-rally/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 10 May 2014 02:51:06 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ukrainians.org.au/events/national-events/call-to-action-a-national-rally/</guid>
      <description>CALL TO ACTION - A National Rally in support of Ukraine and Opposition to Putin’s Russian Aggression in Ukraine – Sunday May 25, 2014 Canberra.
Зaклик до дії - Крaйовa Мaніфеcтaція – підтримуємо Укрaїну – зacуджуємо роcійcьку aгреcію в Укрaїні тa втручaння Путінa тa його влaди в cпрaвaх Укрaїни - Неділя 25-го травня 2014 – Кaнберрa

 9th May 2014
  CALL TO ACTION  The Australian Federation of Ukrainian Organisations announces a call to action:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Photos from the Ukrainian Festival ‘Hopak in the Park’ Ukrainian Dance Spectacular</title>
      <link>https://ukrainians.org.au/culture/photos-from-the-ukrainian-festival-hopak-in-the-park-ukrainian-dance-spectacular/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Apr 2014 01:52:37 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ukrainians.org.au/culture/photos-from-the-ukrainian-festival-hopak-in-the-park-ukrainian-dance-spectacular/</guid>
      <description>Hundreds of Australia&amp;rsquo;s best Ukrainian dancers took part in the Ukrainian Dance Festival on Saturday 26th April 2014 at the Sidney Myer Music Bowl in Melbourne. Supporting this show were dance ensembles from the Irish, Spanish and Greek communities, and the highly acclaimed Ukrainian band “Zirka” from Toronto, Canada.
A full album of photos, courtesy of Taras and Sonja Moravski, can be viewed at: https://www.flickr.com/photos/moravski/sets/72157644354135471/
A small selection is presented here</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hopak in the Park 2014</title>
      <link>https://ukrainians.org.au/culture/hopak-in-the-park-2014/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Feb 2014 23:56:03 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ukrainians.org.au/culture/hopak-in-the-park-2014/</guid>
      <description>The Australian Federation of Ukrainian Organisations presents
UKRAINIAN FESTIVAL ‘Hopak in the Park’ Ukrainian Cossack Dance Spectacular 
Due to matters beyond the control of AFUO Virsky Ensemble is unable to perform at HITP
MELBOURNE will spring into action in spectacular style when an army of Ukrainian Cossack dancers hit the Sidney Myer Music Bowl on April 26th, 2014 from 12:30pm to 6.00pm.
Witness a cast of more than 300 Ukrainian dancers from across Australia kick up a storm as they showcase centuries of dazzling dance moves in the outdoor extravaganza Hopak In the Park.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Панахиди за загиблими на Майдані</title>
      <link>https://ukrainians.org.au/events/national-events/memorial-services-for-the-maidan-deceased/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Jan 2014 00:53:59 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ukrainians.org.au/events/national-events/memorial-services-for-the-maidan-deceased/</guid>
      <description>У храмах УГКЦ в Австралії пройшли Богослужіння за народ України і панахиди за загиблими на Майдані та в усі часи за волю України.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>RALLY in CANBERRA</title>
      <link>https://ukrainians.org.au/events/act/rally-in-canberra/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Dec 2013 11:53:43 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ukrainians.org.au/events/act/rally-in-canberra/</guid>
      <description>Акції в Канберрі**** відбудеться у СУБОТУ, 14го грудня.****
Збірка біля храму УАПЦ в Turner о год. 10.30рано, а від так, короткий похід до Посольства/Амбасада України на 11.00рано.
ПІДТРИМУЙМО наших братів в УКРАЇНІ! Це зокрема тепер ВАЖНИЙ та ВАЖКИЙ ЧАС! МИ з УКРАЇНОЮ! УКРАЇНА це ЄВРОПА! ПРОШУ ПОШИРЮВАТИ ІНФОРМАЦІЇ!
 
RALLY** ****in**** ****CANBERRA****!** SATURDAY, 14 December.****
**Meeting at **10.30AM at Ukrainian Orthodox Church in Turner, and then short walk/march to the Ukrainian Embassy for 11.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Закликаємо на «ЄвроМайдан Австралія!»</title>
      <link>https://ukrainians.org.au/events/national-events/call-to-participate-in-euromaidan-australia/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Nov 2013 01:23:40 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ukrainians.org.au/events/national-events/call-to-participate-in-euromaidan-australia/</guid>
      <description>Закликаємо на «ЄвроМайдан Австралія!» Управа Cоюзу Українських Організацій Aвстралії (СУОА) закликає українців Австралії підтримати світові акції, які наголошують, що Україна - це Європа, і закликають уряд України підписати договір із Євросоюзом.
Ukraine for EU rallies Australia call to action UKR
Вже запляновано:
**Мельборн: **Віче y четвер 28-го листопада 2013 від год. 4.00 до 8.00 вечора перед Стейтовою бібліотекою, на розі Swanston St. і La Trobe St., що знаходиться напроти станції метро Melbourne Central.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Про відмову уряда України від Асоціації з Євросоюзом</title>
      <link>https://ukrainians.org.au/events/international-events/ukraines-suspension-of-the-european-union-association-agreement/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Nov 2013 01:53:54 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ukrainians.org.au/events/international-events/ukraines-suspension-of-the-european-union-association-agreement/</guid>
      <description>[ ](http://www.ozeukes.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/11/Ukraine-EU.jpg)Про відмову уряда України від Асоціації з Євросоюзом
Cоюз Українських Організацій Aвстралії (СУОА) закликає українців Австралії протестувати проти відмову уряда України від Асоціації з Євросоюзом та пітримувати світові акції які наголошують, що Україна це Європа.
Подається копію листа: UKRAINE -EUROPE (2) 20131125
Заплановані акціії: Мельбурн: Віче в центрі Мельбурну в четвер 27-го листопада 2013 від 4:00 год. пп. (детальніше буде подано)
Сідней: Віче в центрі Сіднею в четвер 27-го листопада 2013 (детальніше буде подано)</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Holodomor National Event - Commemorating 80 Years</title>
      <link>https://ukrainians.org.au/events/national-events/holodomor-national-event-commemorating-80-years/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 29 Sep 2013 06:35:05 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ukrainians.org.au/events/national-events/holodomor-national-event-commemorating-80-years/</guid>
      <description>[ ](http://www.ozeukes.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/09/header_holod_3_2.jpg)
Saturday, November 23, 2013 Holodomor - extermination by hunger - the famine of 1932-33 in Ukraine. This act of genocide committed through Stalin&amp;rsquo;s crime against humanity must never be forgotten. Eighty years on - let&amp;rsquo;s join together to remember and honour those that perished and to raise awareness of this tragic chapter of Ukraine&amp;rsquo;s history. For further information on the event email holodomor@ozeukes.com.au or call 0438 372 270</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ХІV ЗДВИГ УКРАЇНЦІВ В АВСТРАЛІЇ – Ч. 3</title>
      <link>https://ukrainians.org.au/culture/national-festival-2013-part-3/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Jun 2013 03:02:44 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ukrainians.org.au/culture/national-festival-2013-part-3/</guid>
      <description>МАРІЧКА ГАЛАБУРДА-ЧИГРИН
ЗДВИГ СУОА СІДНЕЙ 7, 8, 9 червня 2013 - частина 3 **НЕДІЛЯ: 9.6.2013 **
СЛУЖБА БОЖА Подяка за всі Богом надані нашому суспільтву ласки
В українських церквах УАПЦ і УГКЦ в Сіднеї та всіх містах Австралії, де проживає українське поселення відправлялися з ранку в 9 - годині урочисті Богослужби.
В Свято Покровській Церкві УАПЦ в Гомбуш Богослужбу відправляли о. архипресвітер Володимир Люлька, настоятель Свято-Афанасійської Парафії в Ґренвілі, о. митрофорний протоієрей **о.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ХІV ЗДВИГ УКРАЇНЦІВ В АВСТРАЛІЇ – Ч. 2a</title>
      <link>https://ukrainians.org.au/culture/national-festival-2013-part-2a/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Jun 2013 02:08:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ukrainians.org.au/culture/national-festival-2013-part-2a/</guid>
      <description>ДРУГИЙ ДЕНЬ ЗДВИГУ** ****– ****ПРОДОВЖЕННЯ******
МАРІЧКА ГАЛАБУРДА – ЧИГРИН__
СУБОТА 8.6.2013_:_
Тому, що Здвиг тривав лише 3 дні, треба було якось в один день відбути якнайбільше сесій, майстерень, доповідей. Я вже згадувала про те, що фізично було майже неможливо бути всюди, оскільки в один час відбувалися події&amp;hellip;
В будинку **Дому Молоді **на другому поверсі СУМ і ПЛАСТ провели виставку своїх історичних матеріялів.
**А Відділ Союзу Українок ім. Оьги Басараб **має там свою кімнату, де постійно знаходиться виставка прикладного народного мистецьтва, яка дуже популярна серед відвідувачів.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ХІV ЗДВИГ УКРАЇНЦІВ В АВСТРАЛІЇ – Ч. 2</title>
      <link>https://ukrainians.org.au/culture/national-festival-2013-part-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Jun 2013 06:48:47 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ukrainians.org.au/culture/national-festival-2013-part-2/</guid>
      <description>ДРУГИЙ ДЕНЬ ЗДВИГУ
 МАРІЧКА ГАЛАБУРДА – ЧИГРИН
****СУБОТА 8.6.2013_:_
ПЕРЕДАЧА ПОЖЕРТВИ &amp;quot;ФОНДУ КАРПАТИ&amp;quot; УКРАЇНСЬКІЙ ШКОЛІ ім.св. Андрія
**У суботу 8.6.2013 у 10****-****ій годині** ранку в програмі Здвигу Українців в приміщенні братської школи ім св. Андрія в Лідкомбі відбулося вручення грошей, пожертви Фундації &amp;ldquo;КАРПАТИ&amp;rdquo;, головного спонзора Здвигу учителям і дітям, які 22.6.ц.р. збираються Києві, столиці України, щоби розпочати прогульку в батьківщині своїх батьків.
Присутніми були: Голова Союзу Українських Організацій Стефан Романів, Голова Фундації Володмир Войтович та секретар Ярослав Дума, батьки дітей та кілька гостей.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ХІV ЗДВИГ УКРАЇНЦІВ В АВСТРАЛІЇ - Ч. 1</title>
      <link>https://ukrainians.org.au/culture/national-festival-2013-part-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Jun 2013 05:58:36 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ukrainians.org.au/culture/national-festival-2013-part-1/</guid>
      <description>МАРІЧКА ГАЛАБУРДА – ЧИГРИН
СІДНЕЙ 12.6.2009** **
ХІV ЗДВИГ УКРАЇНЦІВ В АВСТРАЛІЇ** **
В днях від 7 – 9 червня 2013 року в Сіднеї з великим успіхом пройшов Здвиг Українців Австралії. Здвиг був ювілейним, бо українці відзначали 65 – ти ліття свого побуту в цій країні.
Українська діяспора в Австралії є одна з наймолодших українських поселень в світі. В 1947 - му році прибуло до Австралії кількадесятків українських родин. В 1948 і в 1949 - му році українці, тзв політичні еміґранти (displaced persons) масово прибули до Австралії — початок української діяспори в цій країні датується 1948 - 1949 - го року.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Гідно проведено Здвиг Укрaїнців Aвcтрaлії</title>
      <link>https://ukrainians.org.au/culture/successful-national-ukrainian-festival-in-australia/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Jun 2013 00:48:01 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ukrainians.org.au/culture/successful-national-ukrainian-festival-in-australia/</guid>
      <description>[ ](http://www.ozeukes.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/06/ZdvyhLogoFinal-ENG-thumb.jpg)Successful National Ukrainian Festival in Australia
The Australian Federation of Ukrainian Organisations (AFUO) has announced that an extremely successful and enjoyable XIV National Festival of Ukrainians in Australia has come to a close.
The full text of the press release (in English) can be read here: UKRAINIAN NATIONAL FESTIVAL IN AUSTRALIA A HUGE SUCCESS Eng
Photos of the events may be viewed on the following sites: http://zdvyh2013.shutterfly.com/ http://www.flickr.com/photos/moravski/sets/72157634053852860/
[ ](http://www.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ukrainian Youth Short Film Festival 2013 - Results</title>
      <link>https://ukrainians.org.au/culture/ukrainian-youth-short-film-festival-2013-results/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Jun 2013 05:18:52 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ukrainians.org.au/culture/ukrainian-youth-short-film-festival-2013-results/</guid>
      <description>[ ](http://www.ozeukes.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/06/Film-Poster-thumb.jpg)Inaugural Ukrainian Youth Short Film Festival
“I am Ukrainian” Young people were invited to interpret this phrase by making a short film to express how they saw their Ukrainian identity and heritage.
The films had to be original and can be realistic, experimental, digital manipulations, humorous, animations or serious: above all, personal, creative and entertaining, opening our eyes to the way young people see what &amp;ldquo;being Ukrainian&amp;rdquo; means to them.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Order of Australia Medals for Ukrainians in Australia</title>
      <link>https://ukrainians.org.au/events/national-events/order-of-australia-medals-for-ukrainians-in-australia/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Jun 2013 03:05:49 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ukrainians.org.au/events/national-events/order-of-australia-medals-for-ukrainians-in-australia/</guid>
      <description>Congratulating Ukrainians in Australia who Received Order of Australia Medals as part of the Queen&amp;rsquo;s Birthday Honours List.

The Australian Federation of Ukrainian Organisations congratulates Ukrainians who received
Order of Australia Medals
Rev Fr Zenon Chorkawyj OAM for services to the Ukrainian Catholic Church
Stephen Chomyn OAM for services to the Ukrainian Community in Brisbane
Anna Stefaniuk OAM for services to education through multicultural initiatives to the Ukrainian community</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>XIV National Ukrainian Festival</title>
      <link>https://ukrainians.org.au/culture/xiv-national-ukrainian-festival/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Apr 2013 08:03:49 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ukrainians.org.au/culture/xiv-national-ukrainian-festival/</guid>
      <description>The XIV National Ukrainian Festival will be held in Sydney on 7th – 9th June 2013.
The Festival will be held under the auspice of the Australian Federation of Ukrainian Organisations and hosted by the Ukrainian Council of NSW.
This year&amp;rsquo;s theme: 65th Anniversary of Ukrainian Settlement in Australia. Past, Present, Future!
XIV National Ukrainian Festival New Website Launched! For up-to-date and extended information visit website zdvyh.ozeukes.com 
The three day festival has a fantastic program of events catering to a wide-ranging audience</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ЗДВИГ УКРAЇНЦІВ В AВCТРAЛІЇ</title>
      <link>https://ukrainians.org.au/culture/national-ukrainian-festival/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 17 Feb 2013 02:26:40 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ukrainians.org.au/culture/national-ukrainian-festival/</guid>
      <description>**ЗДВИГ УКРAЇНЦІВ В AВCТРAЛІЇ **- сідней 7-9 червня 2013
65 ліття посe_лення українців в Aвстралії _,
Шанувати минуле – **** Зміцнювати майбутнє! Вчора, Cьогодні, Завтра!
Управа Cоюзу Українських Організацій Aвстралії підтверджує попередні повідомлення, що в рамках програми 2013 програми - Відзнaчення 65 ліття посe_лення українців в Aвстралії _, _в днях 7-9 червня 2013 в Cіднею відбудеться ___Здвиг Українців Aвстралії.
Наші святкування проходитимуть під гаслом ;
_Шанувати минуле – **** Зміцнювати майбутнє!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ukrainian Youth Short Film Competition 2013</title>
      <link>https://ukrainians.org.au/culture/ukrainian-youth-short-film-competition-2013/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Dec 2012 09:32:45 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ukrainians.org.au/culture/ukrainian-youth-short-film-competition-2013/</guid>
      <description>Оновлення інформації! Updated information!  Thank you to all those who submitted entries into the inaugural “Ukrainian Youth Short Film Festival”.   As it is an innovation that has caught some unprepared for all the work that has to go into producing and submitting, in order to include those who are still making an effort to participate, the deadline has been extended to MONDAY 20th May 5 pm.   There will be no further extensions.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Prepare for the XIV National Ukrainian Festival</title>
      <link>https://ukrainians.org.au/culture/prepare-for-the-xiv-national-ukrainian-festival/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Nov 2012 11:05:21 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ukrainians.org.au/culture/prepare-for-the-xiv-national-ukrainian-festival/</guid>
      <description>XIV National Ukrainian Festival The next National Ukrainian Festival is being planned for the weekend of 7th-9th June 2013 in Sydney.
Under consideration for the weekend are friendly sports events, exhibitions, a zabava-dance and a concert. Cultural ensembles (dance, choral, etc) are encouraged to consider putting forward their best acts to take part in this festival to showcase the best of Ukraine culture and talent.
All Ukrainians and their friends should pencil in this weekend as a not-to-be-missed occasion.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>&#34;Genocide Revealed&#34; - Screenings in Australia</title>
      <link>https://ukrainians.org.au/events/national-events/genocide-revealed-screenings-in-australia/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Nov 2012 02:01:15 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ukrainians.org.au/events/national-events/genocide-revealed-screenings-in-australia/</guid>
      <description>Documentary Genocide Revealed!  Screenings in Australia Genocide Revealed is a historical documentary focusing on the 1932-1933 forced famine in Soviet Ukraine engineered by Stalin&amp;rsquo;s regime. It depicts a human tragedy of unparalleled proportions. Based on moving testimonies of survivors; commentaries by historians and writers; rare historical film and photos of the period; Soviet archival documents; and examines the genocidal intent in the efforts to destroy Ukrainians as an independent nation.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ukraine&#39;s National Day 2012 – Australian Celebrations</title>
      <link>https://ukrainians.org.au/events/national-events/ukraines-national-day-2012-australian-celebrations/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Aug 2012 10:07:29 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ukrainians.org.au/events/national-events/ukraines-national-day-2012-australian-celebrations/</guid>
      <description>UKRAINE&amp;rsquo;S NATIONAL DAY Ukraine celebrates its 21st Anniversary of Independence on 24th August 2012
 Australia&amp;rsquo;s Ukrainian community will also celebrate this occasion around that date with events in all States.
Join your local Ukrainian Association to celebrate Ukraine&amp;rsquo;s National Day (official date 24th August).
For specific information on State celebrations and event information contact your local Ukrainian Association or check the OzeUkes website by clicking on the image (where available) adjoining the specific event.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>XXVI З’ЇЗД CУОA</title>
      <link>https://ukrainians.org.au/events/national-events/26th-afuo-congress/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 22 Jul 2012 04:58:37 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ukrainians.org.au/events/national-events/26th-afuo-congress/</guid>
      <description>22 липня 2012
ПРЕCОВЕ ПОВІДОМЛЕННЯ УCПІШНО ПРОВЕДЕНО XXVI З’ЇЗД CУОA В AВCТРAЛІЇ У субoту 21-го липня 2012 в Мельборні успішно проведено XVI-ий З&amp;rsquo;їзд Cоюзу Українських Організацій Aвстралії. (CУОA).
17 складові частини CУОA були репрезентовані на Зїзді а саме: Епархія УГКЦ, Громади Вікторії, Західної Aвстралії, Південної Aвстралії, Нової Південної Валії, Квінсленду, CУA, ФУCA, CУМ, Пласт ,УЦШР, ЛВУ, НТШ, Дністер, ЕПР, Дивизійники, Українське Козацтво.
Президію З&amp;rsquo;їзду вибрано в такому складі: Пресідник** **Проф Марко Павлишин, Заступник пресідника пані Гaля Касіян, секретарі Ярослав Дума, Ірена Aндреєва, а до почесної президії запрошено Преос.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Скликання XVI-го  З&#39;їзду CУОA</title>
      <link>https://ukrainians.org.au/events/national-events/16th-agm-afuo/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Jul 2012 10:38:22 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ukrainians.org.au/events/national-events/16th-agm-afuo/</guid>
      <description>26-го червня 2012
** Д****о Членів CУОA**
Дорогі Члени CУОA
Подаємо повідомлення про скликання XVI-го З&amp;rsquo;їзду CУОA.
 1. Долучаємо реєстраційну анкету для зголошення делегатів.  Просимо повернути анкету зголошення до 12-го липня 2012.** **Подаємо також формулу зголошення делегатів згідно з 27-ою точкою Cтатуту CУОA. 2. Пригадуємо, що лише фінансові члени CУОA матимуть право голосу на З&amp;rsquo;їзді.З огляду на те, що деякі члени CУОA не вирівняли свою вкладку або мають зауваження щодо калькуляції вкладки, управа CУОA пропонувала Вам подати на письмі Вашій зауваги до **30-го червня 2012.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>AFL Multicultural Round</title>
      <link>https://ukrainians.org.au/events/afl-multicultural-round/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 Jun 2012 03:14:43 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ukrainians.org.au/events/afl-multicultural-round/</guid>
      <description>The Australian Football League (AFL) has named the upcoming weekend of games as the AFL Multicultural Round in recognition of the many diverse backgrounds that make up the participants and fans of Australia’s Game.

For further details see: http://www.afl.com.au/multicultural%20round/tabid/10286/default.aspx</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>National Ukrainian Teachers Conference 2012</title>
      <link>https://ukrainians.org.au/events/national-events/national-ukrainian-teachers-conference-2012/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Jun 2012 10:38:42 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ukrainians.org.au/events/national-events/national-ukrainian-teachers-conference-2012/</guid>
      <description>The 18th National Conference of Ukrainian Community Languages School Teachers was held in Melbourne on Saturday June 9 and Sunday June 10 2012.
The Ukrainian Education Council of Australia, headed by Orysia Stefyn, coordinated a program of reporting, professional development and information exchange. Teachers from Victoria, NSW and SA attended.
Community Languages Australia Executive Director and Chair of the Australian Federation of Ukrainian Organisations, Mr Stefan Romaniw OAM, addressed the conference and outlined the challenges and opportunities that lay ahead and encouraged teachers to continue undertaking professional development.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dr Ludomyr John MYKYTA AM</title>
      <link>https://ukrainians.org.au/events/national-events/dr-ludomyr-john-mykyta-am/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Jun 2012 04:13:54 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ukrainians.org.au/events/national-events/dr-ludomyr-john-mykyta-am/</guid>
      <description>Управа CУОA вітає др Людомира Микиту з Південної Aвстралії з державною нагородою.
The AFUO congratulates **Dr Ludomyr John MYKYTA, Glenside, SA **for receiving an Order of Australia
Member (AM) in the General Division of the Order of Australia
Dr Ludomyr John MYKYTA
** PO Box 193, Glenside SA 5065**
For service to geriatric medicine through care of the aged, education of students, and leadership roles with professional and advisory organisations.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Victor KOVALENKO OAM</title>
      <link>https://ukrainians.org.au/events/national-events/victor-kovalenko-oam/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Jun 2012 04:06:28 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ukrainians.org.au/events/national-events/victor-kovalenko-oam/</guid>
      <description>Управа CУОA вітає Віктора Коваленка з державною нагородою
Congratulations to Victor Kovalenko, for his award of OAM:
Medal (OAM) in the General Division of the Order of Australia Medal
Mr Victor KOVALENKO
** 5/76 Lauderdale Avenue, Fairlight NSW 2094**
For service to sport, particularly as the national head coach of the Australian Olympic Sailing team.
[caption id=&amp;quot;attachment_5347&amp;rdquo; align=&amp;quot;alignleft&amp;rdquo; width=&amp;quot;150&amp;rdquo; caption=&amp;quot;Victor Kovalenko OAM&amp;rdquo;][/caption]
Victor KOVALENKO OAM
   * Born in Dnipropetrovsk in Ukraine on 5th August, 1950.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hopak in the Park 2012</title>
      <link>https://ukrainians.org.au/events/victoria/hopak-in-the-park-2012-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 May 2012 06:24:38 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ukrainians.org.au/events/victoria/hopak-in-the-park-2012-2/</guid>
      <description>[ ](http://www.ozeukes.com/wp-content/uploads/2012/05/HIPT-Welcome1.jpg)Hopak in the Park 2012
A pleasant autumnal day was on hand to welcome over 1,400 attendees to the Sidney Myer Music Bowl in Melbourne, Australia for the second Hopak in the Park on Saturday 28 April 2012.
Proceedings commenced with the singing of the National Anthems of Australia and Ukraine, followed by the Welcome _(Pryvit) _Dance performed by the Veselka and Zaharava Ensembles from Sydney.
The show was ably compered by Kristie Carter, a TV presenter from Newcastle, NSW.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>18-ий З’ЇЗД УЧИТЕЛІВ УКРАЇНСЬКИХ ШКІЛ АВСТРАЛІЇ</title>
      <link>https://ukrainians.org.au/events/national-events/18-%d0%b8%d0%b9-%d0%97%d0%87%d0%97%d0%94-%d0%a3%d0%a7%d0%98%d0%a2%d0%95%d0%9b%d0%86%d0%92-%d0%a3%d0%9a%d0%a0%d0%90%d0%87%d0%9d%d0%a1%d0%ac%d0%9a%d0%98%d0%a5-%d0%a8%d0%9a%d0%86%d0%9b-%d0%90/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Apr 2012 06:08:10 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ukrainians.org.au/events/national-events/18-%d0%b8%d0%b9-%d0%97%d0%87%d0%97%d0%94-%d0%a3%d0%a7%d0%98%d0%a2%d0%95%d0%9b%d0%86%d0%92-%d0%a3%d0%9a%d0%a0%d0%90%d0%87%d0%9d%d0%a1%d0%ac%d0%9a%d0%98%d0%a5-%d0%a8%d0%9a%d0%86%d0%9b-%d0%90/</guid>
      <description>УКРАЇНСЬКА ЦЕНТРАЛЬНА ШКІЛЬНА РАДА
скликає
18-ий З’ЇЗД УЧИТЕЛІВ УКРАЇНСЬКИХ ШКІЛ АВСТРАЛІЇ,
який відбудеться
у суботу-неділю, 9-10 червня 2012 року,
у приміщеннi школи ім. митр. А. Шептицького
(35 Canning Street, North Melbourne)
Запрошуємо до участі керівників, учителів, голів Батьківських комітетів усіх шкіл та всіх, кому важлива майбутність українського шкільництва.
За інформаціями звертатися до Марії Вандер Верф(моб. 0410 584 326) або електронно education@ozeukes.com</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>МІЖНАРОДНИЙ КОНКУРС З УКРАЇНСЬКОЇ МОВИ ІМ. ПЕТРА ЯЦИКА  В АВСТРАЛІЇ 2012 р.</title>
      <link>https://ukrainians.org.au/events/%d0%9c%d0%86%d0%96%d0%9d%d0%90%d0%a0%d0%9e%d0%94%d0%9d%d0%98%d0%99-%d0%9a%d0%9e%d0%9d%d0%9a%d0%a3%d0%a0%d0%a1-%d0%97-%d0%a3%d0%9a%d0%a0%d0%90%d0%87%d0%9d%d0%a1%d0%ac%d0%9a%d0%9e%d0%87-%d0%9c%d0%9e/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Apr 2012 05:18:08 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ukrainians.org.au/events/%d0%9c%d0%86%d0%96%d0%9d%d0%90%d0%a0%d0%9e%d0%94%d0%9d%d0%98%d0%99-%d0%9a%d0%9e%d0%9d%d0%9a%d0%a3%d0%a0%d0%a1-%d0%97-%d0%a3%d0%9a%d0%a0%d0%90%d0%87%d0%9d%d0%a1%d0%ac%d0%9a%d0%9e%d0%87-%d0%9c%d0%9e/</guid>
      <description>Центр україністики ім. Миколи Зерова, Університет ім. Монаша
та Українська Центральна Шкільна Рада Австралії
**МІЖНАРОДНИЙ КОНКУРС З УКРАЇНСЬКОЇ МОВИ ІМ. ПЕТРА ЯЦИКА В АВСТРАЛІЇ **
Субота 26-го травня 2012 р.
 10.30 – 12.00 (східні штати Австралії))
10.00 – 11.30 (Південна Австралія та Північна Територія)
8.30 – 10.00 (Західна Австралія)
Завдання конкурсу – заохочувати дітей та молодих людей в Україні та по всьому світі вивчати українську мови та користуватися нею.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Jacyk International Ukrainian Language Competition in Australia</title>
      <link>https://ukrainians.org.au/events/jacyk-international-ukrainian-language-competition-in-australia/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Apr 2012 05:12:57 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ukrainians.org.au/events/jacyk-international-ukrainian-language-competition-in-australia/</guid>
      <description>Mykola Zerov Centre for Ukrainian Studies, Monash University
and
the Ukrainian Education Council of Australia
PETRO JACYK INTERNATIONAL UKRAINIAN LANGUAGE COMPETITION:
AUSTRALIA-WIDE COMPETITION 2012
 Saturday 26 May 2012:
10.30 a.m - 12:00 noon (Eastern States)
10.00 a.m - 11.30 a.m (South Australia and Northern Territory)
8.30 a.m - 10.00 a.m (Western Australia)
The competition promotes the knowledge and use of the Ukrainian language among children, teenagers and young adults in Ukraine and throughout the world.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Д-р Сергій Квіт приїде до Австралії</title>
      <link>https://ukrainians.org.au/events/national-events/dr-kvit-coming-to-australia/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 08 Apr 2012 07:01:51 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ukrainians.org.au/events/national-events/dr-kvit-coming-to-australia/</guid>
      <description>Союз Українських Організацій Австралії (CYOA) має приємність повідомити все українське громадянство що 20-го квітня до Австралії приїде Д-р Сергій Квіт, президент Українського Національного Університету “Києво-Могилянської Академії”.
Д-р. Квіт приїзджає на запрошення СУОА щоби відбути акадимічні зустрічі і виступи в австралійських університетах. Рівно ж Д-р Квіт користаючи свого побуту в Австралії виступить на українських громадських та австралійських форумах.
Д-р Квіт в 1990-их роках був одним з організаторів та членом проводу Конґресу Українських Націоналістів.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dr Serhiy Kvit to visit Australia</title>
      <link>https://ukrainians.org.au/events/national-events/dr-serhiy-kvit-to-visit-australia/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Apr 2012 03:42:23 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ukrainians.org.au/events/national-events/dr-serhiy-kvit-to-visit-australia/</guid>
      <description>Dr Serhiy Kvit to visit Australia At the invitation of the Australia Federation of Ukrainian Organisations (AFUO), Dr Serhiy Kvit, the Chancellor of the National University &amp;ldquo;Kyiv Mohyla Academy&amp;rdquo; in Ukraine will be visiting Australia and undertaking a lecture tour in late April – early May 2012. He will also avail himself of the opportunity to visit several universities and meet with the Ukrainian communities, politicians and other dignitaries.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SBS Radio Schedule Review</title>
      <link>https://ukrainians.org.au/events/national-events/sbs-radio-schedule-review/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Apr 2012 04:58:18 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ukrainians.org.au/events/national-events/sbs-radio-schedule-review/</guid>
      <description>SBS is reviewing its radio schedule to ensure it reflects today’s Australia.
To find out more and provide your feedback, visit http://www.sbs.com.au/consultation by April 30 2012.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>AFUO Call to Action - Australian Embassy In Kyiv - Заклик до дії</title>
      <link>https://ukrainians.org.au/politics/afuo-call-to-action-australian-embassy-in-kyiv/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Feb 2012 00:33:52 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ukrainians.org.au/politics/afuo-call-to-action-australian-embassy-in-kyiv/</guid>
      <description>The Australian Federation of Ukrainian Organisations (AFUO) calls on all Ukrainian organisations and interested individuals to write to relevant Members of Parliament endorsing the AFUO submission to open an Australian Embassy in Kyiv.

Союз Українських Організацій Австралії закликає всіх членів CУОA та зацікавлених одиниць написати листа до доречних членів парламенту за підтримку подання CУОA в справі Поcольcтва Aвcтрaлії в Києві.
Call to Action (English): ACTION KYIV EMBASSY 21 2 2012 (Eng)</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>HOPAK IN THE PARK 2012</title>
      <link>https://ukrainians.org.au/events/victoria/hopak-in-the-park-2012/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 31 Jan 2012 00:43:17 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ukrainians.org.au/events/victoria/hopak-in-the-park-2012/</guid>
      <description>[ ](http://www.ozeukes.com/wp-content/uploads/2012/01/FINAL-Hopak-in-the-park-2012-thumb.jpg)
 UKRAINIAN COSSACK DANCE SPECTACULAR HOPAK IN THE PARK! 28 April 2012 – Melbourne Australia  The Australian Federation of Ukrainian Organisations (AFUO) which represents over 20 Ukrainian Organisations in Australia, invites you to this year&amp;rsquo;s &amp;ldquo;Hopak in the Park&amp;rdquo;, which will be presented on Saturday 28 April 2012 at the Sidney Myer Music Bowl in Melbourne.
See our YouTube promotion for “Hopak in the Park”. Click here : http://www.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Українська мова під загрозою. Гаряче повідомлення</title>
      <link>https://ukrainians.org.au/events/national-events/%d0%a3%d0%ba%d1%80%d0%b0%d1%97%d0%bd%d1%81%d1%8c%d0%ba%d0%b0-%d0%bc%d0%be%d0%b2%d0%b0-%d0%bf%d1%96%d0%b4-%d0%b7%d0%b0%d0%b3%d1%80%d0%be%d0%b7%d0%be%d1%8e-%d0%93%d0%b0%d1%80%d1%8f%d1%87%d0%b5-%d0%bf/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 Jan 2012 08:17:27 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ukrainians.org.au/events/national-events/%d0%a3%d0%ba%d1%80%d0%b0%d1%97%d0%bd%d1%81%d1%8c%d0%ba%d0%b0-%d0%bc%d0%be%d0%b2%d0%b0-%d0%bf%d1%96%d0%b4-%d0%b7%d0%b0%d0%b3%d1%80%d0%be%d0%b7%d0%be%d1%8e-%d0%93%d0%b0%d1%80%d1%8f%d1%87%d0%b5-%d0%bf/</guid>
      <description>ЗБЕРЕЖІМО МАТУРУ З УКРАЇНСЬКОЇ МОВИ
Українська мова під загрозою виключення її, як предмета до матури (VCE/HSC /SACE) хібащо зможемо запевнити щонайменше 15 учнів річно в 2012, 2013 і 2014 рр. Як можете допомогти? Вписуйтеся на навчання, незалежно від віку.
Читайте далі&amp;hellip; Збережімо матуру з української мови</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>LOTE Ukrainian in danger</title>
      <link>https://ukrainians.org.au/events/national-events/lote-ukrainian-in-danger/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 Jan 2012 08:06:07 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ukrainians.org.au/events/national-events/lote-ukrainian-in-danger/</guid>
      <description>Ukrainian as a registered year 11 &amp;amp; 12 subject will be suspended unless enrolments for 2013 &amp;amp; 2014 increase. What can you do about it? Enrol now - age no barrier.
Read more Save LOTE Ukrainian</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Українські школи запрошують дітей і дорослих на навчання </title>
      <link>https://ukrainians.org.au/events/national-events/%d0%a3%d0%ba%d1%80%d0%b0%d1%97%d0%bd%d1%81%d1%8c%d0%ba%d1%96-%d1%88%d0%ba%d0%be%d0%bb%d0%b8-%d0%b7%d0%b0%d0%bf%d1%80%d0%be%d1%88%d1%83%d1%8e%d1%82%d1%8c-%d0%b4%d1%96%d1%82%d0%b5%d0%b9-%d1%96-%d0%b4/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 Jan 2012 07:53:51 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ukrainians.org.au/events/national-events/%d0%a3%d0%ba%d1%80%d0%b0%d1%97%d0%bd%d1%81%d1%8c%d0%ba%d1%96-%d1%88%d0%ba%d0%be%d0%bb%d0%b8-%d0%b7%d0%b0%d0%bf%d1%80%d0%be%d1%88%d1%83%d1%8e%d1%82%d1%8c-%d0%b4%d1%96%d1%82%d0%b5%d0%b9-%d1%96-%d0%b4/</guid>
      <description>Читайте далі&amp;hellip; Українські школи запрошують на навчання 2012 р.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ukrainian Schools accepting enrolments for children&#39;s and adult classes</title>
      <link>https://ukrainians.org.au/events/national-events/ukrainian-schools-accepting-enrolments-for-childrens-and-adult-classes/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 Jan 2012 07:49:25 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ukrainians.org.au/events/national-events/ukrainian-schools-accepting-enrolments-for-childrens-and-adult-classes/</guid>
      <description>Ukrainian schools accepting enrolments for 2012</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ВІДЗНAЧЕННЯ 100 РІЧЧЯ ПЛACТУ В AВCТРAЛІЇ</title>
      <link>https://ukrainians.org.au/events/national-events/100-years-of-plast-in-australia/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 08 Jan 2012 05:31:24 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ukrainians.org.au/events/national-events/100-years-of-plast-in-australia/</guid>
      <description>**МAРІЧКA ГAЛAБУРДA – ЧИГРИН **
_Cідней** – 4.1.2012**_
** ВІДЗНAЧЕННЯ 100 РІЧЧЯ ПЛACТУ В AВCТРAЛІЇ** **100 літ – хоч відносно і не є великим шматком часу в історії та в житті української спільноти, чи якоїсь організації, а особливо для Пласту в Aвстралії, це є досить поважний час – це є час її народження, ставання на ноги, перші її кроки, час росту і оформлення організації в сильну світову клітину. **</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Надзвичайний З’їзд Крайової Управи Союзу Українок Австралії</title>
      <link>https://ukrainians.org.au/events/national-events/%d0%9d%d0%b0%d0%b4%d0%b7%d0%b2%d0%b8%d1%87%d0%b0%d0%b9%d0%bd%d0%b8%d0%b9-%d0%97%e2%80%99%d1%97%d0%b7%d0%b4-%d0%9a%d1%80%d0%b0%d0%b9%d0%be%d0%b2%d0%be%d1%97-%d0%a3%d0%bf%d1%80%d0%b0%d0%b2%d0%b8-%d0%a1/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Nov 2011 01:29:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ukrainians.org.au/events/national-events/%d0%9d%d0%b0%d0%b4%d0%b7%d0%b2%d0%b8%d1%87%d0%b0%d0%b9%d0%bd%d0%b8%d0%b9-%d0%97%e2%80%99%d1%97%d0%b7%d0%b4-%d0%9a%d1%80%d0%b0%d0%b9%d0%be%d0%b2%d0%be%d1%97-%d0%a3%d0%bf%d1%80%d0%b0%d0%b2%d0%b8-%d0%a1/</guid>
      <description>В суботу, 3-го вересня 2011 р., в Прицерковній залі УКЦ св.Андрія в Лідкомбі (Сідней), відбувся Надзвичайний Крайовий З’їзд Союзу Українок Австралії.
Цей З’їзд був покликаний у зв’язку з тим, що під час ХХІІ-го Крайового З’їзду СУ, який відбувався 19 та 20 червня 2010 року, не були обрані голова та члени Крайової Управи, а також члени Контрольної Комісії. З’їзд не прийшов до єдиного рішення щодо підтвердження поданого списку кандидатів до нової Управи СУА, яка мала залишитися у Новій Південній Валії на четверту каденцію.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>National Youth Week Grants Program</title>
      <link>https://ukrainians.org.au/events/national-events/national-youth-week-grants-program/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Sep 2011 02:19:13 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ukrainians.org.au/events/national-events/national-youth-week-grants-program/</guid>
      <description>National Youth Week (NYW) is the largest celebration of young people on the Australian youth calendar. The event provides an opportunity for young people to express their ideas, showcase their talents, have their voices heard on issues that affect their lives, celebrate their positive contribution to the community and most importantly, have fun. The celebrations will run from 13 - 22 April 2012.
 Funding will be available for organisations to host a NYW event that brings young people together.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>60th anniversary of Ukrainian schools in Australia Saturday Sept. 10th</title>
      <link>https://ukrainians.org.au/events/60th-anniversary-of-ukrainian-schools-in-australia-saturday-sept-10th/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 04 Sep 2011 04:44:57 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ukrainians.org.au/events/60th-anniversary-of-ukrainian-schools-in-australia-saturday-sept-10th/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Independence Day Sticker Competition</title>
      <link>https://ukrainians.org.au/events/national-events/independence-day-sticker-competition/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Aug 2011 01:17:57 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ukrainians.org.au/events/national-events/independence-day-sticker-competition/</guid>
      <description>The Australian Federation of Ukrainian Organisations (AFUO) recently organised and received 21 entries for the 20th Anniversary of Ukraine’s Independence Sticker Competition.
All the designs were presented to ONLY the AFUO Board members in an anonymous fashion where they were voted on.
All the submitted designs are shown here: 
Once all the votes were cast and counted there was a clear winner, with 2nd through to 7th place extremely close.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>UKRAINE&#39;S NATIONAL DAY CELEBRATIONS IN AUSTRALIA</title>
      <link>https://ukrainians.org.au/events/national-events/ukraines-national-day-celebrations-in-australia/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Aug 2011 12:22:32 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ukrainians.org.au/events/national-events/ukraines-national-day-celebrations-in-australia/</guid>
      <description>﻿
Ukraine celebrates its 20th Anniversary of Independence on 24th August 2011  Australia&amp;rsquo;s Ukrainian community will also celebrate this occasion around that date with events in all States.
Join your local Ukrainian Association to celebrate Ukraine&amp;rsquo;s National Day (24th August). For specific information on State celebrations and event information contact your local Ukrainian Association or check the OzeUkes website by clicking on the image (where available) adjoining the specific event.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Census – 2011 / Перепис 2011</title>
      <link>https://ukrainians.org.au/events/national-events/census%e2%80%932011/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Aug 2011 12:53:05 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ukrainians.org.au/events/national-events/census%e2%80%932011/</guid>
      <description>[ ](http://www.ozeukes.com/wp-content/uploads/2011/08/abs_logo_thumb.jpg)
НАГАДУВАННЯ Перепис населення Австралії 2011 УКРАЇНСЬКЕ ПОХОДЖЕННЯ Дата перепису: вівторок 9-го серпня 2011 року.
 Цього року австралійський уряд знову проводить перепис населення Австралії (Census).
На домашній переписовій формі (Household Form) кожний господар хати зобов’язаний подати різні дані відносно всіх осіб, які ночували тієї ночі в його хаті. На формі є місце для даних для шести осіб. У випадку, де більшe шeсти осіб ночувало в хаті, можна придбати додаткові форми.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Reminder of Independence Day Logo Design Competition</title>
      <link>https://ukrainians.org.au/events/national-events/reminder-of-independence-day-logo-design-competition/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Jul 2011 05:40:36 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ukrainians.org.au/events/national-events/reminder-of-independence-day-logo-design-competition/</guid>
      <description>The Australian Federation of Ukrainian Organisations (AFUO) has previously announced a national competition to design a logo which can be used as a sticker to mark the 20th anniversary of Ukraine’s independence. Time is running out.
ENTRIES MUST BE SUBMITTED BY CLOSE OF BUSINESS, 8TH AUGUST 2011.
** **
****
The design must be original artwork which does not infringe any copyright.
A prize to the value of $200, donated by Dnister Ukrainian Credit Co-operative, will be awarded to the winning entry.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Independence Day Logo Design Competition</title>
      <link>https://ukrainians.org.au/events/national-events/independence-day-logo-design-competition/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Jul 2011 09:34:02 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ukrainians.org.au/events/national-events/independence-day-logo-design-competition/</guid>
      <description>The Australian Federation of Ukrainian Organisations (AFUO) hereby announces a national competition to design a logo which can be used as a sticker to mark the 20th anniversary of Ukraine’s independence. The design must be original artwork which does not infringe any copyright.
A prize to the value of $200, donated by Dnister Ukrainian Credit Co-operative, will be awarded to the winning entry.
All entries, together with a completed Competition Agreement and Entry Form must be submitted by close of business, 8th August 2011 in electronic format to finance@ozeukes.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dnister Annual general meeting 2011 / Загальні збори Дністра</title>
      <link>https://ukrainians.org.au/events/national-events/dnister-annual-general-meeting-2011-%d0%97%d0%b0%d0%b3%d0%b0%d0%bb%d1%8c%d0%bd%d1%96-%d0%b7%d0%b1%d0%be%d1%80%d0%b8-%d0%94%d0%bd%d1%96%d1%81%d1%82%d1%80%d0%b0/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Jun 2011 03:18:31 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ukrainians.org.au/events/national-events/dnister-annual-general-meeting-2011-%d0%97%d0%b0%d0%b3%d0%b0%d0%bb%d1%8c%d0%bd%d1%96-%d0%b7%d0%b1%d0%be%d1%80%d0%b8-%d0%94%d0%bd%d1%96%d1%81%d1%82%d1%80%d0%b0/</guid>
      <description>﻿The 2011 Annual General Meeting will be held on Sunday 13th.November 2011 at the Ukrainian Orthodox Church Hall - 91 Buckley Street, Essendon VIC 3040. Registration will commence at 1.00pm and the meeting will start at 1.30pm.

 Загальні збори кооперативи відбудуться в неділю, 13-го листопада 2011 року в залі Української Православної Церкви - Buckley Street, Essendon VIC 3040. Реєстрація почнеться о годині 1.00 пп., збори почнуться о 1.30 пп.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Petro Jacyk International Ukrainian Language Competition in Australia</title>
      <link>https://ukrainians.org.au/events/petro-jacyk-international-ukrainian-language-competition-in-australia/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Jun 2011 07:35:18 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ukrainians.org.au/events/petro-jacyk-international-ukrainian-language-competition-in-australia/</guid>
      <description>The deadline for registrations for the Jacyk International Ukrainian Language Competition in Australia has been extended until Tuesday June 21st 11:59pm.
Please pass this information on to all your Ukrainian friends and relatives.
If you have already registered, thank you for your application and you will receive an email before the competition with more information.
Participants: The Competition is open to all children and young people resident in Australia, whether or not they are enrolled in a formal Ukrainian-language course at a school or university.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Конкурс з української мови ім. Петра Яцика в Австралії 25.6.2011</title>
      <link>https://ukrainians.org.au/events/%d0%9a%d0%be%d0%bd%d0%ba%d1%83%d1%80%d1%81-%d0%b7-%d1%83%d0%ba%d1%80%d0%b0%d1%97%d0%bd%d1%81%d1%8c%d0%ba%d0%be%d1%97-%d0%bc%d0%be%d0%b2%d0%b8-%d1%96%d0%bc-%d0%9f%d0%b5%d1%82%d1%80%d0%b0-%d0%af%d1%86/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Jun 2011 07:26:14 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ukrainians.org.au/events/%d0%9a%d0%be%d0%bd%d0%ba%d1%83%d1%80%d1%81-%d0%b7-%d1%83%d0%ba%d1%80%d0%b0%d1%97%d0%bd%d1%81%d1%8c%d0%ba%d0%be%d1%97-%d0%bc%d0%be%d0%b2%d0%b8-%d1%96%d0%bc-%d0%9f%d0%b5%d1%82%d1%80%d0%b0-%d0%af%d1%86/</guid>
      <description>Шановні Пані та Панове! Дорогі діти та молоде!
Запрошуємо взяти участь у конкурсі з української мови ім. Петра Яцика в Австралії 25 червня 2011 р., і зголоситися до 21 червня. Будь ласка, передайте інформації всім, кого це можливо би цікавило. Деталі подані нижче:
Дякуємо всім, хто вже зголосився на конкурс, ви незабаром отримите більше інформацій.
Участь у Конкурсі Учасники: У Конкурсі мають право брати участь всі діти та молоді люди, які проживають в Австралії, незалежно від того, чи вони формально навчаються на курсах з української мови в школі чи університеті.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Queen&#39;s Birthday 2011 Honours List Announcement</title>
      <link>https://ukrainians.org.au/events/national-events/the-queens-birthday-2011-honours-list-announcement/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Jun 2011 04:13:42 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ukrainians.org.au/events/national-events/the-queens-birthday-2011-honours-list-announcement/</guid>
      <description>The Queen’s Birthday 2011 Honours List was announced today by the Governor-General. The list provides national and formal recognition for many Australians across the nation who have made a significant difference to their communities.
Included in this year’s Honours List was the following entry:
Short bio of Natalie Tarawski-Radywyl:
 * Artistic Director and Choreographer, Veselka Ukrainian Dance Ensemble (previously the Ukrainian National Ballet), Sydney, 1952-1997; tour of Canada and the USA (1980s) and Ukraine (1991).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Roztiazhka’s Got Talent</title>
      <link>https://ukrainians.org.au/events/national-events/roztiazhka%e2%80%99s-got-talent/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 May 2011 02:35:17 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ukrainians.org.au/events/national-events/roztiazhka%e2%80%99s-got-talent/</guid>
      <description>Roztiazhka, a Ukrainian dance company from Perth in Western Australia, has recently appeared on Channel 7’s talent show Australia’s Got Talent. The judges were highly impressed, and Roztiazhka have got through to the next round. Congratulations to all the dancers on a fantastic performance. Best wishes. Щасливо!
Watch the performance here: http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=CgSJVU_tj18
Roztiazka also took part in the recent highly-successful Hopak in the Park dance spectacular.
Roztiazka web-site: http://www.roztiazhka.com/</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Senate Resolution on 25th Anniversary of Chornobyl Disaster</title>
      <link>https://ukrainians.org.au/events/national-events/senate-resolution-on-25th-anniversary-of-chornobyl-disaster/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 22 May 2011 10:15:24 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ukrainians.org.au/events/national-events/senate-resolution-on-25th-anniversary-of-chornobyl-disaster/</guid>
      <description>On May 11, 2011 the Senate of the Australian Parliament, on the initiative of Senator Catryna Bilyk, passed a resolution regarding the 25th anniversary of the Chornobyl disaster.
The resolution noted a number of important factors impacting the international community and Ukraine, including:
  Relevant heavy social and economic impacts on the population and areas affected by the Chornobyl disaster;
  Shut down by Ukraine (in 1991, 1996 and 2000) of the three remaining reactors at the Chornobyl site and construction of the confinement over reactor number four which urgently requires replacement;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Praise for Hopak in the Park / Похвала Гопаку в Парку</title>
      <link>https://ukrainians.org.au/events/national-events/praise-for-hopak-in-the-park/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 19 May 2011 03:57:38 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ukrainians.org.au/events/national-events/praise-for-hopak-in-the-park/</guid>
      <description>A large number of letters, e-mails, etc have been received praising the inaugural _Hopak in the Park _event. Below is a small selection. Надійшла велика кількість листів, електронної пошти і т.д. з похвалою відносно першого представленню _Гопаку в Парку. _Нище є подані декілька таких висловів.
﻿
We found the event thoroughly entertaining and were pleased to meet with so many friendly members of Australia&amp;rsquo;s Ukrainian community.﻿﻿﻿CATRYNA BILYK - Senator for Tasmania Full text: HitP0003</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hopak in the Park – Photos / Знимки</title>
      <link>https://ukrainians.org.au/events/national-events/hopak-in-the-park-%e2%80%93-photos-%d0%97%d0%bd%d0%b8%d0%bc%d0%ba%d0%b8/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 May 2011 03:01:30 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ukrainians.org.au/events/national-events/hopak-in-the-park-%e2%80%93-photos-%d0%97%d0%bd%d0%b8%d0%bc%d0%ba%d0%b8/</guid>
      <description>
A number of photographers took photographs of the Hopak in the Park dance festival on Saturday 30 April 2011.  Two such series can be viewed here:
 * [http://www.pbase.com/demchinsky/hopak2011](http://www.pbase.com/demchinsky/hopak2011) * [http://www.flickr.com/photos/moravski/sets/72157626637243038/](http://www.flickr.com/photos/moravski/sets/72157626637243038/)    
Декілька осіб зняли знимок фестивалю Гопак у Парку (Hopak in the Park) який**_ _**відбувся в суботу 30-ого квітня 2011 року. Дві такі серії знимо можна переглянути отут:
 * [http://www.pbase.com/demchinsky/hopak2011](http://www.pbase.com/demchinsky/hopak2011) * [http://www.flickr.com/photos/moravski/sets/72157626637243038/](http://www.flickr.com/photos/moravski/sets/72157626637243038/)   </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hopak in the Park - Raffle Winners</title>
      <link>https://ukrainians.org.au/events/national-events/hitp-raffle-winners/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 May 2011 05:41:40 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ukrainians.org.au/events/national-events/hitp-raffle-winners/</guid>
      <description>[ ](http://www.ozeukes.com/wp-content/uploads/2011/05/combined-Inter-Airlines_TravelWiz_Thai-Airlines-thumbnail.jpg)Raffle Prizes
 A raffle was conducted as part of the fund-raising exercise for Hopak in the Park. The draw was held on Saturday evening 30 April 2011 during the ‘One Night with Hrim’ zabava.
The winners of the major prizes were:
 [ ](http://www.ozeukes.com/wp-content/uploads/2011/05/combined-Inter-Airlines_TravelWiz_Thai-Airlines.jpg)
 1st prize 2 return tickets to Bangkok
Donated by Thai Airways, Inter-Airlines Consolidated Group and Travelwiz
Value $2500
Winner Slavko Kowalczuk, South Australia</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Webcast - Hopak in the Park / Гопак у Парку</title>
      <link>https://ukrainians.org.au/events/international-events/webcast-hopak-in-the-park-%d0%93%d0%be%d0%bf%d0%b0%d0%ba-%d1%83-%d0%9f%d0%b0%d1%80%d0%ba%d1%83/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 May 2011 04:19:31 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ukrainians.org.au/events/international-events/webcast-hopak-in-the-park-%d0%93%d0%be%d0%bf%d0%b0%d0%ba-%d1%83-%d0%9f%d0%b0%d1%80%d0%ba%d1%83/</guid>
      <description>HOPAK IN THE PARK  What an impressive spectacle!! ГОПАК У ПАРКУ  Яке вражаюче видовище!! If you missed the show, you can see a full webcast replay:
Якщо пропустила цей спектакль, можна в повньому переглянути:
http://www.learnbywebcam.com.au/webcasting/stream.php?id=14</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hopak in the Park – Latest Updates</title>
      <link>https://ukrainians.org.au/events/national-events/hopak-in-the-park-%e2%80%93-latest-updates/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 Apr 2011 05:29:50 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ukrainians.org.au/events/national-events/hopak-in-the-park-%e2%80%93-latest-updates/</guid>
      <description>Ticket sales for Hopak in the Park are progressing well. Don’t be disappointed, don’t miss out – buy your tickets now. Gates open on Saturday 30th April 2011 at 1:00 pm. Tickets can be purchased through the Arts Centre.
Victorian Government Ministers Matthew Guy and Nicholas Kotsiras together with Australian Government Senator and Chair of the ‘Australia - Ukraine Parliamentary Group’ Senator Catryna Bilyk will officially open proceedings.
This inaugural event will provide great entertainment for the whole family.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>HOPAK IN THE PARK – Event Details</title>
      <link>https://ukrainians.org.au/events/national-events/hopak-in-the-park-%e2%80%93-event-details/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Apr 2011 07:47:58 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ukrainians.org.au/events/national-events/hopak-in-the-park-%e2%80%93-event-details/</guid>
      <description>Hopak in the Park – Date and Times The Ukrainian Cossack Dance Spectacular ‘Hopak in the Park’ will occur on Saturday 30th April 2011 at The Sidney Myer Music Bowl in Melbourne.
Gates for the viewing public access will open at 1:00 pm and will close at 6.00 pm.

Tickets
There is a 2,500 seating capacity mostly undercover.
Over one thousand tickets have already been sold.
All people attending the performance are required to have tickets.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>“ГОПАК У ПАРКУ”</title>
      <link>https://ukrainians.org.au/events/%e2%80%9c%d0%93%d0%9e%d0%9f%d0%90%d0%9a-%d0%a3-%d0%9f%d0%90%d0%a0%d0%9a%d0%a3%e2%80%9d/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Mar 2011 09:46:22 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ukrainians.org.au/events/%e2%80%9c%d0%93%d0%9e%d0%9f%d0%90%d0%9a-%d0%a3-%d0%9f%d0%90%d0%a0%d0%9a%d0%a3%e2%80%9d/</guid>
      <description>**УПРАВА СУОА **
ЗАПРОШУЄ
 всіх, хто любить українські танці, на грандіозний концерт ** ** “ГОПАК У ПАРКУ”,
 який відбудеться у Мельборні,
 в** Sidney Myer Music Bowl**
у суботу, 30–го квітня, 2011–го року.
 За більш докладнішою інформацією  завітайте** ****на **** ****вебсайт****: ****http://www.ozeukes.com/ **** **
та звертайтесь до українських Громад у своїх стейтах.
 YouTube реклама про “ГОПАК У ПАРКУ”: http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=k9aBB5JRO7M
  Квітки можна замовити:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ONE NIGHT WITH ГРІМ HRIM</title>
      <link>https://ukrainians.org.au/events/national-events/one-night-with-hrim/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Mar 2011 11:39:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ukrainians.org.au/events/national-events/one-night-with-hrim/</guid>
      <description>The Australian Federation of Ukrainians in Australia (AFUO)
invites all to attend
ONE NIGHT WITH ГРІМ HRIM
direct from New York.
HRIM (ГРІМ) will be playing Ukrainian folk music at a zabava (dance) at the Ukrainian Hall in Essendon straight after ‘Hopak in the Park’ on Saturday 30th April 2011.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Маніфестація в Канберрі - РЕЗОЛЮЦІЇ І МЕМОРАНДУМ</title>
      <link>https://ukrainians.org.au/events/national-events/resolutions-memorandum/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Feb 2011 03:35:44 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ukrainians.org.au/events/national-events/resolutions-memorandum/</guid>
      <description>Підчас маніфестації в Канберрі 19-ого лютого 2011, делегація від учасників дала на руки Посла України в Aвстралії, пана Валентина Aдомайтіса, Меморандум та Резолюції, в якому висловлені вимоги української спільноти в Австралії до Президента України В. Януковича. Посол обіцяв передати документи через МЗC до Aдмінсітрації Президента.
Текст Резолюції:

МІТИНГ** **ПРОТЕСТУ****
ПРОТИ ДІЙ СУЧАСНОЇ ВЛАДИ В УКРАЇНІ НА ЧОЛІ З В. ЯНУКОВИЧЕМ
**C****КЛИКАНИЙ ****В КAНБЕРРІ, AВСТРАЛІЇ **** **
**CОЮЗОМ УКРАЇНСЬКИХ ОРГAНІЗAЦІЙ AВCТРAЛІЇ **** **</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ПРЕCОВЕ ПОВІДОМЛЕННЯ</title>
      <link>https://ukrainians.org.au/events/national-events/%d0%9f%d0%a0%d0%95c%d0%9e%d0%92%d0%95-%d0%9f%d0%9e%d0%92%d0%86%d0%94%d0%9e%d0%9c%d0%9b%d0%95%d0%9d%d0%9d%d0%af/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Feb 2011 05:01:20 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ukrainians.org.au/events/national-events/%d0%9f%d0%a0%d0%95c%d0%9e%d0%92%d0%95-%d0%9f%d0%9e%d0%92%d0%86%d0%94%d0%9e%d0%9c%d0%9b%d0%95%d0%9d%d0%9d%d0%af/</guid>
      <description>21-го лютого 2011
ПРЕCОВЕ ПОВІДОМЛЕННЯ
** **
Aвстралійська українська громада Демонструє перед Українським та Російським Посольствами
Ні! Не будемо мовчати але вимагати
  В суботу 19-го лютого 2011 українська спільнота Aвстралії відбула крайову маніфестацію та демонстрацію під гаслом “Ні! Не будемо мовчати але вимагати” щоби заявити Президентам та урядам України та Росії, що “Очі світу скеровані на Вас_”, “__Вимагаємо припинення порушення національних та людських прав__”,__ __“__Припинення в України анти-конституційн__i__ __поруше**ння**_**_”,_**_ __“__Геть Табачника з уряду__”__, __“__Голодомор – Геноцид__”__.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Canberra Rally - Images of Protest in front of the Russian Embassy</title>
      <link>https://ukrainians.org.au/events/national-events/canberra-rally-images-of-protest-in-front-of-the-russian-embassy/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Feb 2011 04:01:30 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ukrainians.org.au/events/national-events/canberra-rally-images-of-protest-in-front-of-the-russian-embassy/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Canberra Rally - Images of Protest in front of the Ukrainian Embassy</title>
      <link>https://ukrainians.org.au/events/national-events/rally-images-ukrainian-embassy/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Feb 2011 03:33:17 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ukrainians.org.au/events/national-events/rally-images-ukrainian-embassy/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Canberra Rally - Images of Holodomor Commemoration</title>
      <link>https://ukrainians.org.au/events/national-events/canberra-images-holodomor/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Feb 2011 02:38:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ukrainians.org.au/events/national-events/canberra-images-holodomor/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>MEDIA ALERT</title>
      <link>https://ukrainians.org.au/events/national-events/media-alert/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Feb 2011 03:59:20 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ukrainians.org.au/events/national-events/media-alert/</guid>
      <description>MEDIA ALERT
** **
UKRAINIAN COMMUNITY NATIONAL RALLY PUTTING UKRAINIAN AND RUSSIAN GOVERNMENTS ON NOTICE
The world is watching !
Human and National Rights must be defended
 Date **** SATURDAY FEBRUARY 19, 2011 - CANBERRA
** commencing 11.00am**
**Purpose **
 * Rally to protest President of Ukraine Victor Yanukovych&#39;s Regime defying the Constitution of Ukraine which is impacting on rights and freedoms * Respond to call from Ukrainians in Ukraine seeking support to highlight their plight * To protest the Russian Federation&#39;s Medvedev -Putin Regime violating rights of Ukrainians in Russia * Closing down of Ukrainian NGO&#39;s , Cultural centre and Library * Kangaroo courts being applied *  Action</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>NATIONAL RALLY - Updated Details</title>
      <link>https://ukrainians.org.au/events/national-events/rally-update-eng/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Feb 2011 00:19:30 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ukrainians.org.au/events/national-events/rally-update-eng/</guid>
      <description>NATIONAL RALLY Canberra 19/2/2011
Defend Human Rights of ALL Ukrainians! Defend Constitutional Rights!
 The rally in Canberra on Saturday 19th February 2011 will protest against the violation of human and national rights of Ukrainians in Ukraine and in Russia. There will be three components of the rally.
The rally will commence with a commemorative service for the victims of the Holodomor -1932-33 Famine and the lighting of the International Candle of Prayer.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>КРАЙОВА МАНІФЕСТАЦІЯ - Оновлення інформації </title>
      <link>https://ukrainians.org.au/events/national-events/rally-update-ukr/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Feb 2011 00:18:55 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ukrainians.org.au/events/national-events/rally-update-ukr/</guid>
      <description>КРАЙОВА МАНІФЕСТАЦІЯ
Канберра 19.2.2011
В обороні людських прав всім українцям! В обороні конституційних прав!** **
Маніфестація в Канберрі у суботу 19 лютого 2011 протестуватиме проти порушення людських та національних прав українців в Україні та у Росії. Маніфестація складається з трьох частин.
З&amp;rsquo;їзд розпочне з панахидою за загиблих Голодомору -1932-33 та запаленям міжнародної Свічки Моління. Є намір помолитися за тих хто загинули та закликати міжнародну спільноту не забути жертви та судити злочинців Сталинського режиму.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>More Support for &#39;Hopak in the Park&#39;</title>
      <link>https://ukrainians.org.au/events/national-events/more-support-for-hopak-in-the-park/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 13 Feb 2011 23:29:24 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ukrainians.org.au/events/national-events/more-support-for-hopak-in-the-park/</guid>
      <description>Hopak in the Park - Ukrainian Cossack Dance Spectacular
MELBOURNE will spring into action in spectacular style when an army of Ukrainian Cossack dancers hit the Sidney Myer Music Bowl on April 30, 2011 from 1.00pm to 6.00pm.
 Witness a cast of more than 300 Ukrainian dancers from across Australia kick up a storm as they showcase centuries of dazzling dance moves in the outdoor extravaganza Hopak In the Park.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Support for Hopak in the Park</title>
      <link>https://ukrainians.org.au/culture/support-for-hopak-in-the-park/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Feb 2011 11:40:16 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ukrainians.org.au/culture/support-for-hopak-in-the-park/</guid>
      <description>The Australian Federation of Ukrainian Organisations presents
**Hopak in the Park - Ukrainian Cossack Dance Spectacular **
MELBOURNE will spring into action in spectacular style when an army of Ukrainian Cossack dancers hit the Sidney Myer Music Bowl on April 30, 2011 from 1.00pm to 6.00pm.
Witness a cast of more than 300 Ukrainian dancers from across Australia kick up a storm as they showcase centuries of dazzling dance moves in the outdoor extravaganza Hopak In the Park.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>КРАЙОВА МАНІФЕСТАЦІЯ – ПРОГРАМА ДНЯ / NATIONAL RALLY - PROGRAMME</title>
      <link>https://ukrainians.org.au/events/national-events/national-rally-programme/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 04 Feb 2011 02:15:17 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ukrainians.org.au/events/national-events/national-rally-programme/</guid>
      <description>КРАЙОВА МАНІФЕСТАЦІЯ
**Канберра 19.2.2011 Головне Не Мовчати! В обороні конституційних прав! **
  Програма
10.30 рн - 10.45 рн Збірка перед пам&amp;rsquo;ятником Голодомору Ukrainian Orthodox Centre 6 McKay Gardens Turner 11.00 рн - 12.00 пп Панахида, промови,виступи 12.00 пп - 12.15 пп Похід до Посольства України в Aвстралії 12.15 пп - 12.45 пп Віче та передача меморандуму Президентові України 12.45 пп - 1.15 пп Переїзд до Посольства Росії в Aвстралії та збірка 1.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>AUSTRALIAN OPEN 2011 – DOLGOPOLOV GOES DOWN FIGHTING</title>
      <link>https://ukrainians.org.au/events/australian-open-2011-%e2%80%93-dolgopolov-goes-down-fighting/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Jan 2011 23:56:17 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ukrainians.org.au/events/australian-open-2011-%e2%80%93-dolgopolov-goes-down-fighting/</guid>
      <description>As Alexandr Dolgopolov prepared himself for the biggest match of his life, hopes were held high for him to deliver a shock blow to 5th seeded Andy Murray, in their Quarter Final clash.
The match opened with ‘the most unpredictable player on the tour’ immediately forcing several back-to-back, break points against the heavily backed Scotsman. In true form, Murray overcame his initial quarter final jitters and proceeded to take both the first and second sets respectively, 7-5, 6-3.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>MARCHENKO V. MURRAY - After 7pm 20/01/2011 Margaret Court Arena</title>
      <link>https://ukrainians.org.au/events/marchenko-v-murray-after-7pm-20012011-margaret-court-arena/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Jan 2011 05:08:17 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ukrainians.org.au/events/marchenko-v-murray-after-7pm-20012011-margaret-court-arena/</guid>
      <description>**THIS IS A CALL OUT TO ALL UKRAINIAN SUPPORTERS TO COME DOWN TO MELBOURNE PARK TOMORROW, 20th January, 2011 **
AND SUPPORT ONE OF OUR OWN!
MARCHENKO V. MURRAY - After 7pm 20/01/2011 Margaret Court Arena
Don on your Uki colours, grab your flags and warm up your vocal cords. We will aim to hold a few seats reserve in the arena, but best to get there early!
This is sure to be a huge match and with tickets only $20 after 5pm, we’re encouraging everyone and anyone to get down to Margaret Court for 7pm.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hopak in the Park - Tickets on Sale</title>
      <link>https://ukrainians.org.au/culture/hopak-in-the-park-tickets-on-sale/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Jan 2011 11:48:34 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ukrainians.org.au/culture/hopak-in-the-park-tickets-on-sale/</guid>
      <description>30 April 2011 – Melbourne Australia
Sidney Myer Music Bowl
YouTube promotion for “Hopak in the Park”. Click here : http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=k9aBB5JRO7M
To book your tickets online, click here: http://events.theartscentre.com.au/tickets/reserve.aspx?performanceNumber=5974
For condition of entry to the Sidney Myer Music Bowl. please read the following: Conditions of entry MSO 2011 (2)</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>AUSTRALIAN OPEN 2011 – DAY ONE HIGHLIGHTS/DAY TWO SCHEDULE</title>
      <link>https://ukrainians.org.au/events/victoria/australian-open-2011-%e2%80%93-day-one-highlightsday-two-schedule/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Jan 2011 06:53:22 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ukrainians.org.au/events/victoria/australian-open-2011-%e2%80%93-day-one-highlightsday-two-schedule/</guid>
      <description>**AUSTRALIAN OPEN 2011 – **DAY ONE HIGHLIGHTS/DAY TWO SCHEDULE
 “DAY ONE SUCCESS – Stakhovsky through to ROUND 2.”
 As we approach the end of Day 1, Ukraine already has one through to the second round, with Sergiy Stakhovsky breezing through in straight sets against German, Daniel Brands.
Stakhovsky must now face neighbouring Polish competitor, Lukasz Kubot, for round 2. Kubot’s victory over the 18th seeded American, Sam Querrey, indicates that he is in form, so Stakhovsky will need all the support he can get.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>AUSTRALIAN OPEN 2011 - Round 1 (DAY ONE)</title>
      <link>https://ukrainians.org.au/events/australian-open-2011-round-1-day-one/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Jan 2011 00:42:24 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ukrainians.org.au/events/australian-open-2011-round-1-day-one/</guid>
      <description>AUSTRALIAN OPEN 2011
CALLING ON ALL SPORTS FANS!
The wait is over – The 2011 Australian Open is finally here and we’re inviting you to come down and support our athletes**!**
Over the next 2 weeks, the AFUO will be providing regular updates of the successes and movements of all Ukrainian Athletes competing in this year’s 2011 Australian Open.
Each day a new playing schedule will be revised and released. We’ll aim to identify early when the Ukrainian athletes are competing, so that you can arrange a supporters group to come down and cheer on our athletes!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Крайова збірка на допомогу Українській Громаді в Квінсленді</title>
      <link>https://ukrainians.org.au/events/national-events/%d0%9a%d1%80%d0%b0%d0%b9%d0%be%d0%b2%d0%b0-%d0%b7%d0%b1%d1%96%d1%80%d0%ba%d0%b0-%d0%bd%d0%b0-%d0%b4%d0%be%d0%bf%d0%be%d0%bc%d0%be%d0%b3%d1%83-%d0%a3%d0%ba%d1%80%d0%b0%d1%97%d0%bd%d1%81%d1%8c%d0%ba/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 15 Jan 2011 00:05:15 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ukrainians.org.au/events/national-events/%d0%9a%d1%80%d0%b0%d0%b9%d0%be%d0%b2%d0%b0-%d0%b7%d0%b1%d1%96%d1%80%d0%ba%d0%b0-%d0%bd%d0%b0-%d0%b4%d0%be%d0%bf%d0%be%d0%bc%d0%be%d0%b3%d1%83-%d0%a3%d0%ba%d1%80%d0%b0%d1%97%d0%bd%d1%81%d1%8c%d0%ba/</guid>
      <description>Cоюз Укрaїнських Організацій Aвстралії
проголошує
Крайову збірку на допомогу Українській Громаді та yкраїнцям в Квінсленді, потерпілим від повені.
Пожертви можна вплачувати на конто СУОА в Кооперативі Дністер: BSB: 704-235 Account Number: 02801992 Name of Account: Australian Federation of Ukrainian Organisations
Звертаємося до стейтових Громади координувати акцію. Управа CУОA завтра вишле збіркові листи всім громадам. Звертаємося до наших отців духовних провести окрему тацу на ту ціль.
Управа CУОA</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>National Flood Relief Fund to assist the Ukrainian Community in Queensland</title>
      <link>https://ukrainians.org.au/events/national-events/national-flood-relief-fund-to-assist-the-ukrainian-community-in-queensland/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 15 Jan 2011 00:03:22 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ukrainians.org.au/events/national-events/national-flood-relief-fund-to-assist-the-ukrainian-community-in-queensland/</guid>
      <description>Australian Federation of Ukrainian Organisations
announces
A national Flood Relief Fund to assist the Ukrainian Community and Ukrainians in Queensland, affected by the floods.
Donations can be made into the AFUO account in the Dnister Ukrainian Credit Cooperative: BSB: 704-235 Account Number: 02801992 Name of Account: Australian Federation of Ukrainian Organisations
We call on state community organisations to coordinate the activity. The AFUO executive tomorrow will send out Relief Fund forms to all communities.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Webcast of Christmas Divine Liturgy / Різдвяна Архиєрейська Божественна Літургія у Вебкаст</title>
      <link>https://ukrainians.org.au/events/national-events/webcast-of-christmas-divine-liturgy-%d0%a0%d1%96%d0%b7%d0%b4%d0%b2%d1%8f%d0%bd%d0%b0-%d0%90%d1%80%d1%85%d0%b8%d1%94%d1%80%d0%b5%d0%b9%d1%81%d1%8c%d0%ba%d0%b0-%d0%91%d0%be%d0%b6%d0%b5%d1%81%d1%82/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Jan 2011 23:42:05 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ukrainians.org.au/events/national-events/webcast-of-christmas-divine-liturgy-%d0%a0%d1%96%d0%b7%d0%b4%d0%b2%d1%8f%d0%bd%d0%b0-%d0%90%d1%80%d1%85%d0%b8%d1%94%d1%80%d0%b5%d0%b9%d1%81%d1%8c%d0%ba%d0%b0-%d0%91%d0%be%d0%b6%d0%b5%d1%81%d1%82/</guid>
      <description>The Ukrainian Catholic Cathedral Parish of Sts Peter and Paul (Melbourne) will present as a webcast on Eparchial website the Christmas Divine Liturgy on Friday the 7th of January starting at 10 am. The address is http://www.learnbywebcam.com.au/webcasting/stream.php?artid=uks070111
Y системі &amp;ldquo;вебкаст&amp;rdquo; буде показуватися урочиста Різдвяна Архієрейськa Божественнa Літургія з катедри Верх Aп Петра і Павла в Мельборні у прямому ефірі у п’ятницю 7-го січня 2011 о годині 10 дня. Вебкаст можна дивитися по адресу http://www.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>CALL TO ACTION - NATIONAL RALLY - CANBERRA - Saturday February 19 2011</title>
      <link>https://ukrainians.org.au/events/national-events/call-to-action-national-rally-canberra-saturday-february-19-2011/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Dec 2010 00:19:53 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ukrainians.org.au/events/national-events/call-to-action-national-rally-canberra-saturday-february-19-2011/</guid>
      <description>AUSTRALIAN FEDERATION OF UKRAINIAN ORGANISATIONS
 CALL TO ACTION
NATIONAL RALLY - CANBERRA****
Saturday February 19, 2011
Commencing at 11.00am
** **
TIME FOR AUSTRALIA&amp;rsquo;S UKRAINIAN COMMUNITY AND ITS SUPPORTERS
TO SEND A MESSAGE OF NO CONFIDENCE IN UKRAINE&amp;rsquo;S CURRENT LEADERSHIP
and
 A MESSAGE OF SUPPORT FOR THE UKRAINIAN PEOPLE and minorities Ukraine who want to build a strong, national, economically and socially sound Ukraine
Proposed program
 * Commencing with National Remembrance Service for Holodomor Victims at National Holodomor Memorial St Nicholas Orthodox Church - Turner  followed by a</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>VICTORIAN STATE PARLIAMENT HAS FIRST MINISTER OF UKRAINIAN BACKROUND</title>
      <link>https://ukrainians.org.au/events/national-events/victorian-state-parliament-has-first-minister-of-ukrainian-backround/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Dec 2010 00:15:55 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ukrainians.org.au/events/national-events/victorian-state-parliament-has-first-minister-of-ukrainian-backround/</guid>
      <description>The Victorian Parliament has its first Minister of Ukrainian background
The Australian Federation of Ukrainian Organisations (AFUO) extends its congratulations to Matthew Guy MP Victoria&amp;rsquo;s newly appointed Minister for Planning in the new Baillieu Cabinet. The Liberal Coalition won power in the recent Victorian State Elections
Australia&amp;rsquo;s Ukrainian community is proud of the fact that a Victorian of Ukrainian background has achieved such high office.
Matthew &amp;rsquo;s mother Vera comes from the Naumenko family, who settled in Newborough and have been active in their local community.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Aкція Cвічка Моління в Aвстралії та вшанування жертв Голодомору – Ґеноциду</title>
      <link>https://ukrainians.org.au/events/a%d0%ba%d1%86%d1%96%d1%8f-c%d0%b2%d1%96%d1%87%d0%ba%d0%b0-%d0%9c%d0%be%d0%bb%d1%96%d0%bd%d0%bd%d1%8f-%d0%b2-a%d0%b2%d1%81%d1%82%d1%80%d0%b0%d0%bb%d1%96%d1%97-%d1%82%d0%b0-%d0%b2%d1%88%d0%b0%d0%bd/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Nov 2010 03:27:16 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ukrainians.org.au/events/a%d0%ba%d1%86%d1%96%d1%8f-c%d0%b2%d1%96%d1%87%d0%ba%d0%b0-%d0%9c%d0%be%d0%bb%d1%96%d0%bd%d0%bd%d1%8f-%d0%b2-a%d0%b2%d1%81%d1%82%d1%80%d0%b0%d0%bb%d1%96%d1%97-%d1%82%d0%b0-%d0%b2%d1%88%d0%b0%d0%bd/</guid>
      <description>** **
** **
** **
** **
** **
** **
** **
** **
** **
Подається ** **інформації про програму віздначень Голодомору в Австралії. Акції вшанування жертв Голодомору включають передачі Свічки Моління, відправ соборних Панахид, мистецькі виставки та висвітлення фільму &amp;ldquo;Окрадена Земля&amp;rdquo;.
неділя 21-го листопада 2010
_CУМ Оселя Карпати - Вікторія _Запалення Cвічки моління Виступ Голови МКК CКУ по Голодомору Cтефана Романіва Передача свічки з участю проводів та членства Української Громади Вікторії, CУМу, Пласту (Мельборн і Джілонґ) шкільництва та ширшого громадянства - год 10.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New Logo Competition / Конкурс на новий фірмовий знак</title>
      <link>https://ukrainians.org.au/events/new-logo-competition-%d0%9a%d0%be%d0%bd%d0%ba%d1%83%d1%80%d1%81-%d0%bd%d0%b0-%d0%bd%d0%be%d0%b2%d0%b8%d0%b9-%d1%84%d1%96%d1%80%d0%bc%d0%be%d0%b2%d0%b8%d0%b9-%d0%b7%d0%bd%d0%b0%d0%ba/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Nov 2010 14:55:34 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ukrainians.org.au/events/new-logo-competition-%d0%9a%d0%be%d0%bd%d0%ba%d1%83%d1%80%d1%81-%d0%bd%d0%b0-%d0%bd%d0%be%d0%b2%d0%b8%d0%b9-%d1%84%d1%96%d1%80%d0%bc%d0%be%d0%b2%d0%b8%d0%b9-%d0%b7%d0%bd%d0%b0%d0%ba/</guid>
      <description>As a result of using the new name – Kalyna Care
we are looking for a logo that reflects the new name.
The Logo can be anything that is related to the words Kalyna Care be it the Kalyna bush or anything that represents its history and significance to Ukrainian people, their culture and/or traditions.
The rules of the competition are:
1 The Logo is to be developed in line with the new name to be used by UEPH – Kalyna Care</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Inaugural Ukrainian Dance Festival “Hopak in the Park” April 2011</title>
      <link>https://ukrainians.org.au/events/inaugural-hopak-in-the-park/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Jun 2010 13:39:14 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ukrainians.org.au/events/inaugural-hopak-in-the-park/</guid>
      <description>The Australian Federation of Ukrainian Organisations are hosting the inaugural Ukrainian Dance Festival “Hopak in the Park” at the Sidney Myer Music Bowl in April 2011.
The name hopak is derived from the verb hopaty which means “to jump,” as well as the corresponding exclamation hop! which can be uttered during a jump as an expression of surprise or amazement.
The concept is based on a very successful festival that takes place in Canada for a number of years.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Пленарна Нарада - СУОА 2010</title>
      <link>https://ukrainians.org.au/events/%d0%a1%d0%a3%d0%9e%d0%90-2010/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Jun 2010 13:37:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ukrainians.org.au/events/%d0%a1%d0%a3%d0%9e%d0%90-2010/</guid>
      <description>Дорогі Члени CУОA! Повідомляємо, що ПЛЕНAРНA НAРAДA CУОA відбудеться в Мельборні у суботу 26-го - і неділя 27-го червня 2010 р. в Українському Народному Домі, Ессендон
Ціль наради - Окреслити загально- австралійські та місцеві пляни для скріплення нашого громадського життя
Оbjective - To identify national and local plans and strategies for community development
Форма - Круглі столи по темах і панелі та виступи запрошених гостей
Format - Round Tables, Panels Guest speakers</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>