<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Finance on AFUO - СУОА</title>
    <link>https://ukrainians.org.au/categories/finance/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Finance on AFUO - СУОА</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-au</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 30 Dec 2016 21:54:15 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://ukrainians.org.au/categories/finance/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Коляда на Допомогу Українським Солдатам</title>
      <link>https://ukrainians.org.au/politics/christmas-contribution-to-support-our-soldiers-in-ukraine/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Dec 2016 21:54:15 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ukrainians.org.au/politics/christmas-contribution-to-support-our-soldiers-in-ukraine/</guid>
      <description>СУОА - Коляда на Допомогу Українським Солдатам Настають Різдв’яні Свята – В родинному оточенню будемо святкувати народження Ісуса Христа.
Закликаємо Вас у своїх молитвах згадати наших солдатів, які воюють проти Російського агресора на Сході.
Зложіть свою коляду на допомогу нашим солдатам які воюють, тим які повернулися з фронту і потребують нашу допомогу.
Управа СУОА проголошує Коляду на Допомогу Солдатам.
Свою коляду можна зложити на конто U-HELP
BSB: 704-235
ACCOUNT: 00015958</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Local European Business Expo 2016 –  Executive Event summary</title>
      <link>https://ukrainians.org.au/events/local-european-business-expo-2016-executive-event-summary/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Oct 2016 10:55:41 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ukrainians.org.au/events/local-european-business-expo-2016-executive-event-summary/</guid>
      <description>**Local European Business Expo 2016 – Logistics **
Local European Business Expo 2016 was organised on September 18th. 2016 and it gathered 67 exhibitors from participating countries: Poland, Ukraine, Hungary, Czech Republic &amp;amp; Slovakia under one business umbrella conveyed by Eventador (the Organiser for LEBE 2016) to make bridges between countries, businesses and communities existing in Western Australia.
The venue for LEBE 2016 was the premises of Cracovia Club, Beechboro and the event was open for VIP Networking Party from 10:00 to 11:00 and to the public from 11:00 to 16:00.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>AUSTRALIA’S UKRAINIAN COMMUNITY CONTINUES TO SUPPORT UKRAINIAN SOLDIERS AND VOLUNTEERS FIGHTING RUSSIAN AGGRESSION IN EASTERN UKRAINE</title>
      <link>https://ukrainians.org.au/politics/australias-ukrainian-community-continues-to-support-ukrainian-soldiers-and-volunteers-fighting-russian-aggression-in-eastern-ukraine/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Sep 2016 06:51:10 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ukrainians.org.au/politics/australias-ukrainian-community-continues-to-support-ukrainian-soldiers-and-volunteers-fighting-russian-aggression-in-eastern-ukraine/</guid>
      <description>25 вересня 2016
УКРАЇНСЬКА ГРОМАДА АВСТРАЛІЇ ПРОДОВЖУЄ ПІДТРИМУВАТИ УКРАЇНСЬКИХ СОЛДАТІВ І ВОЛОНТЕРІВ, ЯКІ ВОЮЮТЬ ПРОТИ РОСІЙСЬКОЇ АГРЕСІЇ НА СХОДІ УКРАЇНИ Подаємо Грамоту Подяки для СУОА на потреби програми Захист Патріотів з дня 24.9.2016 - за пожертву в сумі $23,000 США (серпнеь 2016).
Управа СУОА дякує всім жертводавцям.
Програма допомоги бійцям, які воюють проти Російської агресії продовжуються .
Вашу пожертву можна вплатити на конто СУОА U-HELP в Кооп. Дністер
BSB: 704-235 Account Number: 00015958</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>AFUO holds discussions with DFAT on furthering Australia-Ukraine relations</title>
      <link>https://ukrainians.org.au/politics/afuo-holds-discussions-with-dfat-on-furthering-australia-ukraine-relations/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Sep 2016 11:32:31 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ukrainians.org.au/politics/afuo-holds-discussions-with-dfat-on-furthering-australia-ukraine-relations/</guid>
      <description>September, 2016
AUSTRALIAN FEDERATION OF UKRAINIAN ORGANISATIONS HOLDS DISCUSSIONS WITH DEPARTMENT OF FOREIGN AFFAIRS AND TRADE ON FURTHERING AUSTRALIA-UKRAINE RELATIONS The Australian Federation of Ukrainians Organisations Chairman Stefan Romaniw recently met with Deputy Secretary of the Australian Government’s Department Foreign Affairs and Trade and Chair of the UN Security Council, Gary Quinlan.
The following issues were discussed:
 * The AFUO call on to Prime Minister Turnbull to ensure the issue of Russian aggression in Eastern Ukraine and annexation of Crimea be raised at the G20 and that the PM to lead the conversation about excluding Russia from the G20.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Local European Business Expo 2016 in Perth</title>
      <link>https://ukrainians.org.au/events/local-european-business-expo-2016-in-perth/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Jun 2016 03:32:26 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ukrainians.org.au/events/local-european-business-expo-2016-in-perth/</guid>
      <description>Dear Ukrainian Hromada,
The Australia-Ukraine Chamber of Commerce (AUCC) is excited to invite your company’s participation in the second edition of the Community Business Expo called “Local European Business Expo 2016” in Western Australia on September 18, 2016
The Local European Business Expo 2016 is an initiative originated from the first edition of “Polish Business Expo 2015” organised by Aneta Gradek and the Polish Community called “Positive Woman Club” in Sept 2015 at Sikorski Club.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>UKRAINE’S AMBASSADOR TO AUSTRALIA VISITING VICTORIA TO PROMOTE  MESSAGE OF GRATITUDE AND THAT UKRAINE IS OPEN FOR BUSINESS</title>
      <link>https://ukrainians.org.au/politics/ukraines-ambassador-to-australia-visiting-victoria-to-promote-message-of-gratitude-and-that-ukraine-is-open-for-business/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 May 2016 03:34:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ukrainians.org.au/politics/ukraines-ambassador-to-australia-visiting-victoria-to-promote-message-of-gratitude-and-that-ukraine-is-open-for-business/</guid>
      <description>**May 26, 2016 **
MEDIA RELEASE UKRAINE’S AMBASSADOR TO AUSTRALIA VISITING VICTORIA TO PROMOTE MESSAGE OF GRATITUDE AND THAT UKRAINE IS OPEN FOR BUSINESS Ukraine’s Ambassador to Australia, His Excellency Mykola Kulinich commences his official Victorian visit today May 26, 2016.
The visit is being facilitated and hosted by the Australian Federation of Ukrainian Organisations(AFUO) and the Association of Ukrainians in Victoria.(AUV)
The AFUO has facilitated a wide-ranging list of meetings for the Ambassador during his stay which include meetings with:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>«Нові ринки» - Австралійсько-Українські форуми OzUke - Australia-Ukraine New Markets. OzUke Forums</title>
      <link>https://ukrainians.org.au/finance/australia-ukraine-new-markets-ozuke-forums/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 May 2016 07:36:18 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ukrainians.org.au/finance/australia-ukraine-new-markets-ozuke-forums/</guid>
      <description>Українсько-Австралійська справа набирає обертів. ПРИЄДНУЙТЕСЬ до двостороннього руху з інтеграції ділових і культурних осередків Австралії та України. Цей рух провадить громадська організація «Австралійсько-Українська Ініціатива» (АУІ) на Міжнародній Комунікаційній Платформі «Нові Ринки».
Всіх хто бажає розширити горизонти своєї справи, кого цікавлять якісно нові можливості співробітництва між Австралією та Україною, хто налаштований на корисне спілкування та результативну взаємодію, запрошуємо до нашої ініціативної команди. Ви долучитесь до широкого кола двосторонніх багаторівневих проектів АУІ та отримаєте змогу втілити свої власні ідеї у цій сфері.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>World&#39;s largest aircraft Ukrainian &#39;Mriya&#39; set to land in Perth</title>
      <link>https://ukrainians.org.au/events/western-australia/worlds-largest-aircraft-ukrainian-mriya-set-to-land-in-perth/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 14 May 2016 10:59:30 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ukrainians.org.au/events/western-australia/worlds-largest-aircraft-ukrainian-mriya-set-to-land-in-perth/</guid>
      <description>14 May 2016
MEDIA RELEASE World’s largest aircraft Ukrainian ‘Mriya’ set to land in Perth On Sunday 15 May at 10am (WST) the Antonov An-225 ‘Mriya’ will make its first-ever trip to Australia when it lands at Perth airport to deliver a generator weighing 130 tons.
Arriving at its final destination of a journey spanning three continents, the crew will be welcomed by Ukraine’s Ambassador to Australia, His Excellency Mykola Kulinich, and Chairman of the Australian Federation of Ukrainian Organisations (AFUO) and General secretary of the Ukrainian World Congress, Mr.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Connecting Communities - Dnister Conference and Focus Group</title>
      <link>https://ukrainians.org.au/events/connecting-communities-dnister-conference-and-focus-group/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Apr 2016 07:34:28 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ukrainians.org.au/events/connecting-communities-dnister-conference-and-focus-group/</guid>
      <description>Together with support from the Australia-Ukraine Chamber of Commerce, Dnister Ukrainian Credit Co-operative is hosting a discussion forum in Queensland on Friday 6th May 2016, at the Hilton Brisbane, to discuss Dnister’s current strategic initiatives and explore avenues for mutual growth and collaboration with the Queensland community.
For more information please refer to Dnister&amp;rsquo;s page dedicated to the event.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>«ФОЛЬКНЕРИ» - ФОНД ПОКРИТТЯ ЛІКАРСЬКИХ ВИТРАТ ПРИ НАРОДЖЕННІ СИНА</title>
      <link>https://ukrainians.org.au/culture/folknery-help-support-hospital-costs-of-their-newly-arrived-son-ukr/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 17 Apr 2016 11:18:18 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ukrainians.org.au/culture/folknery-help-support-hospital-costs-of-their-newly-arrived-son-ukr/</guid>
      <description>14-го квітня 2016
Як Ви напевно вже чули, наші гості з України, Володимир Муляр та Ірина Гаврилець (група «Фолькнери») стали гордими батьками сина Марка.
Марко народився минулого тижня в Royal Women’s Hospital в Сіднеї, 2 місяці раніше терміну, і його потрібно буде тримати в лікарні до двох місяців.
Ірина та Володимир мали замовлені квитки в Аргентину на 2 травня 2016 року, але несподіване народження сина тепер означитиме, що вони повинні залишитися в Австралії протягом довшого періоду.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>FOLKNERY: help support hospital costs of their newly arrived son</title>
      <link>https://ukrainians.org.au/culture/folknery-help-support-hospital-costs-of-their-newly-arrived-son/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Apr 2016 06:27:48 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ukrainians.org.au/culture/folknery-help-support-hospital-costs-of-their-newly-arrived-son/</guid>
      <description>As you may be aware our guests from Ukraine, Folknery - Voloymyr Muliar and Iryna Havrylets are now the proud parents of a newly arrived son Marko.
Marko was born last week 2 months premature in Royal Women’s Hospital in Sydney and will need to spend up to two months in hospital.
Iryna and Volodymyr had tickets booked to Argentina on May 2, 2016, but the unexpected birth of their son will now see them have to stay in Australia for longer period.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Strengthening ties with the Ukrainian Embassy</title>
      <link>https://ukrainians.org.au/gallery/strengthening-ties-with-the-ukrainian-embassy/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Apr 2016 07:25:16 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ukrainians.org.au/gallery/strengthening-ties-with-the-ukrainian-embassy/</guid>
      <description>Dnister team members had the pleasure of meeting with His Excellency, Ukrainian Ambassador to Australia, The Honourable Dr Mykola Kulinich and his Embassy team in Canberra this past week, 6th April 2016.
Read the full story here.
View the photos from the event here.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Local European Business Expo 2016 (Perth, Western Australia)</title>
      <link>https://ukrainians.org.au/events/western-australia/local-european-business-expo-2016-perth-western-australia/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Mar 2016 06:48:29 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ukrainians.org.au/events/western-australia/local-european-business-expo-2016-perth-western-australia/</guid>
      <description>( re-posted from http://aucc.biz/uncategorized/local-european-business-expo-2016-perth-western-australia/ )
The Ukrainian Association of WA (UAWA) and the Australia Ukraine Chamber of Commerce (AUCC) are excited to announce that the Ukrainian Community will be participating in a first ever “Local European Business Expo 2016” in Perth, Western Australia. The Expo will also include Polish &amp;amp; Hungarian Businesses.
The Polish Ambassador, Mr Pawel Milewski, has already confirmed his attendance and will be coming to Perth specifically to welcome the participants and visitors to this extraordinary event.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ОБІЖНИК СУОА Ч. 5. 2015-2018 - ЗВІДОМЛЕННЯ УПРАВИ СУОА ПРО ЗБІРКИ ТА ПРОГРАМИ</title>
      <link>https://ukrainians.org.au/community/obiznyk-cyoa-no-5-2015-2018/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Feb 2016 06:15:46 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ukrainians.org.au/community/obiznyk-cyoa-no-5-2015-2018/</guid>
      <description>29 лютого 2016
ОБІЖНИК СУОА Ч. 5. 2015 – 2018 ЗВІДОМЛЕННЯ УПРАВИ СУОА ПРО ЗБІРКИ ТА ПРОГРАМИ:
 * **U-HELP** * **ROTARY - CARITAS TAX DEDUCTABILITY** * **СКУ - ПРОГРАМА ЗАХИСТ ПАТРІОТІВ ТА ГУМАНІТАРНІ ІНІЦІЯТИВИ**  Управа Союзу Українських Організацій Австралії повідомляє, що далі продовжуються збіркові акції:
 * **U-HELP HUMANITARIAN - EDUCATIONAL - LEADERSHIP PROGRAM** * **ROTARY - CARITAS - Tax Deductable Program**  Війна на сході України продовжується, наслідки цієї кривавої війни катастрофічні.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ukrainian Diaspora Investment Study - The Survey is Ready!</title>
      <link>https://ukrainians.org.au/finance/ukrainian-diaspora-investment-study-the-survey-is-ready/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Feb 2016 10:56:08 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ukrainians.org.au/finance/ukrainian-diaspora-investment-study-the-survey-is-ready/</guid>
      <description>Thank you for your continued support of the US Agency for International Development’s Ukrainian Diaspora Investment Study. The survey is ready! Please show your love for Ukraine this week by taking and distributing the survey FAR AND WIDE throughout the Ukrainian diaspora community and encourage people to take the survey before March 7, 2016.
Please forward this email text to your network and feel free to cut and paste content onto social media.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ukrainian Business and Community Directory seeks to connect all Ukrainians worldwide</title>
      <link>https://ukrainians.org.au/community/ukrainian-business-and-community-directory-seeks-to-connect-all-ukrainians-worldwide/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Feb 2016 11:03:47 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ukrainians.org.au/community/ukrainian-business-and-community-directory-seeks-to-connect-all-ukrainians-worldwide/</guid>
      <description>The Ukrainian Directory has been developed to provide a means of communication for the Ukrainian community worldwide at the community, business, and professional levels, as well as on a personal level. The main idea is to encourage Ukrainians worldwide to support each other in our everyday activities in an endeavor to be more united and to embrace the true spirit of “Свій До Свого,” which means that Ukrainians by origin cooperate with Ukrainians by origin all over the world.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Інтерв&#39;ю з послом України в Австралії паном Миколою Кулінічем на Ukrainian Radio 4EB Brisbane</title>
      <link>https://ukrainians.org.au/politics/interview-mykola-kulinich/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Jan 2016 11:12:51 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ukrainians.org.au/politics/interview-mykola-kulinich/</guid>
      <description>Розмова з новим Наздвичайним і Повноважним послом України в Австралії Миколою Кулінічем під час першого австралійсько-українського бізнес форуму OzUke 2015
Частина 1
Частина 2</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Karpaty Foundation continues to provide funds for major community projects…</title>
      <link>https://ukrainians.org.au/community/karpaty-foundation-continues-to-provide-funds-for-major-community-projects/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 03 Dec 2015 11:11:24 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ukrainians.org.au/community/karpaty-foundation-continues-to-provide-funds-for-major-community-projects/</guid>
      <description>Press Release For Immediate Release 3 December 2015
“Karpaty Foundation continues to provide funds for major community projects…” The Board &amp;amp; Trustees of The Karpaty Foundation have pleasure in announcing that at its recent meeting to review applications for grants and scholarships submitted within the scope of the purpose for which the Foundation was established, three (3) applications for grants were considered. To date, the Foundation has provided some $200,000 in supporting a broad variety of community projects and enabling students to attend various courses at Universities in Ukraine.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>AFUO announces sponsors of the inaugural Australia-Ukraine bilateral forum OzUke 2015</title>
      <link>https://ukrainians.org.au/events/afuo-announces-sponsors-of-the-inaugural-australia-ukraine-bilateral-forum-ozuke-2015/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Nov 2015 11:17:29 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ukrainians.org.au/events/afuo-announces-sponsors-of-the-inaugural-australia-ukraine-bilateral-forum-ozuke-2015/</guid>
      <description>November 5, 2015
MEDIA RELEASE AFUO ANNOUNCES SPONSORS OF THE INAUGURAL AUSTRALIA-UKRAINE BILATERAL FORUM OzUKE2015 Melbourne 25-26 November 2015 The Australian Federation of Ukrainian Organisations (AFUO) is pleased to announce our major sponsors for the OzUke 2015 Inaugural Australia Ukraine Business Forum.
The Forum is being organised by the AFUO in partnership with the newly formed Australia-Ukraine Chamber of Commerce.
Apart from the AFUO which will provide close to $20000 to the forum our **MAJOR PLATINUM SPONSOR is MIMIVIC GROUP INDUSTRIAL DEVELOPERS **Victor and Marijka Rudewych will contribute $20,000 to the Forum.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>AUSTRALIA-UKRAINE BILATERAL RELATIONS FORUM “OzUke2015”</title>
      <link>https://ukrainians.org.au/finance/australia-ukraine-bilateral-relations-forum-ozuke2015/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Oct 2015 04:57:38 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ukrainians.org.au/finance/australia-ukraine-bilateral-relations-forum-ozuke2015/</guid>
      <description>October 8, 2015
AUSTRALIA-UKRAINE BILATERAL RELATIONS FORUM “OzUke2015”
Australia-Ukraine bilateral relations forum “OzUke2015” will be one of the most important events in the Australian –Ukrainian community in the last 25 years. The Forum will be held in Melbourne on 25 - 26 November 2015 at Rydges on Swanston, 701 Swanston Street, Melbourne.
It will build bilateral cooperation between Ukraine and Australia.
The Australia-Ukraine Chamber of Commerce (AUCC) was initiated by the Australian Federation of Ukrainian Organisations (AFUO) and is now a formally incorporated Association.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>OzUke-2015: АВСТРАЛІЯ - УКРАЇНА</title>
      <link>https://ukrainians.org.au/politics/ozuke-2015-avstraliya-ukrayina/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Oct 2015 11:44:53 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ukrainians.org.au/politics/ozuke-2015-avstraliya-ukrayina/</guid>
      <description>Богдан Рудницький веде розмову із Головою Управи Союзу Українських Організацій Австралії ( СУОА) п. Стефаном Романівим. Мова йде про майбутній австралійсько-український форум з питань підприємництва і співпраці (Melbourne at the Rydges on Swanston on Wednesday, November 25 and Thursday, November 26, 2015 and in Kyiv in May 2016). Також СУОА від імені українців Австралії вітає новопризначеного В-ш Посла України в Австралії Високодостойного п. Миколу Кулінича. Йде розмова і про ситуацію в Україні та допомогу воюючим сестрам і братам на рідних землях&amp;hellip;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>OzUke2015 - inaugural Australia-Ukraine bilateral relations forum - November 25 &amp; 26 - Melbourne, Victoria</title>
      <link>https://ukrainians.org.au/events/ozuke2015-inaugural-australia-ukraine-bilateral-relations-forum-november-25-26-melbourne-victoria/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Sep 2015 12:13:56 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ukrainians.org.au/events/ozuke2015-inaugural-australia-ukraine-bilateral-relations-forum-november-25-26-melbourne-victoria/</guid>
      <description>The AFUO today announces that OzUke2015 - the inaugural Australia-Ukraine bilateral relations forum - will take place on November 25 and 26 at the Rydges on Swanston in Melbourne, Victoria.
OzUke2015 is a collaboration between the AFUO and Centre UA, a leading pro-democracy NGO based in Kyiv. It also has the strong cooperation of the Australia-Ukraine Chamber of Commerce, and the support of both the Australian and Ukrainian Governments.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Подяка від &#34;Захисту Патріотів&#34;</title>
      <link>https://ukrainians.org.au/community/patriot-defence-podiaka/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Jul 2015 07:04:12 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ukrainians.org.au/community/patriot-defence-podiaka/</guid>
      <description>Світовий Конґрес Українців
Гуманітарна ініціатива &amp;ldquo;Захист Патріотів&amp;rdquo;
_висловлює подяку _
окремим особам та українським організаціям Австралії
За сприяння у розвитку тактичної медицини в Україні шляхом підготовки військовослужбовців, що захищають територіальну цілісність й недоторканність України та забезпечення індивідуальними аптечками-IFAK за стандартами НАТО для збереження їх життів.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>EABC Business Roundtable with Petro Poroshenko - PHOTO GALLERY</title>
      <link>https://ukrainians.org.au/events/international-events/eabc-business-roundtable-with-petro-poroshenko/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Dec 2014 10:17:48 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ukrainians.org.au/events/international-events/eabc-business-roundtable-with-petro-poroshenko/</guid>
      <description>PHOTO GALLERY EABC Business Roundtable with His Excellency Mr Petro Poroshenko, President of Ukraine 12 December 2014, Sydney
On Friday 12 December the Council was honoured to host a Business Roundtable in partnership with Thales Australia on the occasion of the visit of HE Mr Petro Poroshenko, President of Ukraine.
The Council very much appreciates this opportunity and hope there are opportunities to follow this up with a visit to Ukraine in the future.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Karpaty Foundation Media Release</title>
      <link>https://ukrainians.org.au/community/karpaty-foundation-media-release/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Mar 2014 06:43:50 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ukrainians.org.au/community/karpaty-foundation-media-release/</guid>
      <description>SCU and the Karpaty Foundation provide grants to individuals and organisations and individual scholarships for the purpose of building a fair, just, creative and caring society - particularly in relation to the Ukrainian community in Australia and in Ukraine by:
 * Enriching individual and civic life * Improving the lives of people impoverished from social or cultural disadvantage * Strengthening democratic values and participation * Promoting creativity, innovation, tolerance, and the fulfilment of potential for the betterment and improvement of community values in society, with a focus on: * Education &amp;amp; Scholarship * Arts &amp;amp; Humanity * Welfare &amp;amp; Wellbeing * Sustainability and Environment * Heritage &amp;amp; Society * Special Projects (such as Leadership in Society) as may be determined from time to time.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Збірка на Майдан</title>
      <link>https://ukrainians.org.au/community/maidan-donations/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Feb 2014 00:11:12 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ukrainians.org.au/community/maidan-donations/</guid>
      <description>**[ ](http://www.ozeukes.com/wp-content/uploads/2014/02/Kyiv-Maidan1.jpg)Збірка на Майдан**
На Майдані потрібно тепер допомогу. В грудні 2013р. управа CУОA проголосила збірку на Потреби Майдану.
Всі пожертви пересилати на:
Dnister Account AFUO
 **Закликаємо Вас не пересилати гроші на приватні адреси в Україні **
** **
Maidan Fund The Maidan needs your help.
In December 2013 the AFUO committee announced a collection for the Needs of the Maidan.
Please send your donations to:
Dnister Account AFUO</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Karpaty Foundation – latest update on grants allocated</title>
      <link>https://ukrainians.org.au/community/karpaty-foundation-latest-update-on-grants-allocated-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Jan 2014 04:04:51 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ukrainians.org.au/community/karpaty-foundation-latest-update-on-grants-allocated-2/</guid>
      <description>The Karpaty Foundation has issued a press release in which it summarises recent grants made to members of the Ukrainian community.
Press Release: The Karpaty Foundation PRelease 29January2014</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Жовтень - Місяць CУОA</title>
      <link>https://ukrainians.org.au/community/october-afuo-month/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 29 Sep 2012 04:36:52 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ukrainians.org.au/community/october-afuo-month/</guid>
      <description>Управа Cоюзу Українських Організацій Aвстралій (CУОA) проголошує жовтень яко «Місяцем CУОA».
**_ _**Управа СУОА закликає українські організації, установи та українців Aвстралії зложити свою пожетрву на потреби CУОA, щоб можна було далі провадити працю CУОA. Кожна пожертва важна, а з нею засвідчуєте свою підтримку для нашої громадської централі в Aвстралії.
Ця збірка була затверджена в бюджеті CУОA на Зїзді CУОA в липні 2012.
Подається повний заклик СУОА: OCTOBER ZAKLYK edit</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Karpaty Foundation Press Release</title>
      <link>https://ukrainians.org.au/education/karpaty-foundation-press-release-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Jul 2012 00:26:23 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ukrainians.org.au/education/karpaty-foundation-press-release-2/</guid>
      <description>The Board &amp;amp; Trustees of The Karpaty Foundation recently held a meeting to review applications for grants. Their press release provides details. The Karpaty Foundation PRelease July 2012</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ukrainian Foundations and Institutions Offering Grants or Sponsorships</title>
      <link>https://ukrainians.org.au/culture/ukrainian-foundations-institutions-offering-grants-or-sponsorships/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 17 Dec 2011 04:33:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ukrainians.org.au/culture/ukrainian-foundations-institutions-offering-grants-or-sponsorships/</guid>
      <description>There are a small number of Ukrainian Foundations and Institutions in Australia who offer grants to organisations and individuals for various purposes, generally related to improving knowledge or awareness of things Ukrainian. To assist potential applicants in being aware of which such Foundations / Institutions currently exist and to whom they may apply for a grant/sponsorship, please refer to the list below.
 В Австралії є декілька українських фундацій і установ які дарують дотації та стипендії організаціям і одиницям на різні потреби, переважно пов&amp;rsquo;язані з удосконаленням українознавства.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>