<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Fake news on AFUO - СУОА</title>
    <link>https://ukrainians.org.au/tags/fake-news/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Fake news on AFUO - СУОА</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-au</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 06 Jan 2019 02:09:35 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://ukrainians.org.au/tags/fake-news/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Australians not fooled by Russia’s scandalous propaganda</title>
      <link>https://ukrainians.org.au/current-affairs/australia-not-fooled-propaganda/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Jan 2019 02:09:35 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ukrainians.org.au/current-affairs/australia-not-fooled-propaganda/</guid>
      <description>Despite most of the international community criticising Russia for its aggression in Ukraine and for flaunting international conventions, the country’s embassy in Canberra has paid for an advertisement in which it condemns Australia for contributing to “Russophobia”.____
In the advertisement, published in The Canberra Times, it also blames Russia’s critics for not accepting Russian foreign policy and dismisses as absurd claims Russia had any involvement in the downing of Malaysia Airlines flight MH17 and the almost fatal nerve agent poisoning of British-based former double agent Sergei Skripal and his daughter.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Canberra Times Publishes AFUO Protest to Russian Ambassador&#39;s Paid Ad.</title>
      <link>https://ukrainians.org.au/current-affairs/canberra-times-publishes-afuo-protest-to-russian-ambassadors-paid-ad/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Dec 2018 05:38:55 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ukrainians.org.au/current-affairs/canberra-times-publishes-afuo-protest-to-russian-ambassadors-paid-ad/</guid>
      <description>Unacceptable ad
At a time when Australia and the international community has joined in condemning the seizure of Ukrainian naval personnel and their vessels and reaffirmed world support for Ukraine&amp;rsquo;s sovereignty and integrity, it is unacceptable for an Australian newspaper to carry a paid advertisement from Russia defending what are currently disputed war crimes (The Canberra Times, December 21, p15).
The advertisement mocks the international findings that a Russian missile downed Malaysia Airlines flight MH17, killing 298 innocent souls including 38 Australians.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Statement on misrepresentation and Fake News of AUC</title>
      <link>https://ukrainians.org.au/community/statement-on-misrepresentation-and-fake-news-of-auc/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Dec 2018 09:53:37 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ukrainians.org.au/community/statement-on-misrepresentation-and-fake-news-of-auc/</guid>
      <description>As you may be aware there is a Facebook page of an unregistered person / structure calling itself the Australian Ukrainian Congress (AUC). A person associated with its postings is a failed Victorian politician named Andrew Olexander. Many of the posts are vile and full of vitriol. – with regular four-letter obscenities being posted.
The Australian Federation of Ukrainian Organisations (AFUO) has avoided directly responding to the many false and unsubstantiated posts.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>