<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Crimea on AFUO - СУОА</title>
    <link>https://ozeukes.com/tags/crimea/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Crimea on AFUO - СУОА</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 10 Mar 2016 21:51:35 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://ozeukes.com/tags/crimea/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>AFUO CALL TO ACTION - CRIMEA BELONGS TO UKRAINE</title>
      <link>https://ozeukes.com/politics/afuo-call-to-action-crimea-belongs-to-ukraine/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Mar 2016 21:51:35 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ozeukes.com/politics/afuo-call-to-action-crimea-belongs-to-ukraine/</guid>
      <description>AFUO CALL TO ACTION WRITE, RING, VISIT YOUR FEDERAL MEMBER OF PARLIAMENT OVER THE NEXT WEEK CRIMEA BELONGS TO UKRAINE
The internationally recognised Ukrainian territory of Crimea was annexed by the Russian Federation on 18 March 2014.
Окупація Автономної Республіки Крим та м. Севастополя Росією — збройна агресія Росії спрямована на насильницьке протиправне відторгнення Кримської автономії та Севастополя від України та їх приєднання до Російської Федерації на правах суб&#39;єктів Російської Федерації, що було здійснено протягом березня 2014 року.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Enough is enough, return Crimea to Ukraine</title>
      <link>https://ozeukes.com/politics/enough-is-enough-return-crimea-to-ukraine/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Mar 2016 21:44:17 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ozeukes.com/politics/enough-is-enough-return-crimea-to-ukraine/</guid>
      <description>**March 11, 2016 **
MEDIA RELEASE Peak Ukrainian body of Australia says enough is enough, return Crimea to Ukraine**_ _**
18 March 2016 will mark two years of Russian occupation in Crimea. The Australian Federation of Ukrainian Organisations (AFUO) urges the Australian government and the international community to uphold sanctions against the Russian Federation until it withdraws from Crimea and east Ukraine.
The Ukrainian peninsula was seized by the Russian Federation in March 2014.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>