<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Dr Ulana Suprun on AFUO - СУОА</title>
    <link>https://ozeukes.com/tags/dr-ulana-suprun/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Dr Ulana Suprun on AFUO - СУОА</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 07 Feb 2019 08:43:08 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://ozeukes.com/tags/dr-ulana-suprun/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Show your support for Dr Suprun</title>
      <link>https://ozeukes.com/current-affairs/show-your-support-for-dr-suprun/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Feb 2019 08:43:08 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ozeukes.com/current-affairs/show-your-support-for-dr-suprun/</guid>
      <description>The Administrative Court in Kyiv issued a ruling endeavouring to ban Ukraine&#39;s acting health minister Dr. Ulana Suprun from performing her Ministerial functions.
This is an outrageous and politically motivated act - against an individual who has done nothing but positive actions for Ukraine&#39;s reforms in Health care. See our letter to Ambassador Melissa O&#39;Rourke below.
 * A working group has been formed on the issue * This group has secured President, PM and many others to support (when up until Friday little interest) * Many Governments have taken a watchful position * We have sparked the international social media campaign and activity in a range of countries * A quick decision made after seeing support to put her up for vote in VR * A fraction headed via Andreij Levus MP have now posted on agenda for VR  You can show your support on social media for Dr Ulana Suprun by using the hashtag #SupportSuprun and sharing posts like:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dr Ulana Suprun is coming to Australia!</title>
      <link>https://ozeukes.com/community/dr-ulana-suprun-australia/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Nov 2018 22:26:46 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ozeukes.com/community/dr-ulana-suprun-australia/</guid>
      <description>Fantastic news! Dr Ulana Suprun will be in Australia this coming weekend. Public meetings will be happening in Melbourne and Sydney.
Details for Melbourne: 
Details for Sydney:</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>