<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>call to action on AFUO - СУОА</title>
    <link>https://ozeukes.com/tags/call-to-action/</link>
    <description>Recent content in call to action on AFUO - СУОА</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 29 Apr 2019 11:46:07 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://ozeukes.com/tags/call-to-action/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Westpac has responded, apology to be issued and advertising removed</title>
      <link>https://ozeukes.com/current-affairs/westpac-response-advert/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Apr 2019 11:46:07 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ozeukes.com/current-affairs/westpac-response-advert/</guid>
      <description>Following the many community complaints to Westpac about the Fraud Guarantee advertisement which referred to Ukraine, and following numerous specific conversations with Martine Jager, Chief Digital &amp;amp; Marketing Officer of Westpac group, the advertisement will be withdrawn. Ms Jager apologised on behalf of Westpac and indicated the advertisement was not meant to offend.
We will share the full written response from Westpac when it arrives.
Thank you to all who have been active and responded to our call to action in the past few days, via all the various channels including social media and email.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Call to Action: Respond to the Westpac Advertisement</title>
      <link>https://ozeukes.com/current-affairs/respond-to-westpac-ad/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 27 Apr 2019 07:52:33 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ozeukes.com/current-affairs/respond-to-westpac-ad/</guid>
      <description>The Australian Federation of Ukrainian Organisations (AFUO) calls on members of the Ukrainian community and the broader Australian community to strongly protest the Westpac advertisement in today&#39;s Melbourne Herald Sun &amp;amp; Sydney Daily Telegraph promoting their Westpac Fraud Money Back Guarantee Policy and putting the focus on UKRAINE.____
__ __Issues of fraud and misuse of credit cards is an international phenomenon. __There is no need to isolate Ukraine.
__ If it was intended as a marketing ploy - it is in bad taste and derogatory.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Закликаємо до участи в міжнародній кампанії #УкраїнаПонадУсе | Support the Campaign</title>
      <link>https://ozeukes.com/current-affairs/ukraine-above-all/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Apr 2019 06:13:22 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ozeukes.com/current-affairs/ukraine-above-all/</guid>
      <description>Закликаємо до участи в міжнародній кампанії #УкраїнаПонадУсе
Управа Союзу Українських Організацій Австралії (CYOA) закликає складових частин СУОА та українське суспільство долучитися до міжнародної кампанії #УкраїнаПонадУсе
Кампанія - Просимо перечитати долучений інструктаж – та приступити до акції по соціяльних мережах та в пресі . Хто як не ми ?
Управа СУОА повiдомляє що слідуючій члени нашої спільноти в Австралії -
Софія Матіяш – ПА
Михайло Лаба – Вікторія
Денис Козак - Канберра</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>