<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Ukraine on AFUO - СУОА</title>
    <link>https://ukrainians.org.au/tags/ukraine/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Ukraine on AFUO - СУОА</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-au</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 03 Oct 2019 03:15:51 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://ukrainians.org.au/tags/ukraine/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Media Release: NO DISCUSSIONS ABOUT UKRAINE WITHOUT UKRAINE  President Zelensky must not agree to Russian demands</title>
      <link>https://ukrainians.org.au/current-affairs/zelensky-not-agree-russia-demands/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 03 Oct 2019 03:15:51 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ukrainians.org.au/current-affairs/zelensky-not-agree-russia-demands/</guid>
      <description>This causes unnecessary tension in civil society . International partners and stakeholders are also calling for answers.
The Australian Federation of Ukrainian Organisations,( the peak body for Ukrainians in Australia ) joins with the Ukrainian World Congress (UWC) in asking for clarity and transparency from the government of Ukraine regarding any agreement to hold elections in areas of Ukraine currently occupied by Russia.
The AFUO reaffirms that Ukraine must never agree to Russian demands regarding Ukrainian elections, or Ukraine’s constitutionally mandated strategic course of NATO and EU integration.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Show your support for Dr Suprun</title>
      <link>https://ukrainians.org.au/current-affairs/show-your-support-for-dr-suprun/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Feb 2019 08:43:08 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ukrainians.org.au/current-affairs/show-your-support-for-dr-suprun/</guid>
      <description>The Administrative Court in Kyiv issued a ruling endeavouring to ban Ukraine&amp;rsquo;s acting health minister Dr. Ulana Suprun from performing her Ministerial functions.
This is an outrageous and politically motivated act - against an individual who has done nothing but positive actions for Ukraine&amp;rsquo;s reforms in Health care. See our letter to Ambassador Melissa O&amp;rsquo;Rourke below.
 * A working group has been formed on the issue * This group has secured President, PM and many others to support (when up until Friday little interest) * Many Governments have taken a watchful position * We have sparked the international social media campaign and activity in a range of countries * A quick decision made after seeing support to put her up for vote in VR * A fraction headed via Andreij Levus MP have now posted on agenda for VR  You can show your support on social media for Dr Ulana Suprun by using the hashtag #SupportSuprun and sharing posts like:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Союз Українських Організацій Австралії (СУОА) вітає Митрополита Епіфанія Київського та всієї України</title>
      <link>https://ukrainians.org.au/community/afuocyoa-ukrainian-orthodox-church/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Dec 2018 22:53:51 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ukrainians.org.au/community/afuocyoa-ukrainian-orthodox-church/</guid>
      <description>Величний Історичний День у Літописі України
Об’єднавчий Собор Української Православної Церкви
обрав Митрополита Епіфанія
Главою Української Автокефальної Православної Церкви
Управа Союз Українських Організацій Австралії (СУОА) вітає Об’єднавчий Собор та всіх учасників трьох конфесій Української Православної Церкви – представників УПЦ КП, УАПЦ та кількох представників УПЦ МП, які заснували об’єднану українську православну церкву, визнану світовим православ’ям!
Вітаємо український народ з небуденною історичною подією як день остаточного здобуття Незалежності України від Москви !</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Australia’s Ukrainian community calls for International Condemnation of Russia  after latest attacks on Ukraine</title>
      <link>https://ukrainians.org.au/current-affairs/international-condemnation-for-ru/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Nov 2018 09:54:35 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ukrainians.org.au/current-affairs/international-condemnation-for-ru/</guid>
      <description>On November 25, 2018, Ukrainian Naval vessels were attacked by Russian forces as they were departing from the area of the Kerch Strait and moving back into the Black Sea. Ukrainian President Petro Poroshenko has announced that &amp;ldquo;Russian special forces have taken over some [Ukrainian] ships.&amp;rdquo; Over a half-dozen Ukrainian service members have been injured, and up to 20 are being held captive by Russian forces.
This was a premeditated and deliberate act of aggression against Ukraine by Russia.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Greetings from Ukraine!</title>
      <link>https://ukrainians.org.au/community/video-greeting-ukraine/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Oct 2018 00:14:26 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ukrainians.org.au/community/video-greeting-ukraine/</guid>
      <description>Вітаємо нашу козацьку збірну з перемогами на «Іграх Нескорених» у Сіднеї!
Українці єднаються у своїй підтримці наших нескорених бійців на шляху до перемог.
Дякуємо за відео-привітання з Києва до всіх українців Австралії,
які підготовлені нашими друзями з України:
NGO «Аustralian-Ukrainian Initiative» (Геннадій Кравець) та
українська меблева компанія MERX INTERIO (Вадим Григор&amp;rsquo;єв, Іван Філіпович).
Congratulations to Ukrainian team with victories at Sydney&amp;rsquo;s Invictus Games!
Ukrainians will unite in their support of our fighters on the path to victory.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Holodomor Commemoration Service in Sydney</title>
      <link>https://ukrainians.org.au/events/new-south-wales/holodomor-commemoration-service-in-sydney/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Sep 2018 01:59:59 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ukrainians.org.au/events/new-south-wales/holodomor-commemoration-service-in-sydney/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Help Ukraine&#39;s Veterans &amp; their families through Tax Deductible Donations</title>
      <link>https://ukrainians.org.au/community/ukraine-crisis-appeal/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Jun 2018 12:55:57 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ukrainians.org.au/community/ukraine-crisis-appeal/</guid>
      <description>The Australian Federation of Ukrainian Organisations (AFUO) is proud to announce the launch of the Ukraine Crisis Appeal. This is a collaboration between AFUO, Rotary Australia World Community Service (RAWCS) and Caritas Ukraine. The fund is the only with tax-deductible status in Australia that allows aid to be directed to Ukraine.
The aid programs help address the following for Veterans and their families:
 *  psychological and psycho social support</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Public Lecture: &#34;Crisis Helpline Service in Ukraine&#34;</title>
      <link>https://ukrainians.org.au/events/public-lecture-crisis-helpline-service-in-ukraine/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 Sep 2017 13:30:55 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ukrainians.org.au/events/public-lecture-crisis-helpline-service-in-ukraine/</guid>
      <description>A fantastic opportunity to hear from Executive Director of Lifeline, Alan Woodward. Thanks to the help of AFUO, Alan travelled to Ukraine to evaluate the possibility of establishing the organisation Lifeline.
**A synopsis of the lecture: **
There are estimated to be more than 1,000 crisis helpline services
worldwide. They include telephone and other technology channels for
delivery such as online chat, text and messaging and email.
As Ukraine strengthens and reforms its service system for mental health</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>