<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Media Release on AFUO - СУОА</title>
    <link>https://ukrainians.org.au/tags/media-release/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Media Release on AFUO - СУОА</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-au</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 03 Oct 2019 03:15:51 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://ukrainians.org.au/tags/media-release/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Media Release: NO DISCUSSIONS ABOUT UKRAINE WITHOUT UKRAINE  President Zelensky must not agree to Russian demands</title>
      <link>https://ukrainians.org.au/current-affairs/zelensky-not-agree-russia-demands/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 03 Oct 2019 03:15:51 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ukrainians.org.au/current-affairs/zelensky-not-agree-russia-demands/</guid>
      <description>This causes unnecessary tension in civil society . International partners and stakeholders are also calling for answers.
The Australian Federation of Ukrainian Organisations,( the peak body for Ukrainians in Australia ) joins with the Ukrainian World Congress (UWC) in asking for clarity and transparency from the government of Ukraine regarding any agreement to hold elections in areas of Ukraine currently occupied by Russia.
The AFUO reaffirms that Ukraine must never agree to Russian demands regarding Ukrainian elections, or Ukraine’s constitutionally mandated strategic course of NATO and EU integration.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Media Release: Putin commits another act of aggression against Ukraine</title>
      <link>https://ukrainians.org.au/current-affairs/russian-aggression-continues-2019/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Apr 2019 01:21:41 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ukrainians.org.au/current-affairs/russian-aggression-continues-2019/</guid>
      <description>__
MEDIA RELEASE
Russian President Vladimir Putin has once again committed an act of aggression against Ukraine by signing a decree setting out which groups of people are, for humanitarian reasons, entitled to apply for Russian citizenship through a simplified procedure in the Ukrainian regions of Donetsk and Luhansk currently under occupation by the Russian Army.____
According to the decree, the Russian president made the decision &amp;ldquo;in order to protect human and citizen rights and freedoms&amp;rdquo; based on &amp;ldquo;commonly recognised principles and norms of international law&amp;rdquo; in accordance with the Russian Law on citizenship from May 31, 2002.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Australia’s Ukrainian community calls for International Condemnation of Russia  after latest attacks on Ukraine</title>
      <link>https://ukrainians.org.au/current-affairs/international-condemnation-for-ru/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Nov 2018 09:54:35 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ukrainians.org.au/current-affairs/international-condemnation-for-ru/</guid>
      <description>On November 25, 2018, Ukrainian Naval vessels were attacked by Russian forces as they were departing from the area of the Kerch Strait and moving back into the Black Sea. Ukrainian President Petro Poroshenko has announced that &amp;ldquo;Russian special forces have taken over some [Ukrainian] ships.&amp;rdquo; Over a half-dozen Ukrainian service members have been injured, and up to 20 are being held captive by Russian forces.
This was a premeditated and deliberate act of aggression against Ukraine by Russia.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ukraine&#39;s Veterans receive major support from Cabramatta-Fairfield</title>
      <link>https://ukrainians.org.au/community/cabramatta-fairfield-supports-ukraine/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Oct 2018 05:41:20 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ukrainians.org.au/community/cabramatta-fairfield-supports-ukraine/</guid>
      <description>Ukrainian Association of Cabramatta / Fairfield in NSW has shown strong community leadership and excellence by becoming a Gold Patron ($5000) of the Ukraine Crisis Appeal. The Association has also offered to sponsor the Featherdale event for Team Ukraine &amp;amp; Family &amp;amp; Friends to the value of nearly $3000.00.
The Australian Federation of Ukrainian Organisations (AFUO) Ukraine Crisis Appeal will use funds raised to support rehabilitation of ATO Veterans and their families.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>