<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>General on AFUO - СУОА</title>
    <link>https://ozeukes.com/categories/general/</link>
    <description>Recent content in General on AFUO - СУОА</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 13 Jul 2018 10:46:22 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://ozeukes.com/categories/general/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Less than 100 days until the Invictus Games in Sydney!</title>
      <link>https://ozeukes.com/sport/less-than-100-days-until-the-invictus-games-in-sydney/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Jul 2018 10:46:22 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ozeukes.com/sport/less-than-100-days-until-the-invictus-games-in-sydney/</guid>
      <description>It is less than 100 days until the Invictus Games in Sydney! Read more from the official Invictus announcement here.
The Invictus Games is an international multi-sport event, in which wounded, injured or sick armed services personnel and veterans take part in sports competitions including wheelchair basketball, sitting volleyball, and indoor rowing. This year they are being held in Sydney from October 20-27th.
A team from Ukraine will be participating, meet them below.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Help Ukraine&#39;s Veterans &amp; their families through Tax Deductible Donations</title>
      <link>https://ozeukes.com/community/ukraine-crisis-appeal/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Jun 2018 12:55:57 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ozeukes.com/community/ukraine-crisis-appeal/</guid>
      <description>The Australian Federation of Ukrainian Organisations (AFUO) is proud to announce the launch of the Ukraine Crisis Appeal. This is a collaboration between AFUO, Rotary Australia World Community Service (RAWCS) and Caritas Ukraine. The fund is the only with tax-deductible status in Australia that allows aid to be directed to Ukraine.
The aid programs help address the following for Veterans and their families:
 *  psychological and psycho social support</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Христос  Воскрес! | Easter Greetings from AFUO</title>
      <link>https://ozeukes.com/community/%d1%85%d1%80%d0%b8%d1%81%d1%82%d0%be%d1%81-%d0%b2%d0%be%d1%81%d0%ba%d1%80%d0%b5%d1%81-easter-greetings/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 07 Apr 2018 02:23:15 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ozeukes.com/community/%d1%85%d1%80%d0%b8%d1%81%d1%82%d0%be%d1%81-%d0%b2%d0%be%d1%81%d0%ba%d1%80%d0%b5%d1%81-easter-greetings/</guid>
      <description>**Дорогі Друзі ! **
Управа Союзу Українських Організацій Австралії (CYOA) вітає Вас з Великим Святом Воскресіння Христового !
Нехай святковий настрій, що дарує Світле Воскресіння, наповнить Ваші серця почуттями радості, надії і любові.
Нехай Всевишній дарує Вам та Вашим родинам міцне здоров’я, благополуччя та сили і наснагу для справ
на добробут і процвітання української спільноти в Австралії та для добра України .
Нехай Всевишній дарує мир Україні .
Христос Воскрес !</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Різдвяне привітання проводу ОУН(б)</title>
      <link>https://ozeukes.com/politics/rizdviane-vitanya-provid-oun/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 Dec 2017 10:43:03 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ozeukes.com/politics/rizdviane-vitanya-provid-oun/</guid>
      <description>Вельмишановні подруги i друзі
Ось і відходить у минуле ще один рік, сповнений для України надій і тривог. Ось і сходить над Україною ще одна Різдвяна зірка, сповіщаючи віру, надію і любов.
Різдво цього року запам’ятається всім нам як час, коли, подібно до Різдвяної зірки, сама Україна прагне засяяти для світу новими, незвіданими барвами. Сила України відвертає від неї важкі лиха і відкриває двері до нового майбутнього. Те внутрішнє світло, яке завжди було в нашому народові, освітлює його справжнє обличчя — молоде, прекрасне, чесне.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Вітання з Різдвом Христовим</title>
      <link>https://ozeukes.com/general/merry-christmas-happy-new-year-2017/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Jan 2017 07:00:03 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ozeukes.com/general/merry-christmas-happy-new-year-2017/</guid>
      <description>Дорогі Українці!
Союз Українських Організацій Австралії (СУОА) вітає Вас з Новим 2017 роком та Святом Різдва Христового!
Нехай Вифлеємська Зірка, яка засяє напередодні Великого Свята Різдва Христового та сповістить про народження Сина Божого, принесе в кожну українську родину радість, щастя і здоров’я!
Нехай Господь дарує мир і добробут Україні та зберігає життя українських воїнів, добровольців-патріотів!
Христос Раждається! Славімо Його!
Слава Україні!
We wish all those who are celebrating a very Merry Christmas and a Happy New Year!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>CYOA Registered with &#34;Our Community&#34;</title>
      <link>https://ozeukes.com/community/cyoa-registered-with-our-community/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Sep 2016 12:39:16 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ozeukes.com/community/cyoa-registered-with-our-community/</guid>
      <description>14-го вересня 2016
CYOA Registered with Our Community - CYOA member organisations registered for FUNDING INFORMATION
Управа СУОА зареєструвалася в організації Our Cоmmunity www.ourcommunity.com.au
Ця структура допомагає організаціям які визнані як Non for Profit, подаючи інформацію про різні заходи, форуми, курси ітп, щоб покращити ефективність праці.
Управа СУОА також оплатила входову дотацію та зареєструвалася для додаткових прислуг в сфері ґрантів.
Зареєструвано 10 точок в спільноті - включаючи адрес Стейтових громад, молодечих організацій, шкільництво, жіночі організації.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Світовий Конґрес Українців запрошує громаду долучитися до оновлення архіву</title>
      <link>https://ozeukes.com/community/ukrainian-world-congress-invites-community-to-contribute-to-archives/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 May 2016 07:21:28 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ozeukes.com/community/ukrainian-world-congress-invites-community-to-contribute-to-archives/</guid>
      <description>20 квітня 2016 р.
ЗАКЛИК ДО ГРОМАДИ
Світовий Конґрес Українців запрошує громаду долучитися до оновлення архіву
Світовий Конґрес Українців (СКУ) відзначає своє 50-річчя у 2017 р. серією ювілейних заходів з метою залучити українців і неукраїнців діаспори та України до святкування цієї надзвичайної події.
У рамках підготовки до цього свята ми оновлюємо архіви СКУ, щоб забезпечити належним чином збереження задокументованих історичних матеріалів СКУ для майбутніх поколінь.
З цього приводу ми звертаємося до громади з проханням.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Melbourne Malanka 2016</title>
      <link>https://ozeukes.com/events/melbourne-malanka-2016/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 03 Dec 2015 10:44:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ozeukes.com/events/melbourne-malanka-2016/</guid>
      <description>Association of Ukrainians in Victoria Invite you to celebrate
Melbourne Malanka 2016 Friday January 15th, 2016 Ukrainian Hall, 3-11 Russell St Essendon Starts 6:30pm - Till late $60 per person 3 Course meal Complimentary glass of wine / champagne on arrival Featuring Mad House &amp;amp; Ukrainian Musicians from Folknery Drinks at Bar Prices - Strictly No BYO Dress – Formal bookings: akobas@auv.org.au ANDRIANA Kobas 0421 911 458</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ukrainian Collectibles Society postcard - Australia for a united Ukraine</title>
      <link>https://ozeukes.com/general/ukrainian-collectibles-society-postcard-australia-for-a-united-ukraine/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Dec 2014 10:57:17 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ozeukes.com/general/ukrainian-collectibles-society-postcard-australia-for-a-united-ukraine/</guid>
      <description>**Australia for a united Ukraine[ ](http://www.ozeukes.com/wp-content/uploads/2014/12/Australia.jpg)**
Postcard Series Issue No. 1 Issue date: 20 December 2014
**UCS postcard Series ** **Introduction ** The purpose of the project is to commemorate and highlight significant contemporary and historical events relating to Ukraine, its people and its place in the pantheon of world history. For this first issue – Australia for a united Ukraine – all proceeds will be sent together with any other donations to NGOs in Ukraine that support the ongoing struggle against terrorists.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Australian Presentation and Launch of the book &#34;Holodomor. The Great Famine in Ukraine 1932-1933&#34;  and the book series “Poland and Ukraine in the 1930s and 1940s” </title>
      <link>https://ozeukes.com/events/victoria/australian-presentation-and-launch-of-the-book-holodomor-the-great-famine-in-ukraine-1932-1933-and-the-book-series-%e2%80%9cpoland-and-ukraine-in-the-1930s-and-1940s%e2%80%9d/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 31 Oct 2011 02:48:27 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ozeukes.com/events/victoria/australian-presentation-and-launch-of-the-book-holodomor-the-great-famine-in-ukraine-1932-1933-and-the-book-series-%e2%80%9cpoland-and-ukraine-in-the-1930s-and-1940s%e2%80%9d/</guid>
      <description>Monash European and EU Centre
Mykola Zerov Centre for Ukrainian Studies, Monash University
Professor Iurii Shapoval (National Academy of Sciences of Ukraine) Members of the Institute of National Remembrance, Poland
**Holodomor. The Great Famine in Ukraine 1932-1933 **
**and the book series “Poland and Ukraine in the 1930s and 1940s”**Time: Thursday 10 November 2011, 6.30pm for 7.00pm
(refreshments from 6.30pm, proceedings 7.00-approx. 8.00pm)
Place: Lecture Theatre HB32, Building H, Monash University Caulfield Campus</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>