<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>South Australia on AFUO - СУОА</title>
    <link>https://ozeukes.com/categories/south-australia/</link>
    <description>Recent content in South Australia on AFUO - СУОА</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 30 Jul 2017 22:00:04 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://ozeukes.com/categories/south-australia/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>AFUO welcomes the President of the UWC Eugen Czolij and his wife Hania to Australia</title>
      <link>https://ozeukes.com/events/afuo-welcomes-the-president-of-the-uwc-eugen-czolij-and-his-wife-hania-to-australia/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 30 Jul 2017 22:00:04 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ozeukes.com/events/afuo-welcomes-the-president-of-the-uwc-eugen-czolij-and-his-wife-hania-to-australia/</guid>
      <description>Управа СУОА вітає Президента Світого Конґресу Українців з дружиною – Ганею до Австралії The Australian Federation of Ukrainian Organisations welcomes the President of the Ukrainian World Congress Eugen Czolij and his wife Hania to Australia Програма Зустрічей з Президентом СКУ у Всіх штатах Австралії:
Schedule of meetings:
Перт
Середа 2-го серпня 2017 год 7.00 веч
Wednesday 2 August 7pm Maylands Sport &amp;amp; Rec Club, 50 Clarkson Rd, Maylands 6051</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Shevchenko concert and visual presentation - South Australia</title>
      <link>https://ozeukes.com/events/shevchenko-concert-and-visual-presentation-sa/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Mar 2017 07:07:21 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ozeukes.com/events/shevchenko-concert-and-visual-presentation-sa/</guid>
      <description>The Shevchenko concert-cabaret held on Sunday 12 March was a great success. About 250 people attended this event. Attending our concert were Peter Malinauskas MLC, David Pisoni MP, Michael Atkinson MP, Jennifer Rankine MP, Hon. Grace Portolesi, Angela Evans - Mayor of the City of Charles Sturt, and the presidents of the Belarus, Croatian, German, Hungarian, Latvian, Lithuanian, Scottish and Spanish associations. Very positive comments were made by all and especially the Croatian, German, Lithuanian and Scottish presidents.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Yevshan - Winners – National Dance KAR Dance Competition 2016</title>
      <link>https://ozeukes.com/events/yevshan-winners-national-dance-kar-dance-competition-2016/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Nov 2016 06:24:26 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ozeukes.com/events/yevshan-winners-national-dance-kar-dance-competition-2016/</guid>
      <description>On 29 October 2016, two of Yevshan dance ensemble groups participated in a National Dance KAR competition, winning 8 awards and “All Stars” Title – see photos below – and received an invitation to attend the New York City Dance Experience in July 2017. The competition was held in Michael Murray Performing Arts Centre at Westminster School. The judges were from New York, Los Angeles and Sydney.
Competing in the National Dance KAR competition were professional dance companies such as SA Performing Arts, Xcel Dance studios, Pivotal Dance, Precizion Dance, TIDC Performing Arts Studio and Thats Dancing and more.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ДахаБраха в Аделайді</title>
      <link>https://ozeukes.com/events/south-australia/dakha-brakha-in-adelaide/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Mar 2016 09:26:03 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ozeukes.com/events/south-australia/dakha-brakha-in-adelaide/</guid>
      <description>_Давид Кваснюк, учень 12-го класу Української школи, Аделайда._
WOMADelaide – престижний музичний фестиваль, який щороку приводить в наше місто музикантів з усього світу. Фестиваль проходить в Ботанічному парку і завжди збирає велику авдиторію людей, які люблять музику.
Цього року я вперше був на цьому фестивалі. Фестиваль мав на мене дуже добрий вплив. Мені сподобалася невимушена, весела, відпочинкова атмосфера. Люди слухали музику, говорили, знайомилися, мали пікнік. І хоч надворі було сонячно і досить не по весняному гарячо, парк був просто переповнений людьми.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>DAKHA BRAKHA at WOMADelaide</title>
      <link>https://ozeukes.com/events/south-australia/dakha-brakha-at-womadelaide/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Mar 2016 09:18:02 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ozeukes.com/events/south-australia/dakha-brakha-at-womadelaide/</guid>
      <description>By Roma &amp;amp; Rostyslav Becker
So much anticipation surrounded Dakha Brakha’s 2016 return to WOMADelaide after a five year hiatus. The New Zealand WOMAD 2016 artists’ page pays homage to their international breakthrough in Adelaide 2011 and “ascent in the international music scene after being discovered by Australian WOMADelaide.” So, the curious and the converts with fond memories of their 2011 appearance, gathered around the intimate Novatech Stage to see the band with the impossibly high fur hats and colourful costumes.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dakha Brakha at the 2016 Womadelaide Festival</title>
      <link>https://ozeukes.com/events/dakha-brakha-at-the-2016-womadelaide-festival/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 03 Mar 2016 06:52:03 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ozeukes.com/events/dakha-brakha-at-the-2016-womadelaide-festival/</guid>
      <description>Dakha Brakha one of Ukraine’s musical treasures is set to unleash its wild fusion of authentic village folk, punk, hip hop and tribal trance in a genre they call “ethno chaos” at the 2016 Womadelaide Festival.
Dakha Brakha first appeared at Womadelaide in 2011 to rapturous applause. Since then they have appeared at major festivals around the world including the UK Womad, Sziget and Bonaroo. Rolling Stone magazine called them, “The best breakout band of Bonaroo,” while commenting on their mournful accordion and apocalyptic cello sawing”</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>KAZKA coming soon</title>
      <link>https://ozeukes.com/events/kazka-coming-soon/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Feb 2015 20:01:45 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ozeukes.com/events/kazka-coming-soon/</guid>
      <description>Lehenda Ukrainian Dance Company is thrilled to launch the international tour of its exciting new dance production KAZKA, an original folk ballet inspired by Ukrainian fairy tales.
For further information visit www.lehenda.com.au/kazka</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Malanka 2015 in SA</title>
      <link>https://ozeukes.com/events/malanka-2015-in-sa/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Dec 2014 10:02:37 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ozeukes.com/events/malanka-2015-in-sa/</guid>
      <description>Ukrainians in South Australia are having Malanka (New Year’s Dance) on Saturday 17th January 2015 at the Ballroom Function Centre in Hindmarsh.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Danny McGinlay Learns Ukrainian</title>
      <link>https://ozeukes.com/events/danny-mcginlay-learns-ukrainian/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Dec 2014 19:09:58 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ozeukes.com/events/danny-mcginlay-learns-ukrainian/</guid>
      <description>Danny McGinlay has done a lot of things to impress girls in the past, and from next Valentines Day, in the aptly named Chapel of Love Comedy Club, he’s ready to share with Adelaide the story of his biggest relationship challenge yet.
Living up to his accolades as _‘one of the best comedians in Australia’ _(Gold FM) Danny McGinlay demonstrates, in this hit show from the Melbourne International Comedy Festival, exactly how far he will go for a chick in Kiev.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ukrainian Festival 2013 - South Australia</title>
      <link>https://ozeukes.com/events/south-australia/ukrainian-festival-2013-south-australia/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Nov 2013 02:13:11 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ozeukes.com/events/south-australia/ukrainian-festival-2013-south-australia/</guid>
      <description>The Ukrainian Women’s Association in SA and The Association of Ukrainians in SA are jointly promoting the “Ukrainian Festival 2013”. The festival will be held on Sun 1 Dec 2013, 11.30-4pm at the Ukrainian Community Centre, 66 Orsmond St, Hindmarsh, SA..</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ВШAНУВAННЯ ЖЕРТВ ГОЛОДОМОРІВ / HOLODOMOR COMMEMORATION (South Australia)</title>
      <link>https://ozeukes.com/events/south-australia/holodomor-commemoration-south-australia/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 26 Nov 2011 00:28:18 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ozeukes.com/events/south-australia/holodomor-commemoration-south-australia/</guid>
      <description>The Association of Ukrainians in South Australia Inc will mark the day of Remembrance of the tragedy of the Holodomor (Famine in Ukraine) on Saturday 26th November at the Holodomor Memorial in the grounds of St Michael’s Orthodox Church, Port Road, Croydon. Укpаїнська Гpомада Південної Австpалії вшановує пам&#39;ять жертв Голодомору в суботу 26-ого листопада 2011р перед пам&#39;ятником Голодомору при православні церкви св. Михаїла, Port Road, Croydon.
Повні дані / Full details: Holodomor 2011 SA</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Відзначення 20-ої річниці Дня Незалежности України в Аделаїді / Celebration of 20th Anniversary of Independence Day of Ukraine in Adelaide</title>
      <link>https://ozeukes.com/events/south-australia/20th-anniversary-of-independence-day-of-ukraine-in-adelaide/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Jul 2011 08:29:27 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ozeukes.com/events/south-australia/20th-anniversary-of-independence-day-of-ukraine-in-adelaide/</guid>
      <description>Відзначення 20-ої річниці Дня Незалежности України в Аделаїді
 Українська Громада Південної Австралії (УГПА) запрошує всіх на концерт з нагоди 20-ої річниці Дня Незалежности України. Концерт відбудеться в неділю 28-го серпня 2011р. в Народному Домі в Гайндмарші.
 
 Celebration of 20th Anniversary of Independence Day of Ukraine in Adelaide
The Association of Ukrainians in South Australia (AUSA) invites everyone to a concert celebrating the 20th Anniversary of Independence Day of Ukraine.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>