<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Ukraine Crisis Appeal on AFUO - СУОА</title>
    <link>https://ukrainians.org.au/tags/ukraine-crisis-appeal/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Ukraine Crisis Appeal on AFUO - СУОА</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-au</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 26 Dec 2019 10:52:20 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://ukrainians.org.au/tags/ukraine-crisis-appeal/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Ukraine Crisis Appeal: Your money at work - 1st stage report.</title>
      <link>https://ukrainians.org.au/community/crisisappeal-funding-report/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Dec 2019 10:52:20 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ukrainians.org.au/community/crisisappeal-funding-report/</guid>
      <description>The is the first stage funding report from the Ukraine Crisis Appeal committee. You can read the whole report by clicking here. This report includes detail about the Ukrainians who were helped.
_Background for the first stage of funding: _ In 2018, $128,000 AUD was raised by the fund. This enabled the Veteran Program to support 25 Veterans and their families (approximately 100 people) on the journey for a better life.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Development of OT in Ukraine is now apart of the Ukrainian Crisis Аppeal</title>
      <link>https://ukrainians.org.au/community/occupational-therapy-ukraine-crisis-appeal/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Oct 2019 04:48:52 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ukrainians.org.au/community/occupational-therapy-ukraine-crisis-appeal/</guid>
      <description>A few months ago, we introduced you to Kirrily Manning, an Australian Occupational Therapist (OT) playing a key role working to develop the OT profession in Ukraine. You can read more about her story here in English and here in Ukrainian. 
Throughout the years that Go Global, Ukraine ran at Curtin University (2009-2013) led by Kirrily, over 70 students from occupational therapy, speech therapy, physiotherapy and nutrition travelled to Ukraine.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Record donation efforts by Ukrainians in Australia for Crisis Appeal</title>
      <link>https://ukrainians.org.au/community/record-donation-crisis-appeal/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Jan 2019 02:36:54 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ukrainians.org.au/community/record-donation-crisis-appeal/</guid>
      <description>This article is also available in Ukrainian.
In partnership with Rotary Australia (RAWCS), Caritas Ukraine and the Australian Federation of Ukrainian Organisations (AFUO), the crisis fund formed to provide humanitarian aid to war-affected veterans and families, has raised $128,000. This has been a fantastic effort that has involved all State Hromadas, Churches, Youth Associations and hundreds of individual donors. It shows what a small community like ours can achieve when it unites for a cause.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>AFUO becomes Gold Patron of Invictus Games - Ukraine Crisis Appeal</title>
      <link>https://ukrainians.org.au/community/afuo-gold-patron-crisis-appeal/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Oct 2018 10:50:56 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ukrainians.org.au/community/afuo-gold-patron-crisis-appeal/</guid>
      <description>The Australian Federation of Ukrainian Organisations (AFUO) has become a GOLD PATRON of the Ukraine Crisis Appeal donating $5000 to the Appeal. The appeal is coinciding with Team Ukraine who will be participating in the Invictus Games in Sydney on October 20-28, 2018____
__ This funding is to support rehabilitation of ATO Veterans and their families. Caritas Ukraine in consultation with the AFUO will identity projects in Ukraine delivering much needed rehabilitation to our veterans who have been fighting Russian aggression in Eastern Ukraine.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ukraine&#39;s Veterans receive major support from Cabramatta-Fairfield</title>
      <link>https://ukrainians.org.au/community/cabramatta-fairfield-supports-ukraine/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Oct 2018 05:41:20 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ukrainians.org.au/community/cabramatta-fairfield-supports-ukraine/</guid>
      <description>Ukrainian Association of Cabramatta / Fairfield in NSW has shown strong community leadership and excellence by becoming a Gold Patron ($5000) of the Ukraine Crisis Appeal. The Association has also offered to sponsor the Featherdale event for Team Ukraine &amp;amp; Family &amp;amp; Friends to the value of nearly $3000.00.
The Australian Federation of Ukrainian Organisations (AFUO) Ukraine Crisis Appeal will use funds raised to support rehabilitation of ATO Veterans and their families.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Team Ukraine Meet &amp; Greet |  Зустріч з командою Україна</title>
      <link>https://ukrainians.org.au/events/team-ukraine-meet-invictus/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Sep 2018 09:53:15 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ukrainians.org.au/events/team-ukraine-meet-invictus/</guid>
      <description>В жовтні розпочнуться Ігри Нескорених в Сіднеї, де виступатимуть 15 українських військовослужбовців та ветеранів. Спілка Української Молоді в Австралії запрошує членів Української спільноти на зустріч &amp;ldquo;Meet &amp;amp; Greet&amp;rdquo;, яке відбудеться у четвер, 25 жовтня, о 6 годині вечора в Gallon Wine Bar (117 Harris St, Pyrmont, NSW), де буде можливість зустріти наших Нескорених Героїв. Квитки $65+BF від особи. **Всі кошти йдуть на “Ukraine Crisis Appeal”. Квитки можна придбати через лінк: sydinvictusgamesukraine.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>