<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Invictus Games on AFUO - СУОА</title>
    <link>https://ukrainians.org.au/tags/invictus-games/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Invictus Games on AFUO - СУОА</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-au</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 06 Jan 2019 02:36:54 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://ukrainians.org.au/tags/invictus-games/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Record donation efforts by Ukrainians in Australia for Crisis Appeal</title>
      <link>https://ukrainians.org.au/community/record-donation-crisis-appeal/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Jan 2019 02:36:54 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ukrainians.org.au/community/record-donation-crisis-appeal/</guid>
      <description>This article is also available in Ukrainian.
In partnership with Rotary Australia (RAWCS), Caritas Ukraine and the Australian Federation of Ukrainian Organisations (AFUO), the crisis fund formed to provide humanitarian aid to war-affected veterans and families, has raised $128,000. This has been a fantastic effort that has involved all State Hromadas, Churches, Youth Associations and hundreds of individual donors. It shows what a small community like ours can achieve when it unites for a cause.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Invictus Games Sydney Team Ukraine: Day One to Four Summary</title>
      <link>https://ukrainians.org.au/events/international-events/invictus-games-wrap-one/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Oct 2018 02:50:07 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ukrainians.org.au/events/international-events/invictus-games-wrap-one/</guid>
      <description>Wondering how Team Ukraine is doing? Catch up on all the Invictus Games events here, from the minute they arrived in Australia to the latest competition results.
18th OCTOBER, DAY ONE: ARRIVAL
Team Ukraine arrived early Thursday to a vibrant crowd at Sydney Airport. Zahrava Dance Ensemble performed, also giving a traditional welcome with bread and salt.

**DAY TWO: MEETING WITH LUKE FOLEY MP **Members of the team were welcomed at NSW Parliament by Luke Foley MP.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Luke Foley raises Sentsov plight and Team Ukraine in NSW Parliament</title>
      <link>https://ukrainians.org.au/politics/foley-motion-sentsov-invictus/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Oct 2018 00:06:14 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ukrainians.org.au/politics/foley-motion-sentsov-invictus/</guid>
      <description>On the 23rd of October 2018, Luke Foley MP, tabled a Private Members Statement, which raised the matter of Oleg Sentsov and welcomed Team Ukraine to Australia for the Invictus Games.
On the matter of Sentsov, Mr Foley stated: &amp;ldquo;I add my voice to the many thousands of voices around the world calling for the immediate release of Oleg Sentsov from his frozen Russian prison. In recent months many Australians of Ukrainian background from my electorate of Auburn and beyond have raised with me the plight of Oleg Sentsov.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Greetings from Ukraine!</title>
      <link>https://ukrainians.org.au/community/video-greeting-ukraine/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Oct 2018 00:14:26 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ukrainians.org.au/community/video-greeting-ukraine/</guid>
      <description>Вітаємо нашу козацьку збірну з перемогами на «Іграх Нескорених» у Сіднеї!
Українці єднаються у своїй підтримці наших нескорених бійців на шляху до перемог.
Дякуємо за відео-привітання з Києва до всіх українців Австралії,
які підготовлені нашими друзями з України:
NGO «Аustralian-Ukrainian Initiative» (Геннадій Кравець) та
українська меблева компанія MERX INTERIO (Вадим Григор&amp;rsquo;єв, Іван Філіпович).
Congratulations to Ukrainian team with victories at Sydney&amp;rsquo;s Invictus Games!
Ukrainians will unite in their support of our fighters on the path to victory.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>УКРАЇНСЬКА ГРОМАДА АВСТРАЛІЇ ВІТАЄ  НАЦІОНАЛЬНУ ЗБІРНУ КОМАНДУ -   “ІГРИ НЕСКОРЕНИХ&#34;</title>
      <link>https://ukrainians.org.au/community/ukrainian-community-welcomes-team-ukraine/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Oct 2018 09:34:35 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ukrainians.org.au/community/ukrainian-community-welcomes-team-ukraine/</guid>
      <description>**Союз Українських Організацій Австралії (СУОА ) щиросердечно **вітає учасників української національної збірної команди “ Ігри Нескорених “ та бажає високих спортивних досягнень у міжнародних змаганнях, які відбудуться у Сіднеї, 20 - 27 жовтня 2018 року.____
СУОА закликає українську спільноту підтримати учасників збірної команди – ветеранів та військовослужбовців України, що отримали поранення в зоні АТО, захищаючи свою Батьківщину.____
Адже історія кожного з них – це історія неймовірної сили волі до життя,до перемоги та піднесення міжнародного авторитету української держави.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>AFUO becomes Gold Patron of Invictus Games - Ukraine Crisis Appeal</title>
      <link>https://ukrainians.org.au/community/afuo-gold-patron-crisis-appeal/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Oct 2018 10:50:56 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ukrainians.org.au/community/afuo-gold-patron-crisis-appeal/</guid>
      <description>The Australian Federation of Ukrainian Organisations (AFUO) has become a GOLD PATRON of the Ukraine Crisis Appeal donating $5000 to the Appeal. The appeal is coinciding with Team Ukraine who will be participating in the Invictus Games in Sydney on October 20-28, 2018____
__ This funding is to support rehabilitation of ATO Veterans and their families. Caritas Ukraine in consultation with the AFUO will identity projects in Ukraine delivering much needed rehabilitation to our veterans who have been fighting Russian aggression in Eastern Ukraine.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ukraine&#39;s Veterans receive major support from Cabramatta-Fairfield</title>
      <link>https://ukrainians.org.au/community/cabramatta-fairfield-supports-ukraine/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Oct 2018 05:41:20 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ukrainians.org.au/community/cabramatta-fairfield-supports-ukraine/</guid>
      <description>Ukrainian Association of Cabramatta / Fairfield in NSW has shown strong community leadership and excellence by becoming a Gold Patron ($5000) of the Ukraine Crisis Appeal. The Association has also offered to sponsor the Featherdale event for Team Ukraine &amp;amp; Family &amp;amp; Friends to the value of nearly $3000.00.
The Australian Federation of Ukrainian Organisations (AFUO) Ukraine Crisis Appeal will use funds raised to support rehabilitation of ATO Veterans and their families.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Invictus Games | Your Guide to Team Ukraine Activities</title>
      <link>https://ukrainians.org.au/events/invictus-games-ukraine-guide/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Oct 2018 10:26:45 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ukrainians.org.au/events/invictus-games-ukraine-guide/</guid>
      <description>Invictus Games is only 2 weeks away in Sydney. There are some fantastic opportunities for you, the community, to not only see Team Ukraine compete, but also meet the team members and hear their stories. **COMMUNITY EVENTS | ** **_ Інформація українською мовою | VIEW INFORMATION IN UKRAINIAN HERE_**
TEAM UKRAINE ARRIVAL SYDNEY INTERNATIONAL AIRPORT –_ 7 am THURSDAY 18.10.2018 _
Meeting place will be in forecourt outside the arrival terminal and marked by a Ukrainian flag.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Team Ukraine Meet &amp; Greet |  Зустріч з командою Україна</title>
      <link>https://ukrainians.org.au/events/team-ukraine-meet-invictus/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Sep 2018 09:53:15 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ukrainians.org.au/events/team-ukraine-meet-invictus/</guid>
      <description>В жовтні розпочнуться Ігри Нескорених в Сіднеї, де виступатимуть 15 українських військовослужбовців та ветеранів. Спілка Української Молоді в Австралії запрошує членів Української спільноти на зустріч &amp;ldquo;Meet &amp;amp; Greet&amp;rdquo;, яке відбудеться у четвер, 25 жовтня, о 6 годині вечора в Gallon Wine Bar (117 Harris St, Pyrmont, NSW), де буде можливість зустріти наших Нескорених Героїв. Квитки $65+BF від особи. **Всі кошти йдуть на “Ukraine Crisis Appeal”. Квитки можна придбати через лінк: sydinvictusgamesukraine.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Join the Invictus Flag Presentation in Sydney!</title>
      <link>https://ukrainians.org.au/community/join-the-invictus-flag-presentation-in-sydney/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Aug 2018 11:47:40 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ukrainians.org.au/community/join-the-invictus-flag-presentation-in-sydney/</guid>
      <description>The Invictus Games is coming to Sydney in October this year. As part of festivities leading up to October, an Invictus Games Flag will be presented to the Ukrainian Community by Luke Foley MP. You can be apart of the Flag Presentation, it is happening this Saturday, August 25th in Sydney, 1.30pm at the Independence Festival. More details about the festival can be found here.
Following the presentation, there will be a community photo with Luke Foley MP, at 1.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Less than 100 days until the Invictus Games in Sydney!</title>
      <link>https://ukrainians.org.au/sport/less-than-100-days-until-the-invictus-games-in-sydney/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Jul 2018 10:46:22 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ukrainians.org.au/sport/less-than-100-days-until-the-invictus-games-in-sydney/</guid>
      <description>It is less than 100 days until the Invictus Games in Sydney! Read more from the official Invictus announcement here.
The Invictus Games is an international multi-sport event, in which wounded, injured or sick armed services personnel and veterans take part in sports competitions including wheelchair basketball, sitting volleyball, and indoor rowing. This year they are being held in Sydney from October 20-27th.
A team from Ukraine will be participating, meet them below.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>