<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>War in Ukraine on AFUO - СУОА</title>
    <link>https://ukrainians.org.au/tags/war-in-ukraine/</link>
    <description>Recent content in War in Ukraine on AFUO - СУОА</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-au</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 03 Oct 2019 03:15:51 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://ukrainians.org.au/tags/war-in-ukraine/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Media Release: NO DISCUSSIONS ABOUT UKRAINE WITHOUT UKRAINE  President Zelensky must not agree to Russian demands</title>
      <link>https://ukrainians.org.au/current-affairs/zelensky-not-agree-russia-demands/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 03 Oct 2019 03:15:51 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ukrainians.org.au/current-affairs/zelensky-not-agree-russia-demands/</guid>
      <description>This causes unnecessary tension in civil society . International partners and stakeholders are also calling for answers.
The Australian Federation of Ukrainian Organisations,( the peak body for Ukrainians in Australia ) joins with the Ukrainian World Congress (UWC) in asking for clarity and transparency from the government of Ukraine regarding any agreement to hold elections in areas of Ukraine currently occupied by Russia.
The AFUO reaffirms that Ukraine must never agree to Russian demands regarding Ukrainian elections, or Ukraine’s constitutionally mandated strategic course of NATO and EU integration.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Media Release: Putin commits another act of aggression against Ukraine</title>
      <link>https://ukrainians.org.au/current-affairs/russian-aggression-continues-2019/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Apr 2019 01:21:41 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ukrainians.org.au/current-affairs/russian-aggression-continues-2019/</guid>
      <description>__
MEDIA RELEASE
Russian President Vladimir Putin has once again committed an act of aggression against Ukraine by signing a decree setting out which groups of people are, for humanitarian reasons, entitled to apply for Russian citizenship through a simplified procedure in the Ukrainian regions of Donetsk and Luhansk currently under occupation by the Russian Army.____
According to the decree, the Russian president made the decision &amp;ldquo;in order to protect human and citizen rights and freedoms&amp;rdquo; based on &amp;ldquo;commonly recognised principles and norms of international law&amp;rdquo; in accordance with the Russian Law on citizenship from May 31, 2002.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Record donation efforts by Ukrainians in Australia for Crisis Appeal</title>
      <link>https://ukrainians.org.au/community/record-donation-crisis-appeal/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Jan 2019 02:36:54 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ukrainians.org.au/community/record-donation-crisis-appeal/</guid>
      <description>This article is also available in Ukrainian.
In partnership with Rotary Australia (RAWCS), Caritas Ukraine and the Australian Federation of Ukrainian Organisations (AFUO), the crisis fund formed to provide humanitarian aid to war-affected veterans and families, has raised $128,000. This has been a fantastic effort that has involved all State Hromadas, Churches, Youth Associations and hundreds of individual donors. It shows what a small community like ours can achieve when it unites for a cause.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Less than 100 days until the Invictus Games in Sydney!</title>
      <link>https://ukrainians.org.au/sport/less-than-100-days-until-the-invictus-games-in-sydney/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Jul 2018 10:46:22 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ukrainians.org.au/sport/less-than-100-days-until-the-invictus-games-in-sydney/</guid>
      <description>It is less than 100 days until the Invictus Games in Sydney! Read more from the official Invictus announcement here.
The Invictus Games is an international multi-sport event, in which wounded, injured or sick armed services personnel and veterans take part in sports competitions including wheelchair basketball, sitting volleyball, and indoor rowing. This year they are being held in Sydney from October 20-27th.
A team from Ukraine will be participating, meet them below.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>