<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Sport on AFUO - СУОА</title>
    <link>https://ozeukes.com/categories/sport/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Sport on AFUO - СУОА</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 24 Oct 2018 02:50:07 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://ozeukes.com/categories/sport/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Invictus Games Sydney Team Ukraine: Day One to Four Summary</title>
      <link>https://ozeukes.com/events/international-events/invictus-games-wrap-one/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Oct 2018 02:50:07 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ozeukes.com/events/international-events/invictus-games-wrap-one/</guid>
      <description>Wondering how Team Ukraine is doing? Catch up on all the Invictus Games events here, from the minute they arrived in Australia to the latest competition results.
18th OCTOBER, DAY ONE: ARRIVAL
Team Ukraine arrived early Thursday to a vibrant crowd at Sydney Airport. Zahrava Dance Ensemble performed, also giving a traditional welcome with bread and salt.

**DAY TWO: MEETING WITH LUKE FOLEY MP **Members of the team were welcomed at NSW Parliament by Luke Foley MP.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Invictus Games | Your Guide to Team Ukraine Activities</title>
      <link>https://ozeukes.com/events/invictus-games-ukraine-guide/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Oct 2018 10:26:45 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ozeukes.com/events/invictus-games-ukraine-guide/</guid>
      <description>Invictus Games is only 2 weeks away in Sydney. There are some fantastic opportunities for you, the community, to not only see Team Ukraine compete, but also meet the team members and hear their stories. **COMMUNITY EVENTS | ** **_ Інформація українською мовою | VIEW INFORMATION IN UKRAINIAN HERE_**
TEAM UKRAINE ARRIVAL SYDNEY INTERNATIONAL AIRPORT –_ 7 am THURSDAY 18.10.2018 _
Meeting place will be in forecourt outside the arrival terminal and marked by a Ukrainian flag.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Invictus Games tickets now on sale!</title>
      <link>https://ozeukes.com/events/invictus-games-tickets-now-on-sale/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Aug 2018 12:27:36 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ozeukes.com/events/invictus-games-tickets-now-on-sale/</guid>
      <description>Support Team Ukraine at the Invictus Games in Sydney!
Tickets have now gone on sale for events. See in the image below all the events Ukraine is participating in.
Click here to buy tickets. 
[caption id=&amp;quot;attachment_11895&amp;rdquo; align=&amp;quot;alignnone&amp;rdquo; width=&amp;quot;772&amp;rdquo;] Invictus Games 2018[/caption]</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Less than 100 days until the Invictus Games in Sydney!</title>
      <link>https://ozeukes.com/sport/less-than-100-days-until-the-invictus-games-in-sydney/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Jul 2018 10:46:22 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ozeukes.com/sport/less-than-100-days-until-the-invictus-games-in-sydney/</guid>
      <description>It is less than 100 days until the Invictus Games in Sydney! Read more from the official Invictus announcement here.
The Invictus Games is an international multi-sport event, in which wounded, injured or sick armed services personnel and veterans take part in sports competitions including wheelchair basketball, sitting volleyball, and indoor rowing. This year they are being held in Sydney from October 20-27th.
A team from Ukraine will be participating, meet them below.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>RUSSIA DOESN&#39;T ADHERE TO INTERNATIONALLY ACCEPTED AGREEMENTS NOR DOES IT PLAY BY THE RULES AT THE WINTER OLYMPICS</title>
      <link>https://ozeukes.com/politics/russia-doesnt-adhere-to-internationally-accepted-agreements-nor-does-it-play-by-the-rules-at-the-winter-olympics/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 25 Feb 2018 21:25:15 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ozeukes.com/politics/russia-doesnt-adhere-to-internationally-accepted-agreements-nor-does-it-play-by-the-rules-at-the-winter-olympics/</guid>
      <description>February 26, 2018
MEDIA RELEASE
RUSSIA DOESN’T ADHERE TO INTERNATIONALLY ACCEPTED AGREEMENTS NOR DOES IT PLAY BY THE RULES AT THE WINTER OLYMPICS RULES ARE NOT FOR US – WHETHER IN MILITARY ATTACKS OR SPORTING EVENTS
Putin’s Russian Federation’s aggression in Eastern Ukraine continues. It illegally, annexed Crimea, it sniggers and totally disrespects international accords – Minsk and others. _These rules are not for us. _
But this disrespect for the international community doesn’t end with military actions.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>АКЦІЯ – STOP  PUTIN – STOP WAR</title>
      <link>https://ozeukes.com/events/international-events/stop-putin-stop-war/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Jan 2018 11:31:54 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ozeukes.com/events/international-events/stop-putin-stop-war/</guid>
      <description>January 19, 2018
АКЦІЯ – STOP PUTIN – STOP WAR Управа Союзу Українських Організацій Австралії (СУОА) звертає Вашу увагу на міжнародну акцію STOP PUTIN – STOP WAR, яка покликана не допустити проведення Чемпіонату світу з футболу у Росії.
22 січня пройде уже п’ятий етап акції STOP PUTIN – STOP WAR.
Її метою є намагання привернути увагу світової громадськості до Російської загарбницької війни, яка четвертий рік триває в Україні та не допустити щоб Чемпіонат світу з футболу пройшов на спортивних майданчиках країни-агресора.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Marta Kostyuk – Ukrainian Star Wins Girls Junior Australian Tennis Championship / Марта Костюк – молода українка перемогла у чемпіонаті з тенісу для юніорів на міжнародній арені</title>
      <link>https://ozeukes.com/sport/marta-kostyuk-ukrainian-star-wins-girls-junior-australian-tennis-championship/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 29 Jan 2017 02:15:46 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ozeukes.com/sport/marta-kostyuk-ukrainian-star-wins-girls-junior-australian-tennis-championship/</guid>
      <description>MEDIA RELEASE
28 January 2017
MARTA KOSTYUK – UKRAINIAN STAR WINS GIRLS JUNIOR AUSTRALIAN TENNIS CHAMPIONSHIP
14-year-old Ukrainian Tennis star Marta Kostyuk won the Australian Open Junior Girls title this afternoon in Melbourne, Australia defeating 17-year-old top-seeded Swiss player Rebeka Masarova .
Her tenacity, focus and skills were amazing.
The Australian Federation of Ukrainian Organisations (AFUO) congratulates Marta on her great achievement.
Having won the championship, she approached the microphone and shouted Slava Ukraini!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ПЕРТ-2016: ЧЕМПІОНАТ СВІТУ З ЛЕГКОЇ АТЛЕТИКИ СЕРЕД ВЕТЕРАНІВ</title>
      <link>https://ozeukes.com/sport/pert-2016-chempionat-svitu-z-legkoyi-atletiki-sered-veteraniv/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Nov 2016 10:24:06 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ozeukes.com/sport/pert-2016-chempionat-svitu-z-legkoyi-atletiki-sered-veteraniv/</guid>
      <description>Богдан Рудницький веде розмову із керівником Збірної спортивної дружини легкоатлетів-ветеранів України Валентиною Крепкіною. Із понад 4000 атлетів з 91-ої країни на світовій першості у Перту українські спортовці із 10 осіб сенсаційно вибороли 13 медалей&amp;hellip;
http://www.sbs.com.au/yourlanguage/ukrainian/uk/content/pert-2016-chempionat-svitu-z-legkoyi-atletiki-sered-veteraniv?language=uk</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Western Sydney Wanderers support war-affected kids in Ukraine</title>
      <link>https://ozeukes.com/sport/western-sydney-wanderers-support-war-affected-kids-in-ukraine/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Aug 2016 11:36:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ozeukes.com/sport/western-sydney-wanderers-support-war-affected-kids-in-ukraine/</guid>
      <description>8 AUGUST 2016
MEDIA RELEASE
Western Sydney Wanderers support war-affected kids in Ukraine New South Wales soccer club the Western Sydney Wanderers has generously donated uniforms to a youth soccer team in the war-torn city of Luhansk in Ukraine.
Australian-Ukrainian, Jaroslav Duma OAM, came into contact with the youth team, Kolos, during a recent visit to Ukraine to volunteer with not-for-profit organisation Patriot Defence. The children lacked uniforms to play in the regional soccer competition in Novoaidar Raion in eastern Ukraine.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Footy tipping - Catholicukes</title>
      <link>https://ozeukes.com/sport/footy-tipping-catholicukes/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 29 Mar 2015 21:29:06 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ozeukes.com/sport/footy-tipping-catholicukes/</guid>
      <description>Footy season is upon us - Footy tipping is back !
Test your knowledge !
Sign up and lead the pack !
http://www.footytips.com.au/comps/Catholicukes</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>USC Lions Smash their way to victory!</title>
      <link>https://ozeukes.com/sport/usc-lions-smash-their-way-to-victory/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Jun 2014 06:43:58 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ozeukes.com/sport/usc-lions-smash-their-way-to-victory/</guid>
      <description>USC took out the 2014 Maribyrnong Volleyball Championships in the Open Men&#39;s division, on Sunday the 15th of June, held at the Maribyrnong Sports Academy. Topping their group and cruising through the cross over, the USC boys played a great brand of volleyball. However, the grand final proved to be a greater test against BLASH.
Dropping the first set 25-18, USC pulled it together in the second set to take it 25-17.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Victor Kovalenko into the Sport Australia Hall of Fame</title>
      <link>https://ozeukes.com/sport/victor-kovalenko-into-the-sport-australia-hall-of-fame/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 04 Oct 2013 08:10:16 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ozeukes.com/sport/victor-kovalenko-into-the-sport-australia-hall-of-fame/</guid>
      <description>Inductee Announcement - Victor Kovalenko OAM ‘Medal Maker’ Kovalenko sails into The Sport Australia Hall of Fame The man behind Australia’s most successful sport at the London Olympics, Victor Kovalenko OAM, will be honoured among Australia’s sporting elite when he is inducted into The Sport Australia Hall of Fame next week.
Kovalenko, who was head coach of the Australian sailing team that won three golds and one silver Olympic medal last year, is recognised for his unyielding commitment to strategy and work rate - a formula that has delivered ultimate success to those who have worked beneath him.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fifth International Ukrainian Football Tournament</title>
      <link>https://ozeukes.com/sport/fifth-international-ukrainian-football-tournament/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 May 2013 02:47:06 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ozeukes.com/sport/fifth-international-ukrainian-football-tournament/</guid>
      <description>The fifth International Ukrainian Football Tournament (IUFT) will be held from June 30 to July 6 2013, in the state of New York, USA. Taking part in the competition will be a team from Australia.
A full report can be read at: http://iuft.ukiedaily.com/2013/05/iuft-2013-new-york-confirms-teams-from-great-britain-and-australia/</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ukrainians at the 2013 Australian Open</title>
      <link>https://ozeukes.com/sport/ukrainians-at-the-2013-australian-open/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Jan 2013 00:17:38 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ozeukes.com/sport/ukrainians-at-the-2013-australian-open/</guid>
      <description>The 2013 Australian Open Tennis Championships started on Monday 14th January 2013 and ends on Sunday, 27th January.
A number of Ukrainian tennis players entered into various events, including Qualifying rounds.
Ukrainian Men World Ranking
20
243
205
154
(s) 102 (d) 237
Ukrainian Ladies World Ranking
179
226
203
127
85
198
Several players have qualified for the main events:
Scheduled matches involving Ukrainian Players Men’s Singles 1st Round Women’s Singles 1st Round Men’s Doubles 1st Round The Australian Federation of Ukrainian Organisations (AFUO) extends its best wishes and hopes for success to all the Ukrainian participants.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Kovalenko - Ukrainian Background - Olympics Medal Maker for Australia</title>
      <link>https://ozeukes.com/sport/kovalenko-ukrainian-background-olympics-medal-maker-for-australia/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Aug 2012 09:46:57 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ozeukes.com/sport/kovalenko-ukrainian-background-olympics-medal-maker-for-australia/</guid>
      <description>Saturday August 11, 2012
MEDIA RELEASE
Victor Kovalenko Ukrainian Background Australian Olympics Medal Maker Australian sailing&#39;s coach, Victor Kovalenko has guided Australia to another gold medal at the London Olympics in the men&#39;s 470 sailing class. The race** ****was won by ****Mathew Belcher and Malcolm Page**.
Kovalenko of Ukrainian background, who has made Australia home, has an outstanding record in training and leading Australian sailing teams to glory in the sport</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>UEFA EURO 2012 Information</title>
      <link>https://ozeukes.com/events/international-events/uefa-euro-2012-information/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 31 May 2012 02:46:14 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ozeukes.com/events/international-events/uefa-euro-2012-information/</guid>
      <description>UEFA EURO 2012 – Video Clips
In the build up to the EURO 2012 European Football Championship, which will take place in Poland and Ukraine from June 8 to July 1, a number of video clips have been released which can be viewed on the internet.
У підготовці до чемпіонату Європи 2012 року (Євро 2012), який відбудеться в Польщі та Україні від 8-го червня до 1-го липня, випущено декілька відеокліпів почерез інтернет.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ukraine squad for EURO 2012</title>
      <link>https://ozeukes.com/events/international-events/ukraine-squad-for-euro-2012/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 31 May 2012 02:41:18 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ozeukes.com/events/international-events/ukraine-squad-for-euro-2012/</guid>
      <description>**Ukrainian squad for EURO 2012**
The 23-man squad who will represent Ukraine during the finals of the EURO 2012 European Football Championship, which will take place in Poland and Ukraine from June 8 to July 1, has been named by the head coach of Ukraine&#39;s national football team, Oleh Blokhin.
Спискок команди на чемпіонат Європи 2012 року
Головний тренер збірної України з футболу Олег Блохін назазначив які футболісти потрапали в спискок команди на чемпіонат Європи 2012 року (Євро 2012), який відбудеться в Польщі та Україні від 8-го червня до 1-го липня.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Community Golf Day - Melbourne</title>
      <link>https://ozeukes.com/events/victoria/community-golf-day-melbourne/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Feb 2012 22:53:42 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ozeukes.com/events/victoria/community-golf-day-melbourne/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Australian Tennis Open 2012 – Ukrainian Players</title>
      <link>https://ozeukes.com/events/international-events/australian-tennis-open-2012-ukrainian-players/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 19 Jan 2012 06:43:39 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ozeukes.com/events/international-events/australian-tennis-open-2012-ukrainian-players/</guid>
      <description>The first tennis grand slam event of 2012, the Australian Open, got under way on Monday 16th January 2012 at Melbourne Park, Melbourne, Australia. A number of Ukrainian tennis players entered into the competition.
Ukrainian Men
Ukrainian Women
Results of the first 2 rounds of Singles competitions Men&#39;s Singles - 1st Round
Set score
Result
3
2
** **
3
2
Set scores
Result
_ _
3
2
** **</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ґранд фінал Австралійської футбольної ліґи. Нобл Парк</title>
      <link>https://ozeukes.com/events/%d2%90%d1%80%d0%b0%d0%bd%d0%b4-%d1%84%d1%96%d0%bd%d0%b0%d0%bb-%d0%90%d0%b2%d1%81%d1%82%d1%80%d0%b0%d0%bb%d1%96%d0%b9%d1%81%d1%8c%d0%ba%d0%be%d1%97-%d1%84%d1%83%d1%82%d0%b1%d0%be%d0%bb%d1%8c%d0%bd/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Sep 2011 03:35:17 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ozeukes.com/events/%d2%90%d1%80%d0%b0%d0%bd%d0%b4-%d1%84%d1%96%d0%bd%d0%b0%d0%bb-%d0%90%d0%b2%d1%81%d1%82%d1%80%d0%b0%d0%bb%d1%96%d0%b9%d1%81%d1%8c%d0%ba%d0%be%d1%97-%d1%84%d1%83%d1%82%d0%b1%d0%be%d0%bb%d1%8c%d0%bd/</guid>
      <description>Ґранд фінал Австралійської футбольної ліґи. Пряма транслація на великому екрані. Субота 1 жовтня від год. 12.00 дня. Український народний дім, 26 Chandler Rd., Noble Park Можна буде набути смачну перекуску. Вступ і паркування авт – безкоштовні. Вхід до клюбу з–заду будинку по сходах на перший поверх.
_Якщо хтось не розуміє правила гри, не турбуйтеся, пояснимо! _
__Дружня атмосфера! Запрошуємо всіх.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>AFL Grand final Noble Park</title>
      <link>https://ozeukes.com/events/afl-grand-final-noble-park/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Sep 2011 03:32:07 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ozeukes.com/events/afl-grand-final-noble-park/</guid>
      <description>AFL Grand final live on big screen Saturday Оctober 1st from 12 noon onwards Ukrainian Community Centre, 26 Chandler Rd., Noble Park Food, refreshments available. Free admission and parking. Club Room - 1st floor. Entry at rear of Centre</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ukrainian Golf Club in Victoria</title>
      <link>https://ozeukes.com/events/victoria/ukrainian-golf-club-in-victoria/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Aug 2011 00:59:08 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ozeukes.com/events/victoria/ukrainian-golf-club-in-victoria/</guid>
      <description>The next game of the Association of Ukrainians in Victoria Golf Club (AUVGC)is a Melbourne - Geelong challenge to be held on 28 August 2011 at Curlewis.** **
****Presentations after the game will be held at Ukrainian Hall, 57 Pakington St, Geelong, and will join in the celebrations for 20th anniversary of Ukrainian independence.
For further details check here: http://www.ukigolf.org.au/Next-Game.html</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>World Cadets Judo Championship</title>
      <link>https://ozeukes.com/events/international-events/world-cadets-judo-championship/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Jul 2011 02:00:24 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ozeukes.com/events/international-events/world-cadets-judo-championship/</guid>
      <description>The 2nd World Judo Championship for Cadets (boys and girls under the age of 17 years) will be held in Kyiv, Ukraine, between the 11th and 14th of August 2011.
The Australian Cadets Judo Team will be representing Australia in this world championship.
The Australian team comprises of 26 members and includes young athletes, their coaches, team officials, and some escorting parents.
This is a truly all Australian team with athletes from:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Multicultural Youth Sports Partnership Grants</title>
      <link>https://ozeukes.com/sport/multicultural-youth-sports-partnership-grants/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 May 2011 02:50:47 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ozeukes.com/sport/multicultural-youth-sports-partnership-grants/</guid>
      <description>On Friday 29 April 2011, as part of the Federal Government&#39;s commitment to increasing participation in sport, Minister for Sport Mark Arbib and Parliamentary Secretary for Immigration and Multicultural Affairs Kate Lundy officially opened applications for the Multicultural Youth Sports Partnership Program.
The Program will provide grants of between $5000 and $50 000 to create opportunities for young people from culturally and linguistically diverse backgrounds, to engage with sport and physical activity.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ukraine beats Australia in Fed Cup tie</title>
      <link>https://ozeukes.com/events/international-events/ukraine-beats-australia-in-fed-cup-tie/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 17 Apr 2011 11:30:57 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ozeukes.com/events/international-events/ukraine-beats-australia-in-fed-cup-tie/</guid>
      <description>In an upset result Ukraine’s women tennis players have defeated Australia in a Fed Cup tie. The win gives Ukraine the right to remain in the elite Fed Cup World Group and relegates Australia to the lower tier World Group II.
Scores were level after the first two singles matches played at Glen Iris Valley Recreation Club in Mt. Waverley, Melbourne on Saturday 16 April 2011, and were level again after the two reverse singles rubbers on Sunday.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Australia vs Ukraine Fed Cup Tennis Match</title>
      <link>https://ozeukes.com/events/international-events/australia-vs-ukraine-fed-cup-tennis-match/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Mar 2011 11:35:03 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ozeukes.com/events/international-events/australia-vs-ukraine-fed-cup-tennis-match/</guid>
      <description>Australia will host Ukraine in a Fed Cup tie in April for the right to stay in the World Group.
The Fed Cup was launched in 1963 to celebrate the 50th anniversary of the International Tennis Federation (ITF). It’s now the world’s largest annual international team competition in women’s sport, with 80 nations competing in 2010.
Details regarding the Australia versus Ukraine tie
Venue
The Glen Iris Valley Recreation Club 260-270 High Street Road Mount Waverley 3149</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Viktor Chernous Boxing in Melbourne</title>
      <link>https://ozeukes.com/sport/viktor-chernous-boxing-in-melbourne/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 Feb 2011 00:24:32 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ozeukes.com/sport/viktor-chernous-boxing-in-melbourne/</guid>
      <description>[](http://www.ozeukes.com/wp-content/uploads/2011/02/250px-Chernous_victor1.jpg)[![](http://www.ozeukes.com/wp-content/uploads/2011/02/250px-Chernous_victor2-150x150.jpg) ](http://www.ozeukes.com/wp-content/uploads/2011/02/250px-Chernous_victor2.jpg)The Ukrainian-born Viktor ‘The Hurricane’ Chernous is the current Australian welterweight champion. On the 4th March 2011 Victor takes on the New Zealand champion Steve Heremai at Flemington Racecourse, Melbourne. The fight will be broadcast on Foxtel.
Viktor’s trainer, Ivan Bukavina, thinks that his opponent will be the hardest he has faced to-date. “He is tough and a big puncher, but Viktor will win” says Ivan Bukavina, who would not have matched him up if he didn’t believe that Viktor would win.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ukraine wins Cyprus friendly tournament</title>
      <link>https://ozeukes.com/sport/ukraine-wins-cyprus-friendly-tournament/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Feb 2011 05:51:07 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ozeukes.com/sport/ukraine-wins-cyprus-friendly-tournament/</guid>
      <description>Courtesy of Greenwich Time
NICOSIA, Cyprus (AP) — Ukraine beat Sweden in a penalty shootout after a 1-1 draw to win a friendly tournament in Cyprus on Wednesday, while Romania defeated the Cypriot hosts also on penalties to take third place.
The four-nation event was used by the teams as preparation for next month&#39;s Euro 2012 qualifying matches.
Sweden grabbed the early lead in the 7th minute when Zlatan Ibrahimovic chested a high pass into the path of Johan Elmander, who half-volleyed the ball from the edge of the box into the top corner of the net.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Euro 2012 Tickets On Sale only till 31 March 2011</title>
      <link>https://ozeukes.com/events/international-events/euro-2012-tickets-on-sale-only-till-31-march-2011/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Feb 2011 23:13:42 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ozeukes.com/events/international-events/euro-2012-tickets-on-sale-only-till-31-march-2011/</guid>
      <description>Ticket sales for UEFA EURO 2012 will start on 1 March 2011 through www.UEFA.com and end on 31 March 2011
Any application received after the application closing date will not be processed.
Assuming demand for tickets exceeds supply, a random lottery will determine the successful applications.
Please note: all correctly submitted and accepted applications received between 1 March and 31 March 2011 will be taken into consideration. It makes no difference whether you register early (on 1 March 2011) or later during the month.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>AUSTRALIAN OPEN 2011 – DOLGOPOLOV GOES DOWN FIGHTING</title>
      <link>https://ozeukes.com/events/australian-open-2011-%e2%80%93-dolgopolov-goes-down-fighting/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Jan 2011 23:56:17 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ozeukes.com/events/australian-open-2011-%e2%80%93-dolgopolov-goes-down-fighting/</guid>
      <description>As Alexandr Dolgopolov prepared himself for the biggest match of his life, hopes were held high for him to deliver a shock blow to 5th seeded Andy Murray, in their Quarter Final clash.
The match opened with ‘the most unpredictable player on the tour’ immediately forcing several back-to-back, break points against the heavily backed Scotsman. In true form, Murray overcame his initial quarter final jitters and proceeded to take both the first and second sets respectively, 7-5, 6-3.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>AUSTRALIAN OPEN 2011 - DOLGOPOLOV Versus MURRAY </title>
      <link>https://ozeukes.com/events/australian-open-2011-dolgopolov-versus-murray/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Jan 2011 06:12:47 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ozeukes.com/events/australian-open-2011-dolgopolov-versus-murray/</guid>
      <description>** THIS IS ONCE AGAIN A MASS CALL OUT TO ALL UKRAINIAN SUPPORTERS TO COME DOWN TO MELBOURNE PARK TOMORROW, 26th January, 2011 AND SUPPORT ONE OF OUR OWN!**
** **
Dolgopolov will need all the support he can get to make it through to the semis, so pack your picnic lunch and make a great day of it.
As the 3rd day match on Rod Laver arena, it is expected that the match won&#39;t start till after 2pm.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>AUSTRALIAN OPEN 2011 – DOLGOPOLOV TO PLAY ON AUSTRALIA DAY</title>
      <link>https://ozeukes.com/events/australian-open-2011-%e2%80%93-dolgopolov-to-play-on-australia-day/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Jan 2011 02:28:58 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ozeukes.com/events/australian-open-2011-%e2%80%93-dolgopolov-to-play-on-australia-day/</guid>
      <description>**“MARCHENKO GOES DOWN FIGHTING” **Marchenko was always going to have the odds stacked against him as he faced Murray in Round 2 on Thursday night. But with an enthusiastic 30 odd Ukrainian supporters cheering him on, hopes were held high. In what was a gallant battle, Murray proved too good for the up and coming Ukrainian, smashing him in 3 sets, 6-1, 6-3, 6-3.
**“DAY 10 – ANOTHER UKRAINIAN FACES MURRAY!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Congratulations to Alexander Dolgopolov</title>
      <link>https://ozeukes.com/events/international-events/congratulations-to-alexander-dolgopolov/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Jan 2011 12:13:16 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ozeukes.com/events/international-events/congratulations-to-alexander-dolgopolov/</guid>
      <description>Congratulations to Alexander Dolgopolov, the unseeded Ukrainian tennis player who today defeated the fourth-seeded Swede Robin Soderling in five sets 1-6 6-3 6-1 4-6 6-2 at the Australian Tennis Open.
Despite badly losing the first set, Alexander quietly and competently rallied to outsmart and out-play his larger and more-experienced opponent. The further the match progressed, the more positively did Alexander play, winning over the support of the vocal crowd. Alexander will next face Andy Murray in the quarter-finals.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>MARCHENKO V. MURRAY - After 7pm 20/01/2011 Margaret Court Arena</title>
      <link>https://ozeukes.com/events/marchenko-v-murray-after-7pm-20012011-margaret-court-arena/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Jan 2011 05:08:17 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ozeukes.com/events/marchenko-v-murray-after-7pm-20012011-margaret-court-arena/</guid>
      <description>**THIS IS A CALL OUT TO ALL UKRAINIAN SUPPORTERS TO COME DOWN TO MELBOURNE PARK TOMORROW, 20th January, 2011 **
AND SUPPORT ONE OF OUR OWN!
MARCHENKO V. MURRAY - After 7pm 20/01/2011 Margaret Court Arena
Don on your Uki colours, grab your flags and warm up your vocal cords. We will aim to hold a few seats reserve in the arena, but best to get there early!
This is sure to be a huge match and with tickets only $20 after 5pm, we’re encouraging everyone and anyone to get down to Margaret Court for 7pm.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>AUSTRALIAN OPEN 2011 – DAY 2/3 HIGHLIGHTS/DAY FOUR SCHEDULE</title>
      <link>https://ozeukes.com/events/australian-open-2011-%e2%80%93-day-23-highlightsday-four-schedule/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Jan 2011 04:53:07 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ozeukes.com/events/australian-open-2011-%e2%80%93-day-23-highlightsday-four-schedule/</guid>
      <description>**AUSTRALIAN OPEN 2011 – **
**DAY 2/3 HIGHLIGHTS/DAY FOUR SCHEDULE **
“DAY TWO – 3 out of 4 aint bad!”
Bondarenko opened DAY TWO, against 54th ranked Chinese Shuai Peng. After a promising start, it turned into a tight 3-set battle, ending in Peng’s favour 2-6, 6-3, 8-6. Kateryna’s Open is far from over however, seeing her team up with Safina for the Women’s doubles later in the week.
Next up was Alexandr Dolgopolov, who blitzed his Kazakhstani opponent in straight sets, 6-3, 6-2, 6-4.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>AUSTRALIAN OPEN 2011 – DAY ONE HIGHLIGHTS/DAY TWO SCHEDULE</title>
      <link>https://ozeukes.com/events/victoria/australian-open-2011-%e2%80%93-day-one-highlightsday-two-schedule/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Jan 2011 06:53:22 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ozeukes.com/events/victoria/australian-open-2011-%e2%80%93-day-one-highlightsday-two-schedule/</guid>
      <description>**AUSTRALIAN OPEN 2011 – **DAY ONE HIGHLIGHTS/DAY TWO SCHEDULE
 “DAY ONE SUCCESS – Stakhovsky through to ROUND 2.”
 As we approach the end of Day 1, Ukraine already has one through to the second round, with Sergiy Stakhovsky breezing through in straight sets against German, Daniel Brands.
Stakhovsky must now face neighbouring Polish competitor, Lukasz Kubot, for round 2. Kubot’s victory over the 18th seeded American, Sam Querrey, indicates that he is in form, so Stakhovsky will need all the support he can get.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>AUSTRALIAN OPEN 2011 - Round 1 (DAY ONE)</title>
      <link>https://ozeukes.com/events/australian-open-2011-round-1-day-one/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Jan 2011 00:42:24 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ozeukes.com/events/australian-open-2011-round-1-day-one/</guid>
      <description>AUSTRALIAN OPEN 2011
CALLING ON ALL SPORTS FANS!
The wait is over – The 2011 Australian Open is finally here and we’re inviting you to come down and support our athletes**!**
Over the next 2 weeks, the AFUO will be providing regular updates of the successes and movements of all Ukrainian Athletes competing in this year’s 2011 Australian Open.
Each day a new playing schedule will be revised and released. We’ll aim to identify early when the Ukrainian athletes are competing, so that you can arrange a supporters group to come down and cheer on our athletes!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rukopash Hopak</title>
      <link>https://ozeukes.com/sport/rukopash-hopak/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Sep 2010 12:39:08 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ozeukes.com/sport/rukopash-hopak/</guid>
      <description>We are proud to announce the introduction of Rukopash Hopak into Australia.
If you want to know what it is all about, check out the overview of Rukopash Hopak from Ukraine or the demonstration in Geelong. For more background information, you can also check out this PowerPoint presentation or the WikiPedia entry.
The following workshops are currently planned:
 * Melbourne - Saturday 23rd October, 2:30 pm, Venue: Dim Molodi * Sydney - Saturday 13th November, 2:00 pm, Venue: Dim Molodi * Perth - Saturday 18th December (TBC) * Brisbane - January 2011 (TBC)  If you are interested, or want more information, please contact Mark Tkaczuk.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>2010 UCI Road World Championships</title>
      <link>https://ozeukes.com/events/2010-uci-road-world-championships/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Sep 2010 12:12:07 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ozeukes.com/events/2010-uci-road-world-championships/</guid>
      <description>2010 UCI Road World Championships</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>