<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Help Ukraine on AFUO - СУОА</title>
    <link>https://ukrainians.org.au/tags/help-ukraine/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Help Ukraine on AFUO - СУОА</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-au</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 06 Oct 2019 04:48:52 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://ukrainians.org.au/tags/help-ukraine/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Development of OT in Ukraine is now apart of the Ukrainian Crisis Аppeal</title>
      <link>https://ukrainians.org.au/community/occupational-therapy-ukraine-crisis-appeal/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Oct 2019 04:48:52 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ukrainians.org.au/community/occupational-therapy-ukraine-crisis-appeal/</guid>
      <description>A few months ago, we introduced you to Kirrily Manning, an Australian Occupational Therapist (OT) playing a key role working to develop the OT profession in Ukraine. You can read more about her story here in English and here in Ukrainian. 
Throughout the years that Go Global, Ukraine ran at Curtin University (2009-2013) led by Kirrily, over 70 students from occupational therapy, speech therapy, physiotherapy and nutrition travelled to Ukraine.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Meet Kirrily: An OT working to help kids in Ukraine</title>
      <link>https://ukrainians.org.au/community/kirrily-help-ukraine/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 May 2019 10:45:31 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ukrainians.org.au/community/kirrily-help-ukraine/</guid>
      <description>Kirrily Manning is an Occupational Therapist (OT) who graduated from the University of South Australia in 1994. Kirrily currently teaches at both an undergraduate and masters level at the school of Occupational Therapy, Social Work and Speech Therapy within Curtin University.
In 2005, Kirrily started volunteer work, assisting children with disabilities in orphanages in Ukraine, later setting up a student international placement program for Curtin University. Go Global Ukraine facilitated Australian occupational therapy, physiotherapy and speech therapy students to work in these same orphanages with a focus on upskilling staff in therapeutic care practices.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Record donation efforts by Ukrainians in Australia for Crisis Appeal</title>
      <link>https://ukrainians.org.au/community/record-donation-crisis-appeal/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Jan 2019 02:36:54 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ukrainians.org.au/community/record-donation-crisis-appeal/</guid>
      <description>This article is also available in Ukrainian.
In partnership with Rotary Australia (RAWCS), Caritas Ukraine and the Australian Federation of Ukrainian Organisations (AFUO), the crisis fund formed to provide humanitarian aid to war-affected veterans and families, has raised $128,000. This has been a fantastic effort that has involved all State Hromadas, Churches, Youth Associations and hundreds of individual donors. It shows what a small community like ours can achieve when it unites for a cause.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ukraine&#39;s Veterans receive major support from Cabramatta-Fairfield</title>
      <link>https://ukrainians.org.au/community/cabramatta-fairfield-supports-ukraine/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Oct 2018 05:41:20 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ukrainians.org.au/community/cabramatta-fairfield-supports-ukraine/</guid>
      <description>Ukrainian Association of Cabramatta / Fairfield in NSW has shown strong community leadership and excellence by becoming a Gold Patron ($5000) of the Ukraine Crisis Appeal. The Association has also offered to sponsor the Featherdale event for Team Ukraine &amp;amp; Family &amp;amp; Friends to the value of nearly $3000.00.
The Australian Federation of Ukrainian Organisations (AFUO) Ukraine Crisis Appeal will use funds raised to support rehabilitation of ATO Veterans and their families.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>УКРАЇНЦІ В АВСТРАЛІЇ ЗАСУДЖУЮТЬ НЕЗАКОННОГО УТРИМАННЯ  РОСІЙСЬКОЮ ФЕДЕРАЦІЄЮ  УКРАЇНСЬКОГО ЖУРНАЛІСТА РОМАНА СУЩЕНКА</title>
      <link>https://ukrainians.org.au/current-affairs/free-sushenko/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Oct 2018 01:38:13 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ukrainians.org.au/current-affairs/free-sushenko/</guid>
      <description>__
Минає два роки з часу незаконного утримання під вартою в РФ українського журналіста Романа Сущенка.
Нещодавно кремлівський режим засудив його до 12 років колонії строгого режиму за надуманими звинуваченнями у шпіонажі.
Союз Українських Організацій Австралія (СУОА) приєднується до всіх украінських громад світу у засудженні дій РФ і закликає своїх членів та австралійський уряд посилити тиск на РФ у справі звільнення всіх незаконно арештованих українських політичних в&amp;rsquo;язнів.
Пригадується сьогодні чудовий малюнок Сущенка - австралійський Сідней.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Less than 100 days until the Invictus Games in Sydney!</title>
      <link>https://ukrainians.org.au/sport/less-than-100-days-until-the-invictus-games-in-sydney/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Jul 2018 10:46:22 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ukrainians.org.au/sport/less-than-100-days-until-the-invictus-games-in-sydney/</guid>
      <description>It is less than 100 days until the Invictus Games in Sydney! Read more from the official Invictus announcement here.
The Invictus Games is an international multi-sport event, in which wounded, injured or sick armed services personnel and veterans take part in sports competitions including wheelchair basketball, sitting volleyball, and indoor rowing. This year they are being held in Sydney from October 20-27th.
A team from Ukraine will be participating, meet them below.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Help Ukraine&#39;s Veterans &amp; their families through Tax Deductible Donations</title>
      <link>https://ukrainians.org.au/community/ukraine-crisis-appeal/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Jun 2018 12:55:57 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ukrainians.org.au/community/ukraine-crisis-appeal/</guid>
      <description>The Australian Federation of Ukrainian Organisations (AFUO) is proud to announce the launch of the Ukraine Crisis Appeal. This is a collaboration between AFUO, Rotary Australia World Community Service (RAWCS) and Caritas Ukraine. The fund is the only with tax-deductible status in Australia that allows aid to be directed to Ukraine.
The aid programs help address the following for Veterans and their families:
 *  psychological and psycho social support</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>