<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>ACT on AFUO - СУОА</title>
    <link>https://ozeukes.com/categories/act/</link>
    <description>Recent content in ACT on AFUO - СУОА</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 17 Jul 2019 08:08:31 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://ozeukes.com/categories/act/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>MH17 Commemorative Service in Canberra</title>
      <link>https://ozeukes.com/events/mh17-service-canberra/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Jul 2019 08:08:31 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ozeukes.com/events/mh17-service-canberra/</guid>
      <description>**The Service will take place at MH17 Memorial, Parliament House Canberra, ACT on Friday 19th July 2019 at 1pm. **
The Commemorative Service will be conducted by His Eminence Metropolitan Antony, the Prime Hierarch of the Ukrainian Orthodox Church of the USA and Diaspora and His Eminence Archbishop Daniel, Archbishop of the Ukrainian Orthodox Church of the USA and Diaspora with the participation of Ukrainian Greek Catholic and Orthodox Churches of Canberra.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>AFUO participates in 70th Anniversary Celebrations in Canberra |  Святкування 70-річчя в Канберрі</title>
      <link>https://ozeukes.com/events/70-anniversary-canberra/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 29 Sep 2018 12:40:54 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ozeukes.com/events/70-anniversary-canberra/</guid>
      <description>This weekend in Canberra, 70th Anniversary celebrations are in progress, honouring 70 years of Ukrainian Settlement, and 70 years of the Ukrainian Autocephalic Orthodox Church in Australia.
[caption id=&amp;quot;attachment_11964&amp;rdquo; align=&amp;quot;aligncenter&amp;rdquo; width=&amp;quot;480&amp;rdquo;] AFUO gifted a plaque to honour the occasion[/caption]
Beginning the proceedings, a service was held today St. John the Baptist Anglican Church - where exactly 70 years ago, Ukrainian Orthodox Christians served the very first Divine Liturgy in Australia. Leaders from all Ukrainian clergies in Australia were present.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Invitation to hear Dr. Phillip Karber - Reflecting on Ukraine’s Current &#34;War in the East&#34;</title>
      <link>https://ozeukes.com/events/invitation-to-hear-dr-phillip-karber-reflecting-on-ukraines-current-war-in-the-east/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 12 Nov 2016 21:32:58 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ozeukes.com/events/invitation-to-hear-dr-phillip-karber-reflecting-on-ukraines-current-war-in-the-east/</guid>
      <description>The Australian Federation of Ukrainian Organisations has pleasure in announcing that it has invited
Dr. Phillip Karber to meet with Australia’s Ukrainian community during his stay and commitments with Australia’ Defence Forces.
Dr Karber an international authority from the USA, has undertaken 25 Frontline and Command visits to Donbas war region and is an internationally recognised expert in defence and national security matters.
He is President of the Potomac Foundation; he was named to this position in 2012, having been a Senior Fellow since the Foundation’s inception in 1988.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ukrainian Protest Rally in Canberra - Media coverage</title>
      <link>https://ozeukes.com/events/act/ukrainian-protest-rally-in-canberra-media-coverage/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 May 2014 01:49:07 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ozeukes.com/events/act/ukrainian-protest-rally-in-canberra-media-coverage/</guid>
      <description>Scores of cars from Brisbane, Melbourne and Sydney carrying Ukrainian flags drove to Canberra to take part in an AutoMaidan round the streets of Australia’s capital city on Sunday May 25th 2014, the day of Presidential elections in Ukraine. The AutoMaidan terminated in front of the Russian embassy where hundreds of peaceful protesters expressed their support for Ukraine and strong opposition to Putin’s aggression in Ukraine.
Earlier in the day many of the protesters who had Ukrainian citizenship had taken the opportunity to vote at the Ukrainian Embassy.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>National Rally in Support of Ukraine - from Sydney</title>
      <link>https://ozeukes.com/events/new-south-wales/national-rally-in-support-of-ukraine-from-sydney/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 18 May 2014 04:18:07 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ozeukes.com/events/new-south-wales/national-rally-in-support-of-ukraine-from-sydney/</guid>
      <description>AFUO-UCNSW Canberra Rally Sydney Bus May 25th 
Bookings for Sydney Bus to Canberra Rally and Ukrainian Elections Sunday May 25th 8.00am, St Andrew&#39;s Ukrainian Catholic Church, 57 Church St, Lidcombe. $25 Employed Adults, $10 pensioners/ students/ children + $1.50 booking fee each. Bus will also be picking up from Cabramatta Ukrainian Hall. Queries 0410 866 820.
Замовлення на автобус з Сіднею на акцію і на украінські вибори в Канберрі 25-го травня.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>National Rally in Support of Ukraine</title>
      <link>https://ozeukes.com/events/national-rally-in-support-of-ukraine/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 May 2014 01:18:23 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ozeukes.com/events/national-rally-in-support-of-ukraine/</guid>
      <description>The Australian Federation of Ukrainian Organisations (AFUO) calls on all concerned Australians to participate in a National Rally in Support of Ukraine.
The rally will express its strong opposition to Putin’s aggression in Ukraine.
The final stage of the rally will be culminate at the Embassy of the Russian Federation in Australia in Canberra on Sunday May 25, 2014 at 1.00pm, the day of the Presidential elections in Ukraine.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Free Lecture in Canberra - Ukraine: Between the EU and Russia</title>
      <link>https://ozeukes.com/events/act/free-lecture-in-canberra-ukraine-between-the-eu-and-russia/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 29 Mar 2014 00:39:49 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ozeukes.com/events/act/free-lecture-in-canberra-ukraine-between-the-eu-and-russia/</guid>
      <description>Ukraine: Between the EU and Russia Professor Norman Davies will be presenting a lecture titled “Ukraine: Between the EU and Russia”.
The event will be chaired by Professor the Hon Gareth Evans AC QC, Chancellor of the Australian National University.
The lecture is free and open to the public.
Date: Tuesday 1 April 2014 Time: 5.00 pm – 6.30 pm Venue: The Hall, University House, Balmain Cres Canberra
RSVP by Friday 28 March 2014 E-mail: europe@anu.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Демонстрація в Канберрі</title>
      <link>https://ozeukes.com/events/act/rally-in-canberra-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 Jan 2014 22:53:59 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ozeukes.com/events/act/rally-in-canberra-2/</guid>
      <description>МАРІЧКА ГАЛАБУРДА - ЧИГРИН
СІДНЕЙ 30.1.2014
 В четвер 30.1.2014 ми, члени української спільноти Сіднею й Канберри відбули демонстрацію (rally) в Канберрі перед приміщенням Міністерства Зовнішніх Зв&amp;quot;язків ( Departмent of Foreign Affairs and Trade) на підтримку Майдану, тих, хто стоїть на Майдані й їх вимоги.

Приїхали ті, хто міг й хотів. Відпрацьовує поняття не кількість - а якість. Нас не було багато. В Канберрі температира досягала 38 тепла!
Друга частина демонстрації відбулася перед Амбасадою ( посольством ) України.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Canberra Malanka</title>
      <link>https://ozeukes.com/events/act/canberra-malanka/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Jan 2014 23:32:44 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ozeukes.com/events/act/canberra-malanka/</guid>
      <description>The Ukrainian Community in Canberra will welcome in the Ukrainian New Year with its Malanka 2014 on Friday 17th January 2014 at St. Volodymyr’s Ukrainian Catholic Church Hall.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Акція підтримки Євромайдану в Канберрі</title>
      <link>https://ozeukes.com/events/act/euromaidan-support-in-canberra/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Dec 2013 05:26:51 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ozeukes.com/events/act/euromaidan-support-in-canberra/</guid>
      <description>Українська Aвстралія знова вийшла в підтримку Євромайдану
 
В суботу 14.12.2013 в Канберрі, столиция Aвстралії, відбулася акція підтримки Євромайдану перед Посольством України в Aвстралії .

Aкція організована Cоюзом Українських Організацій Aвстралії в співпраці з отцям та парафії УГКЦ та УAПЦ в Канберрі.
В акції взяли участь молодь, студенти та громадяни.

 Проведено спільну молитву для України, були виступи, прийнято резолюцію яка була вручена Тимчасово Повіреним у справах України в Aвстралії Cтаніславу Cташевському.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>RALLY in CANBERRA</title>
      <link>https://ozeukes.com/events/act/rally-in-canberra/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Dec 2013 11:53:43 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ozeukes.com/events/act/rally-in-canberra/</guid>
      <description>Акції в Канберрі**** відбудеться у СУБОТУ, 14го грудня.****
Збірка біля храму УАПЦ в Turner о год. 10.30рано, а від так, короткий похід до Посольства/Амбасада України на 11.00рано.
ПІДТРИМУЙМО наших братів в УКРАЇНІ! Це зокрема тепер ВАЖНИЙ та ВАЖКИЙ ЧАС! МИ з УКРАЇНОЮ! УКРАЇНА це ЄВРОПА! ПРОШУ ПОШИРЮВАТИ ІНФОРМАЦІЇ!
 
RALLY** ****in**** ****CANBERRA****!** SATURDAY, 14 December.****
**Meeting at **10.30AM at Ukrainian Orthodox Church in Turner, and then short walk/march to the Ukrainian Embassy for 11.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Вшанування жертв Голодомору в Канбеpрі </title>
      <link>https://ozeukes.com/events/act/canberra-commemorates-the-holodomor/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Nov 2013 00:35:47 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ozeukes.com/events/act/canberra-commemorates-the-holodomor/</guid>
      <description>МАРІЧКА ГАЛАБУРДА–ЧИГРИН В КАНБЕPРІ вшанування жертв Голодомору 1932 – 1933 років Під гаслом &amp;ldquo;**Україна Пам’ятає – Світ Визнає!&amp;rdquo; - з рамен Консисторії УАПЦ і Об&#39;єднання Українських Громад НПВ відбулася в неділю 17.11.2013 в Канберрі **вшанування пам’яті жертв, тих, хто 80 років тому згинув траґічною смертю підчас Голодомору-Геноциду українського народу.
З Благословення Архиєпископа Іоана (Івана Дерев&#39;янки) Правлячого Єпископа Австралійсько-Новозеляндської Єпархії УАПЦ, в центрі Православ&#39;я в Канбеrрі Соборнo відбулося посвячення оновленого Пам&#39;ятника жертвам Голодомору, який був зведений 30 років тому в часі 50-тої річниці Голодомору в 1985 році, посвячений Владикою Володимиром Дідовичем, відслонений тоді головою опизицію до австралійського уряду - паном **Джоном Говардом.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Screening of &#39;Genocide Revealed&#39; in Federal Parliament</title>
      <link>https://ozeukes.com/events/act/screening-of-genocide-revealed-in-federal-parliament/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Nov 2012 02:21:21 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ozeukes.com/events/act/screening-of-genocide-revealed-in-federal-parliament/</guid>
      <description>INVITATION
 To commemorate the 80th anniversary
of the Ukrainian genocide – Holodomor
 The Australian-Ukrainian Parliamentary Group
Invites Senators, Members, and Staff to a short Screening of the award winning film
‘Genocide Revealed’  and Q&amp;amp;A
 6:30-7:30PM 26 November 2012 – Committee Room 1S4
RSVP to Senator Bilyk’s Office on 03 6229 4444 or scott.faulkner@aph.gov.au</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ювілейні Cвяткувaння в Кaнберрі</title>
      <link>https://ozeukes.com/events/act/jubilee-celebrations-in-canberra/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Aug 2012 02:43:39 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ozeukes.com/events/act/jubilee-celebrations-in-canberra/</guid>
      <description>МAРІЧКA ГAЛAБУРДA – ЧИГРИН
ЮВІЛЕЙНІ CВЯТКУВAННЯ В КAНБЕРРІ У день хрещення Русі - України, який відзначають 28 липня, у день пам’яті святого рівноапостольного великого князя Володимира, віруючі українських парафій в діяспорі, які присвячені пам’яті великого князя відзначають престольний празник.
В Україні, в Києві, вірні Української православної церкви Київського патріярхату вже кілька років проходять хресною ходою центром столиці від Володимирського собору до Володимирської гірки, де стоїть пам’ятник князя. Цього року, в суботу 28.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>