<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>International Events on AFUO - СУОА</title>
    <link>https://ozeukes.com/categories/international-events/</link>
    <description>Recent content in International Events on AFUO - СУОА</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 24 Oct 2018 02:50:07 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://ozeukes.com/categories/international-events/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Invictus Games Sydney Team Ukraine: Day One to Four Summary</title>
      <link>https://ozeukes.com/events/international-events/invictus-games-wrap-one/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Oct 2018 02:50:07 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ozeukes.com/events/international-events/invictus-games-wrap-one/</guid>
      <description>Wondering how Team Ukraine is doing? Catch up on all the Invictus Games events here, from the minute they arrived in Australia to the latest competition results.
18th OCTOBER, DAY ONE: ARRIVAL
Team Ukraine arrived early Thursday to a vibrant crowd at Sydney Airport. Zahrava Dance Ensemble performed, also giving a traditional welcome with bread and salt.

**DAY TWO: MEETING WITH LUKE FOLEY MP **Members of the team were welcomed at NSW Parliament by Luke Foley MP.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Invictus Games | Your Guide to Team Ukraine Activities</title>
      <link>https://ozeukes.com/events/invictus-games-ukraine-guide/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Oct 2018 10:26:45 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ozeukes.com/events/invictus-games-ukraine-guide/</guid>
      <description>Invictus Games is only 2 weeks away in Sydney. There are some fantastic opportunities for you, the community, to not only see Team Ukraine compete, but also meet the team members and hear their stories. **COMMUNITY EVENTS | ** **_ Інформація українською мовою | VIEW INFORMATION IN UKRAINIAN HERE_**
TEAM UKRAINE ARRIVAL SYDNEY INTERNATIONAL AIRPORT –_ 7 am THURSDAY 18.10.2018 _
Meeting place will be in forecourt outside the arrival terminal and marked by a Ukrainian flag.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>АКЦІЯ – STOP  PUTIN – STOP WAR</title>
      <link>https://ozeukes.com/events/international-events/stop-putin-stop-war/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Jan 2018 11:31:54 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ozeukes.com/events/international-events/stop-putin-stop-war/</guid>
      <description>January 19, 2018
АКЦІЯ – STOP PUTIN – STOP WAR Управа Союзу Українських Організацій Австралії (СУОА) звертає Вашу увагу на міжнародну акцію STOP PUTIN – STOP WAR, яка покликана не допустити проведення Чемпіонату світу з футболу у Росії.
22 січня пройде уже п’ятий етап акції STOP PUTIN – STOP WAR.
Її метою є намагання привернути увагу світової громадськості до Російської загарбницької війни, яка четвертий рік триває в Україні та не допустити щоб Чемпіонат світу з футболу пройшов на спортивних майданчиках країни-агресора.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>AFUO Meet and Greet with Australia’s Ambassador to Ukraine H.E. Melissa O’Rourke</title>
      <link>https://ozeukes.com/events/international-events/afuo-meet-and-greet-with-australias-ambassador-to-ukraine-h-e-melissa-orourke/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Nov 2017 22:43:15 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ozeukes.com/events/international-events/afuo-meet-and-greet-with-australias-ambassador-to-ukraine-h-e-melissa-orourke/</guid>
      <description>Video from the AFUO hosted Meet and Greet with Australia’s Ambassador to Ukraine H.E. Melissa O’Rourke with many dignitaries – 18.09.2017 – Radisson Hotel, Kyiv.
https://drive.google.com/file/d/0B3TtU45OVqMzZGs5UEpuY1VTLVE/view?ts=59fae40b</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>RUSSIA TO USE WORLD FESTIVAL OF YOUTH AND STUDENTS TO DEFY INTERNATIONAL CONVENTIONS</title>
      <link>https://ozeukes.com/events/international-events/russia-to-use-world-festival-of-youth-and-students-to-defy-international-conventions/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Sep 2017 08:12:06 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ozeukes.com/events/international-events/russia-to-use-world-festival-of-youth-and-students-to-defy-international-conventions/</guid>
      <description>September 7, 2017
MEDIA RELEASE
RUSSIA TO USE WORLD FESTIVAL OF YOUTH AND STUDENTS TO DEFY INTERNATIONAL CONVENTIONS – AFUO CALLS ON AUSTRALIAN YOUTH, STUDENTS AND GOVERNMENT TO BOYCOTT The World Festival of Youth and Students will be hosted by the Russian Federation between October 14-22, 2017. Young people from different countries have been invited.
The program of the events is scheduled to have foreign delegates visit the territory of Ukraine temporarily occupied by the armed aggressor - the Russian Federation – such as Sevastopol and Simferopol (Autonomous Republic of Crimea, Ukraine).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Австралію відвідає Президент Світового Конґресу Українців (СКУ) Евген Чолій</title>
      <link>https://ozeukes.com/events/ukrainian-world-congress-uwc-president-eugene-czolij-to-visit-australia-ukr/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Jul 2017 07:54:43 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ozeukes.com/events/ukrainian-world-congress-uwc-president-eugene-czolij-to-visit-australia-ukr/</guid>
      <description>АВСТРАЛІЮ ВІДВІДАЄ ПРЕЗИДЕНТ СВІТОВОГО КОНҐРЕСУ УКРАЇНЦІВ (СКУ) ЕВГЕН ЧОЛІЙ
Управа Союзу Українських Організацій Австралії ( СУОА ) повідомляє українську громаду що на запрошення СУОА Австралію відвідає
ПРЕЗИДЕНТ СВІТОВОГО КОНҐРЕСУ УКРАЇНЦІВ ЕВГЕН ЧОЛІЙ
Візит заплянований з нагоди відзначення 50-річчя СКУ та 70 ліття Поселення Українців в Австралії. Для ознайомлення з життям та діяльністю української діаспори на австралійському континенті пан Чолій відвідає всі українські громади.
Управа СУОА також організує зустрічі з високопосадовцями австралійського політичного та академічного світу.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ukrainian World Congress (UWC) President Eugene Czolij to visit Australia</title>
      <link>https://ozeukes.com/events/ukrainian-world-congress-uwc-president-eugene-czolij-to-visit-australia/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Jul 2017 07:47:59 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ozeukes.com/events/ukrainian-world-congress-uwc-president-eugene-czolij-to-visit-australia/</guid>
      <description>UKRAINIAN WORLD CONGRESS (UWC) PRESIDENT EUGENE CZOLIJ TO VISIT AUSTRALIA
The Australian Federation of Ukrainian Organisations is pleased to announce the planned visit to Australia of
THE PRESIDENT OF THE UKRAINIAN WORLD CONGRESS EUGENE CZOLIJ
Mr. Czolij will visit all our communities in Australia at the invitation of the AFUO to celebrate the 50th Anniversary of the UWC and 70th Anniversary of Ukrainian Settlement in Australia.
A series of meetings with senior Government officials including the Prime Minister, Minister for Foreign Affairs, other Ministers and representatives of Think Tanks and NGO’s are being planned.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Плекаємо єдність, боронимо Україну від агресора!</title>
      <link>https://ozeukes.com/events/international-events/plekayemo-yednist-boronymo-ukrayinu-vid-agresora/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 31 Jan 2017 23:00:53 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ozeukes.com/events/international-events/plekayemo-yednist-boronymo-ukrayinu-vid-agresora/</guid>
      <description>21 та 22 січня українці по всьому світові проводили заходи на підтримку єдності України та акції проти російської агресії. Акції носили назву «Україна єдина» та «Стоп Путін! Стоп війна!».
Так, акція «Стоп Путін! Стоп війна!» прокотилася земною кулею вже втретє. В заході взяли участь понад 70 міст з чотирьох десятків країн.
Вимоги світового українства залишаються незмінними: звільнення всіх громадян України, фактично взятих в заручники Кремлем та його маріонетками з так званих «днр-лнр», звільнення всіх українських територій від російських військ, повернення Криму, запровадження цілодобової спостережної місії ОБСЄ, в тому числі вздовж неконтрольованої Україною лінії кордону з РФ.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Stop Putin&#39;s War in Ukraine 3.0 - AFUO CALL TO ACTION</title>
      <link>https://ozeukes.com/events/stop-putins-war-in-ukraine-3-0-afuo-call-to-action/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Jan 2017 04:05:18 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ozeukes.com/events/stop-putins-war-in-ukraine-3-0-afuo-call-to-action/</guid>
      <description>СОЮЗ УКРАЇНСЬКИХ ОРГАНІЗАЦІЙ АВСТРАЛІЇ (СУОА)
**ЗАКЛИКАЄ **ПІДТРИМАТИ АКЦІЮ ВСЕСВІТНЬOГО РУХУ ПАТРІОТІВ УКРАЇНИ
STOP PUTIN&#39;S WAR IN UKRAINE 3.0 ЩО ВІДБУВАТИМЕТЬСЯ 21 СІЧНЯ 2017 РОКУ У 60 КРАЇНАХ СВІТУ
** **ТОЖ ЗАКЛИКАЄМО УКРАЇНСЬКУ СПІЛЬНОТУ ТА ЇЇ ПРИХИЛЬНИКІВ ДО АКТИВНОЇ УЧАСТІ
Facebook події заплановані у Сіднеї
https://www.facebook.com/events/1650151431945093/
та Мельбурні
https://www.facebook.com/events/410161919325380/</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ukraine is calling for international volunteers!</title>
      <link>https://ozeukes.com/events/international-events/ukraine-is-calling-for-international-volunteers/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Oct 2016 10:39:33 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ozeukes.com/events/international-events/ukraine-is-calling-for-international-volunteers/</guid>
      <description>Do you have or would like to get volunteer experience?
Ukraine is calling for you to participate in a new wave of English summer camps for children in 2017, including those affected by the armed conflict in Eastern Ukraine.
We are looking for English-speaking volunteers who would come to Ukraine and interact with the children in English, get great time, new friends and unforgettable experience!
As a volunteer you will get special training and opportunity to share experience in the following spheres: STEAM (Science, Technology, Engineering, Art, Mathematics), Leadership and Career, Citizenship, Sports&amp;amp;Health!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>AFUO SUPPORTS CULTURAL EXCHANGE AUSTRALIA - UKRAINE</title>
      <link>https://ozeukes.com/events/international-events/afuo-supports-cultural-exchange-australia-ukraine/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Sep 2016 04:10:28 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ozeukes.com/events/international-events/afuo-supports-cultural-exchange-australia-ukraine/</guid>
      <description>The Australian Federation of Ukrainian Organisations is financially supporting the Embassy of Australia in Kyiv Cultural Program.
Ana de la Vega, a highly regarded Australian flautist based in Berlin, will be performing at the Philharmonic in Kyiv on Monday 26 September, in concert with the Kyiv Camerata chamber orchestra. This concert will be part of the Philharmonic’s standard program season.
On Tue 27 or Wed 28 Sept, Ana will be leading a masterclass at the Tchaikovsky Musical Academy, and that evening performing a public recital at the academy.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>AUSTRALIA-UKRAINE RELATIONS FORUM TO BE HELD IN KYIV TODAY</title>
      <link>https://ozeukes.com/events/international-events/australia-ukraine-relations-forum-to-be-held-in-kyiv-today/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Aug 2016 11:49:51 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ozeukes.com/events/international-events/australia-ukraine-relations-forum-to-be-held-in-kyiv-today/</guid>
      <description>**29 August 2016 **
**_MEDIA RELEASE _**
AUSTRALIA -UKRAINE RELATIONS FORUM TO BE HELD IN KYIV TODAY BUILDING STRONGER PARTNERSHIPS The Australian Federation of Ukrainian Organisations (AFUO) is hosting the Australia - Ukraine Forum in Kyiv today, August 29, 2016.
Amongst the participants will be:
 * Ambassador of Ukraine to Australia - Mykola Kulinich * Chargé d’Affaires Australian Embassy Kyiv, Ukraine - Bruce Edwards * Acting Minister for Health - Ulyana Suprun * Chair - Foreign Affairs Committee of Verchovna Rada - Hanna Hopko * CEO – Horizon Capital – Lenna Koszarny * CEO of American Chamber of Commerce in Ukraine - Andy Hunder * Senior representatives from the Ministries of; * Foreign Affairs * Internal Affairs * Defence * Speaker’s office * Australian business people in Ukraine  and others</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>COSSACK BROTHERS at Lviv Ukrainian Dance and Cultural Festival</title>
      <link>https://ozeukes.com/events/international-events/cossack-brothers-at-lviv-ukrainian-dance-and-cultural-festival/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Jul 2016 12:48:09 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ozeukes.com/events/international-events/cossack-brothers-at-lviv-ukrainian-dance-and-cultural-festival/</guid>
      <description>Australia&#39;s Ukrainian community being represented at Lviv Ukrainian Dance and Cultural Festival by COSSACK BROTHERS ! Well done!
Брати Козаки представляють українську громаду Австралії на Фестивалі Українського Танцю і Культури у Львові! Вітаємо!
http://tvoemisto.tv/news/lviv_pryymaie_mizhnarodnyy_festyval_tantsyu_10_foto_79484.html</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>IV МІЖНАРОДНА НАУКОВО-ПРАКТИЧНА КОНФЕРЕНЦІЯ “УКРАЇНСЬКА МОВА У СВІТІ”</title>
      <link>https://ozeukes.com/events/iv-miok-conference/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Jul 2016 06:38:24 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ozeukes.com/events/iv-miok-conference/</guid>
      <description>Міжнародний інститут освіти, культури та зв’язків з діаспорою (МІОК) запрошує взяти участь у IV Міжнародній науково-практичній конференції «Українська мова у світі», яка відбудеться 9 – 10 листопада 2016 року в НУ «Львівська політехніка».
Тематичні напрями конференції:
 * _методика викладання української мови для студентів-іноземців та діаспори;_ * _особливості функціонування української мови за кордоном;_ * _мова і міграція (теоретичні аспекти);_ * _проблеми мовної адаптації внутрішньо переміщених осіб._  Офіційні мови конференції: українська, англійська.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ukrainian diaspora rejoices over Eurovision win</title>
      <link>https://ozeukes.com/events/international-events/ukrainian-diaspora-rejoices-over-eurovision-win/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 15 May 2016 03:53:07 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ozeukes.com/events/international-events/ukrainian-diaspora-rejoices-over-eurovision-win/</guid>
      <description>15 May 2016
**_MEDIA RELEASE _**
Ukrainian diaspora rejoices over Eurovision win In a victory loaded with political meaning, Ukraine’s 2016 Eurovision entrant Jamala, has taken out the coveted prize, much to Australian-Ukrainians’ delight.
The 32-year old singer is a Crimean Tatar, an ethnic group native to Ukraine’s Crimean peninsula since the 13th—17th centuries. In 1944 the Tatars were deported from Crimea by the Soviet government. Decades later they later returned to their homeland but have experienced renewed ethnic tension since the Russian Federation’s annexation of Crimea in 2014.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>World&#39;s largest aircraft Ukrainian &#39;Mriya&#39; set to land in Perth</title>
      <link>https://ozeukes.com/events/western-australia/worlds-largest-aircraft-ukrainian-mriya-set-to-land-in-perth/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 14 May 2016 10:59:30 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ozeukes.com/events/western-australia/worlds-largest-aircraft-ukrainian-mriya-set-to-land-in-perth/</guid>
      <description>14 May 2016
MEDIA RELEASE World’s largest aircraft Ukrainian ‘Mriya’ set to land in Perth On Sunday 15 May at 10am (WST) the Antonov An-225 ‘Mriya’ will make its first-ever trip to Australia when it lands at Perth airport to deliver a generator weighing 130 tons.
Arriving at its final destination of a journey spanning three continents, the crew will be welcomed by Ukraine’s Ambassador to Australia, His Excellency Mykola Kulinich, and Chairman of the Australian Federation of Ukrainian Organisations (AFUO) and General secretary of the Ukrainian World Congress, Mr.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ВІДЗНАЧЕННЯ ДРУГОЇ РІЧНИЦІ РЕВОЛЮЦІЇ ГІДНОСТІ</title>
      <link>https://ozeukes.com/events/international-events/the-revolution-of-dignity-remember-reflect-committ/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Feb 2016 10:35:15 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ozeukes.com/events/international-events/the-revolution-of-dignity-remember-reflect-committ/</guid>
      <description>**20 **лютого 2016
ОБІЖНИК СУОА
Ч. 3. 2015 – 2018
** **ВІДЗНАЧЕННЯ ДРУГОЇ РІЧНИЦІ РЕВОЛЮЦІЇ ГІДНОСТІ
Тими днями будемо відзначувати 2-гу річницю Революції Гідності.
Будемо пам’ятати всіх поляглих – Небесну Сотню та багато інших, які віддали своє життя.
Мабуть в цей час не потрібно багато слів.
Треба лише застановитися, рефлектувати та собі обіцяти, що не віддамо Україну в руки Путіна або в руки корупціонерів ані зрадників.
Нашим святим обов’язком - Іти до перемоги – Добро над злом!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>УКРАЇНА ВІДКРИТА ДЛЯ АВСТРАЛІЇ</title>
      <link>https://ozeukes.com/events/international-events/ukrayina-vidkrita-dlya-avstraliyi/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Dec 2015 01:16:31 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ozeukes.com/events/international-events/ukrayina-vidkrita-dlya-avstraliyi/</guid>
      <description>Богдан Рудницький веде розмову із паном Геннадієм Кравцем. Пан Кравець - один з організаторів із України українсько-австралійського двостороннього форум OzUke 2015. Він - власник і директор «Еталон Студії - міжнародні проекти» та &amp;ldquo;Міжнародний проект «Нові ринки». Він бере участь у двосторонніх і багатосторонніх проектах і забезпечує звукову і візуальну продукцію. Пан Кравець має понад 15 років досвіду з міжнародної співпраці з офіційною підтримкою від урядових установ, впливових державних діячів і численних представників ділових кіл з 27-ми країн на 5-ти континентах&amp;hellip;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>AFUO announces sponsors of the inaugural Australia-Ukraine bilateral forum OzUke 2015</title>
      <link>https://ozeukes.com/events/afuo-announces-sponsors-of-the-inaugural-australia-ukraine-bilateral-forum-ozuke-2015/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Nov 2015 11:17:29 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ozeukes.com/events/afuo-announces-sponsors-of-the-inaugural-australia-ukraine-bilateral-forum-ozuke-2015/</guid>
      <description>November 5, 2015
MEDIA RELEASE AFUO ANNOUNCES SPONSORS OF THE INAUGURAL AUSTRALIA-UKRAINE BILATERAL FORUM OzUKE2015 Melbourne 25-26 November 2015 The Australian Federation of Ukrainian Organisations (AFUO) is pleased to announce our major sponsors for the OzUke 2015 Inaugural Australia Ukraine Business Forum.
The Forum is being organised by the AFUO in partnership with the newly formed Australia-Ukraine Chamber of Commerce.
Apart from the AFUO which will provide close to $20000 to the forum our **MAJOR PLATINUM SPONSOR is MIMIVIC GROUP INDUSTRIAL DEVELOPERS **Victor and Marijka Rudewych will contribute $20,000 to the Forum.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Фoрум украïнськoï мoлoдi дiаспoри ОДЕСА 2015</title>
      <link>https://ozeukes.com/events/fumd-odesa-2015/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 14 Jun 2015 21:02:08 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ozeukes.com/events/fumd-odesa-2015/</guid>
      <description>Шанoвні українці Австралії,
Свiтoвий Кoнґрес Украïнських Мoлoдiжних Органiзацiй (СКУМО), 19-28 серпня 2015 р. oрганiзoвує Фoрум украïнськoï мoлoдi дiаспoри ОДЕСА 2015 (ФУМД), який складатиметься з трьoх частин -&amp;gt; Табiр мoлoдi дiаспoри (19-25 серпня) та Рiчнi Збoри СКУМО i Дiаспoра Фест (26-28 серпня). 1. Щoдo Табoру украïнськoï мoлoдi дiаспoри, чекаємo прoпoзицiï дo прoграми. Якi лекцiï, тренiнги, майстер класи та нефoрмальну прoграму прoпoнуєте? Вiк учасникiв 18-35 р., кoжний кандидат пoвинен oтримати рекoмендацiйнoгo листа вiд украïнськoï oрганiзацiï закoрдoнoм Всi учасники пoвнiстю забеспечинi прoживанням, харчуванням та видповидною прoграмoю.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Community gathering with  Hanna Hopko - Зустріч з  Ганною Гопко</title>
      <link>https://ozeukes.com/events/community-gathering-with-hanna-hopko/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Jun 2015 11:33:11 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ozeukes.com/events/community-gathering-with-hanna-hopko/</guid>
      <description>Australian Federation of Ukrainian Organisations ** Association of Ukrainians in Victoria**
Invites you to a community gathering with
Hanna Hopko Chair of the Committee on Foreign Affairs

Союз Українських Організацій Австралії Українська Громада Вікторії
запрошує Українську Громаду на зустріч з
Ганною Гопко Голова Комітету у закордонних справах</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Inaugural Ukraine-Australia Bilateral NGO / B2B Conference Series to be held in late 2015 in Melbourne and Kyiv - OzUkes2015</title>
      <link>https://ozeukes.com/events/international-events/inaugural-ukraine-australia-bilateral-ngo-b2b-conference/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Apr 2015 01:24:32 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ozeukes.com/events/international-events/inaugural-ukraine-australia-bilateral-ngo-b2b-conference/</guid>
      <description>MEDIA RELEASE
COMMUNITY-BASED ORGANISATIONS WORK FOR AUSTRALIA-UKRAINE TIES – INAUGURAL BILATERAL CONFERENCE TO BE HELD
An inaugural Ukraine/Australia relations conference series will be held in late 2015 on the initiative of the Australian Federation of Ukrainian Organisations (AFUO) and Centre UA.
_OzUke2015 _will be a bilateral event at the NGO level to promote greater bilateralism between Australia and Ukraine in a new era of cooperation.
Stefan Romaniw, President of AFUO, the peak body for the Ukrainian Australian community, said: “Now is the time to build greater ties between Ukrainian society and Australian society for the benefit of both.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>AFUO YouTube Channel</title>
      <link>https://ozeukes.com/events/international-events/afuo-youtube-channel-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Apr 2015 01:34:17 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ozeukes.com/events/international-events/afuo-youtube-channel-2/</guid>
      <description>**AFUO met the Deputy Head of the foreign affairs committee **
The AFUO delegation and World Congress of Ukrainian representatives met Ms Hanna Hopko, People’s Deputy and Chair of the Ukrainian parliament’s (Rada) Foreign Affairs Committee. Discussion focussed on building better ties by expediting the process of appointing an Ambassador to Australia, dropping the WTO case against Australia, and creating community-based structures for information campaigns to promote Ukraine’s standing abroad. Ms Hopko is clearly a strong up-and-comer in Ukrainian parliamentary politics who is results-focused.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>AFUO YouTube Channel</title>
      <link>https://ozeukes.com/events/international-events/afuo-youtube-channel/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 29 Mar 2015 21:57:14 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ozeukes.com/events/international-events/afuo-youtube-channel/</guid>
      <description>From now, community members and our friends can follow news from AFUO on our new YouTube channel.
This includes the latest updates and news from the AFUO&#39;s current delegation in Ukraine.
AFUO started exchange program between Australian universities and Kyiv Mohyla Academy students
[embed]https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=icAOXxh7wnI[/embed]
**Meeting in the Ukrainian Chamber of commerce and industry **
[embed]https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=F6BwCRfHwp4[/embed]
Meeting with ministry of education of Ukraine
https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=yrJI9cxsQbo
**Economy relationship between Australia and Ukraine is under special commission control **</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Подяка від Захисту патріотів / Thank you from Patriot Defence</title>
      <link>https://ozeukes.com/events/international-events/thank-you-from-patriot-defence/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Mar 2015 10:17:03 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ozeukes.com/events/international-events/thank-you-from-patriot-defence/</guid>
      <description>AUFO U-HELP works in tandem with the Patriot Defence CУОA - U-HELP співпрацює з програмою Захист Патріотів
10 березня 2015 року
Дорогі друзі «Захисту патріотів»,
Дев’ять місяців минуло з моменту заснування гуманітарної ініціативи Світового Конгресу Українців «Захист патріотів». Пройшло 282 днів з моменту організації першого тренування 1 червня 2014 року. За цей проміжок часу ми навчили більше 12 814 бійців за адаптованим курсом Бійця-рятувальника, та роздали понад 10 222 індивідуальних аптечок (IFAK), відбулося 175 навчальних виїздів і проведено понад 220 навчальних сесій у більше ніж 75 локаціях по всій Україні.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>KAZKA coming soon</title>
      <link>https://ozeukes.com/events/kazka-coming-soon/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Feb 2015 20:01:45 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ozeukes.com/events/kazka-coming-soon/</guid>
      <description>Lehenda Ukrainian Dance Company is thrilled to launch the international tour of its exciting new dance production KAZKA, an original folk ballet inspired by Ukrainian fairy tales.
For further information visit www.lehenda.com.au/kazka</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>EABC Business Roundtable with Petro Poroshenko - PHOTO GALLERY</title>
      <link>https://ozeukes.com/events/international-events/eabc-business-roundtable-with-petro-poroshenko/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Dec 2014 10:17:48 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ozeukes.com/events/international-events/eabc-business-roundtable-with-petro-poroshenko/</guid>
      <description>PHOTO GALLERY EABC Business Roundtable with His Excellency Mr Petro Poroshenko, President of Ukraine 12 December 2014, Sydney
On Friday 12 December the Council was honoured to host a Business Roundtable in partnership with Thales Australia on the occasion of the visit of HE Mr Petro Poroshenko, President of Ukraine.
The Council very much appreciates this opportunity and hope there are opportunities to follow this up with a visit to Ukraine in the future.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PUTIN DOES NOT DESERVE TO BE AT G20</title>
      <link>https://ozeukes.com/events/international-events/afuo-media-release-putin-does-not-deserve-to-be-at-g20/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Oct 2014 21:46:58 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ozeukes.com/events/international-events/afuo-media-release-putin-does-not-deserve-to-be-at-g20/</guid>
      <description>The Australian Federation of Ukrainian Organisations (AFUO) abhors the allowing of Vladimir Putin to the G20 Leaders Summit in Brisbane in November.
“In the future, world leaders will greatly regret appeasing Putin – the greatest threat to international order and prosperity and Western values. It is a huge mistake, as Putin has repeatedly shown that he will take a marathon when given a millimetre,” Mr Stefan Romaniw OAM, AFUO President, said.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>AFUO Media Release: Putin grabs more of Ukraine / Australia needs to do more</title>
      <link>https://ozeukes.com/events/international-events/afuo-media-release-putin-grabs-more-of-ukraine-australia-needs-to-do-more/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 Apr 2014 02:41:41 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ozeukes.com/events/international-events/afuo-media-release-putin-grabs-more-of-ukraine-australia-needs-to-do-more/</guid>
      <description>The Australian Federation of Ukrainian Organisations (AFUO) has issued a media release regarding the latest attempts by the Putin regime to make further aggressive incursions into Ukraine. The statement also calls upon the Australian government to make more concerted actions to condemn these internationally illegal activities by the Russian government.  Media statement: AFUO Media Release on Donetsk intervention
In addition, the AFUO has written directly to the Minister for Foreign Affairs, the Hon.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Світове відзначення 200-ліття з дня народження Тараса Шевченка</title>
      <link>https://ozeukes.com/events/international-events/world-celebration-of-taras-shevchenko-200-anniversary-of-birth/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Mar 2014 01:39:48 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ozeukes.com/events/international-events/world-celebration-of-taras-shevchenko-200-anniversary-of-birth/</guid>
      <description>Світова комісія з відзначення 200-ліття з дня народження Тараса Шевченка при Світовому Конґресі Українців (СКУ) закликає всю українську діаспору 9 березня 2014 р. гідно вшанувати Великого Шевченка та разом з цим схилити голови перед світлою пам’яттю полеглих Героїв Небесної сотні.
Подається повністю листа від СКУ в в цій справі, та в якому є параметри як висилати відеокліпи на 5 канал відносно вшанування 200-ліття з дня народження Т. Шевченка. 
28 лютого 2014 р.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>EuroMaidan – A Video Overview</title>
      <link>https://ozeukes.com/events/international-events/euromaidan-a-video-overview/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Feb 2014 05:57:12 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ozeukes.com/events/international-events/euromaidan-a-video-overview/</guid>
      <description>[ ](http://www.ozeukes.com/wp-content/uploads/2014/02/Kyiv-Maidan.jpg)**EuroMaidan - An Overview of the Crisis in Ukraine **
First aired at the EuroMaidan Rally in Sydney on 2nd February 2014 Compiled by: Andrew Duma
ЄвроМайдан - короткий перегляд кризи на Україні Вперше висвітлене в Сіднеї на мітинґу 2 лютого 2014 року на підтримку ЄвроМайдану Упорядник: Aндрій Дума
 </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Преcове повідомлення - Уряд Aвстралії висловив уряду України занепокоєння</title>
      <link>https://ozeukes.com/events/international-events/press-release-australian-govt-expresses-concerns-to-ukrainian-govt/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Jan 2014 00:47:01 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ozeukes.com/events/international-events/press-release-australian-govt-expresses-concerns-to-ukrainian-govt/</guid>
      <description>25 січня 2014
ПРЕCОВЕ ПОВІДОМЛЕННЯ Уряд Aвстралії офіційно висловив уряду України глибоке занепокоєння та стурбованість Посадовці Міністерства закордонних справ Австралії за підтримки міністра закордонних справ Джулі Бішоп офіційно висловили уряду України глибоке занепокоєння уряду Австралії недавніми актами насильства та зіткненнями між протестувальниками та силовиками в Україні.
Тимчасовoго повіреного у справах України в Австралії Станіслава Сташевського було запрошено на зустріч з ключовими австралійськими посадовцями для передачі цього повідомлення.
Уряд Австралії висловив стурбованість у зв&#39;язку зі смертю та зникненням протестувальників і заявив, що винні мають бути притягнуті до відповідальності.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Media Release - Australian Gov’t Calls in Ukraine Embassy</title>
      <link>https://ozeukes.com/events/international-events/media-release-australian-govt-calls-in-ukraine-embassy/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 25 Jan 2014 01:30:38 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ozeukes.com/events/international-events/media-release-australian-govt-calls-in-ukraine-embassy/</guid>
      <description>The Australian Federation of Ukrainian Organisations (AFUO) has been advised that the Australian Ministry of Foreign Affairs has officially conveyed its deep concerns regarding recent events in Ukraine. The following statement has been released by the AFUO:
 
 MEDIA RELEASE
  AUSTRALIAN GOVERNMENT CALLS IN UKRAINE EMBASSY TO OBJECT TO VIOLENCE – DFAT ADVICE
 Senior Australian diplomats acting for the Minister of Foreign Affairs Julie Bishop MP have officially conveyed the Australian Government&#39;s deep concern about recent violent clashes in Kyiv to the Government of Ukraine, according to the AFUO.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Заклик ввести санкції проти режиму Януковича</title>
      <link>https://ozeukes.com/events/international-events/call-for-sanctions-against-the-yanukovych-regime/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 19 Dec 2013 02:04:36 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ozeukes.com/events/international-events/call-for-sanctions-against-the-yanukovych-regime/</guid>
      <description>Стефан Романів: Закликаємо Світ ввести санкції проти режиму Януковича «Світовий Конгрес Українців через українські громади в різних країнах ЄС, Америки, а також Австралії буде звертатися до урядовців цих країн з вимогою вводити персональні санкції до чиновників та бізнесменів, що вчинили незаконні дії щодо учасників Євромайданів в Україні».
Про це заявив Генеральний Секретар Світвого Конгресу Українців, Голова Організації Українських Націоналістів (бандерівців) Стефан Романів під час брифінгу в прес-центрі Штабу Національного Спротиву.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Чому українці вийшли на мирний протест / What Ukraine’s protest is about</title>
      <link>https://ozeukes.com/events/international-events/what-ukraines-protest-is-about/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Dec 2013 09:26:53 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ozeukes.com/events/international-events/what-ukraines-protest-is-about/</guid>
      <description>[ ](http://www.ozeukes.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/12/Ukraine-protest01.jpg)ЧОМУ УКРАЇНЦІ ВИЙШЛИ НА МИРНИЙ ПРОТЕСТ
Організатори Євромайдану в Києві подали коротку інформацію про події в Україні для масового розповсюдження. Подається тут ці інформації українською мовою: Lystivka_UKR
What Ukraine’s protest is about The organizers of the continuing mass protest movement “EuroMaidan” in Ukraine have issued a statement regarding the reasons for the actions. The English-language text of the statement can be read here: Lystivka_ENG
Note: The term “EuroMaidan” is derived from two parts</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Про відмову уряда України від Асоціації з Євросоюзом</title>
      <link>https://ozeukes.com/events/international-events/ukraines-suspension-of-the-european-union-association-agreement/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Nov 2013 01:53:54 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ozeukes.com/events/international-events/ukraines-suspension-of-the-european-union-association-agreement/</guid>
      <description>[ ](http://www.ozeukes.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/11/Ukraine-EU.jpg)Про відмову уряда України від Асоціації з Євросоюзом
Cоюз Українських Організацій Aвстралії (СУОА) закликає українців Австралії протестувати проти відмову уряда України від Асоціації з Євросоюзом та пітримувати світові акції які наголошують, що Україна це Європа.
Подається копію листа: UKRAINE -EUROPE (2) 20131125
Заплановані акціії: Мельбурн: Віче в центрі Мельбурну в четвер 27-го листопада 2013 від 4:00 год. пп. (детальніше буде подано)
Сідней: Віче в центрі Сіднею в четвер 27-го листопада 2013 (детальніше буде подано)</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ВІДЗНAЧЕННЯ ЖЕРТОВНОCТІ ВІКТОРA ТA МAРІЙКИ РУДЕВИЧ</title>
      <link>https://ozeukes.com/events/international-events/recognising-the-generosity-of-victor-and-marijka-rudewych/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 07 Sep 2013 00:34:43 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ozeukes.com/events/international-events/recognising-the-generosity-of-victor-and-marijka-rudewych/</guid>
      <description>**ВІДЗНAЧЕННЯ ЖЕРТОВНОCТІ ВІКТОРA ТA МAРІЙКИ РУДЕВИЧ НA ПІДТРИМКУ В УКРAЇНІ ТA ДІЯCПОРІ**
Віктор і Марійка Рудевич є добре знані жертводавці в Aвстралії.
Протягом довгих років вони жертвували і далі жертвують на різні цілі – Церкви (УГКЦ і УAПЦ), Українську громаду Вікторії – централю та філії, «Дністер», Кредитну Кооперативу, Дім Cтарших, Оселю CУМ «Карпати», українське шкільництво, лекторат україністики ім. Зерова в університеті Монаша, УГВ Клуб Ґольфу. Крім цього вони допомагали та спонсорували різні заняття, імпрези.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Учні з Сіднею (Австралія) завітали до дрогобицької школи</title>
      <link>https://ozeukes.com/events/international-events/sydney-ukrainian-students-visit-drohobych/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 07 Jul 2013 05:14:21 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ozeukes.com/events/international-events/sydney-ukrainian-students-visit-drohobych/</guid>
      <description>1-го липня 2013 року завітали до дрогобицької загальноосвітньої школи № 1 учні суботньої української школи з Сіднею (Австралія), а також дорослі представники української діаспори. Такі зустрічі вже стали традиційними, тобто відбуваються щороку.
Управа CУОA вітає керівництво та студентів Української Братської Школи ім Aндрея з Cіднею з їхньою мандрівкою по Україні та бажаємо щасливої подорожі.
Детальніше - читайте на сайті &amp;ldquo;Дрогобич Інфо&amp;rdquo;: http://droginfo.com.ua/ content/view/4759/
Є і відео: http://www.youtube.com/user/TheYouFed/videos?sort=dd&amp;amp;view=0&amp;amp;tag_id=&amp;amp;shelf_index=0</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Збірка нa підтримку виборчо-спостережної Міcії CКУ</title>
      <link>https://ozeukes.com/events/international-events/support-for-uwc-election-monitoring-mission/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Aug 2012 07:58:40 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ozeukes.com/events/international-events/support-for-uwc-election-monitoring-mission/</guid>
      <description>Союз Українських Організацій Австралії (СУОА) випустив зaклик до фінaнcової збірки нa підтримку виборчо-спостережної міcії CКУ (Світовий Конґрес Українців) підчас виборів до Верховної Ради Укрaїни в 2012р.
The Australian Federation of Ukrainian Organisations (AFUO) has issued a call to action requesting financial support from Ukrainian community in Australia to fund the Ukrainian World Congress (UWC) election monitoring mission in Ukraine for the 2012 parliamentary elections.

22-серпня 2012
ЗAКЛИК ДО ФІНAНCОВОЇ ЗБІРКИ НA ПІДТРИМКУ ВИБОРЧУ МІCІЮ CКУ УКРAЇНA 2012</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>2012 Elections in Ukraine</title>
      <link>https://ozeukes.com/events/international-events/2012-elections-in-ukraine/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Aug 2012 03:46:07 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ozeukes.com/events/international-events/2012-elections-in-ukraine/</guid>
      <description>2012 Elections in Ukraine The 2012 elections to the Ukrainian Parliament, Verkhovna Rada, are due to be held on October 28, 2012. The elections will use a mixed voting system (50% under party lists and 50% under simple-majority constituencies).
In accordance with previous elections held in Ukraine, observers from foreign states and international organizations will monitor the election process. A handbook for official observers has been issued by the Ministry of Foreign Affairs of Ukraine.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Victorian Minister Meets Ukrainian Government Officials in Kyiv</title>
      <link>https://ozeukes.com/events/international-events/victorian-minister-meets-ukrainian-government-officials-in-kyiv/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 31 Jul 2012 11:16:41 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ozeukes.com/events/international-events/victorian-minister-meets-ukrainian-government-officials-in-kyiv/</guid>
      <description>Tuesday July 31, 2012
For Immediate release
MEDIA RELEASE VICTORIAN PLANNING MINISTER MATTHEW GUY MEETS WITH UKRAINIAN GOVERNMENT OFFICIALS IN KYIV ** **Kyiv - Victoria&#39;s State Planning Minister Matthew Guy and Australian Federation of Ukrainian Organisations Chairman Stefan Romaniw, today met with Ukraine&#39;s Deputy Foreign Minister Ruslan Demchenko and Deputy Minister for Culture Yurij Bohutski .
[caption id=&amp;quot;attachment_5506&amp;rdquo; align=&amp;quot;alignnone&amp;rdquo; width=&amp;quot;600&amp;rdquo;] Left to right: Stefan Romaniw, Ruslan Demchenko, Matthew Guy, Yurij Bohutski[/caption]</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Лиcти укрaїнcьких організацій в Aвcтрaлії в справі закону про мову</title>
      <link>https://ozeukes.com/events/international-events/protest-letters-against-language-bill/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Jul 2012 02:58:03 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ozeukes.com/events/international-events/protest-letters-against-language-bill/</guid>
      <description>Декілька укрaїнcьких організацій в Aвcтрaлії написали протестаційні листи проти антиконcтитaційного зaкону щодо мови. Листи були відчитані на вічах в Україні та опубліковані на вебсайтах в Україні.
Копії протестаційних листів:
 * Cоюз Українських Організацій Aвстралії (CУОA): [MOVA - VIDKRYTYJ LYST](http://www.ozeukes.com/wp-content/uploads/2012/07/MOVA-VIDKRYTYJ-LYST.pdf) * Спілка Української Молоді в Австралії (КУ CУМ): [KY CYM Statement re Language Zakon in Ukraine July 2012](http://www.ozeukes.com/wp-content/uploads/2012/07/KY-CYM-Statement-re-Language-Zakon-in-Ukraine-July-2012.pdf) * Союз Українок Австралії (CУA): [CYA](http://www.ozeukes.com/wp-content/uploads/2012/07/CYA.pdf) * Ліга Вільної України (ЛВУ): [LVU](http://www.ozeukes.com/wp-content/uploads/2012/07/LVU.pdf) * Епархіяльна Пасторальна Рада Української Греко-Католицької Церкви в Австралії (ЕПР): [EPC](http://www.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ПAМ’ЯТНИК ТAРACОВІ ЧУПРИНЦІ</title>
      <link>https://ozeukes.com/events/international-events/taras-chuprynka-memorial/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Jul 2012 10:14:15 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ozeukes.com/events/international-events/taras-chuprynka-memorial/</guid>
      <description>**_МAРІЧКA ГAЛAБУРДA-ЧИГРИН_**
За матеріялами пресової агенції Інтерфакс, Кореспондент нет. Знимки Вaсиль Завалка
В КAЛУШІ ВІДCЛОНИЛИ ПAМ’ЯТНИК ТAРACОВІ ЧУПРИНЦІ
В суботу 30 – го червня 2012 року в годині 11 іи ранку ( в Cіднеї була 6 година вечора) з нагоди 105-річчя від дня народження Романа Шухевича, головного командира Української Повстанської Aрмії (Тарас Чупринка) відкрили в місті Калуш (Івано-Франківська обл.)
На площі біля центру художньої творчості дітей та молоді на вулиці Сивецькій Право відкрити пам’ятник надали міському голові Калуша Ігореві Насаликові, синові Шухевича, Героєві України Юрієві Шухевичеві, заступникові голови Івано-Франківської обладміністрації Романові Іваницькому, голові Калуської станиці Братства вояків ОУН-УПА Степанові Петрашові та голові Калуської райради Василеві Дзундзі.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Захист української мови / Defence of the Ukrainian language</title>
      <link>https://ozeukes.com/events/international-events/defence-of-the-ukrainian-language/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 Jun 2012 00:46:50 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ozeukes.com/events/international-events/defence-of-the-ukrainian-language/</guid>
      <description>Захист української мови Конференція Українських Державницьких Організацій Канади (КУДОК) висловила протест проти прийняття законопроекту “Про засади державної мовної політики”, ухвалений Верховною Радою України в першому читанні 5 червня 2012 р.
Повний текст (українською мовою) цєї заяви можна прочитати тут: Petition on Ukrainian language CCSU (Ukr)
Заяву-Петицію можна підтримати своїм підписом цього документа «он-лайн» на: http://www.lucorg.com/signature.php?signature_id=10/ua

Defence of the Ukrainian language The Canadian Conference in Support of Ukraine (CCSU) has expressed a resolute protest against the adoption of the first reading to the draft law on the Principles of State Language Policy that took place in the Parliament of Ukraine on June 5, 2012.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>UEFA EURO 2012 Information</title>
      <link>https://ozeukes.com/events/international-events/uefa-euro-2012-information/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 31 May 2012 02:46:14 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ozeukes.com/events/international-events/uefa-euro-2012-information/</guid>
      <description>UEFA EURO 2012 – Video Clips
In the build up to the EURO 2012 European Football Championship, which will take place in Poland and Ukraine from June 8 to July 1, a number of video clips have been released which can be viewed on the internet.
У підготовці до чемпіонату Європи 2012 року (Євро 2012), який відбудеться в Польщі та Україні від 8-го червня до 1-го липня, випущено декілька відеокліпів почерез інтернет.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ukraine squad for EURO 2012</title>
      <link>https://ozeukes.com/events/international-events/ukraine-squad-for-euro-2012/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 31 May 2012 02:41:18 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ozeukes.com/events/international-events/ukraine-squad-for-euro-2012/</guid>
      <description>**Ukrainian squad for EURO 2012**
The 23-man squad who will represent Ukraine during the finals of the EURO 2012 European Football Championship, which will take place in Poland and Ukraine from June 8 to July 1, has been named by the head coach of Ukraine&#39;s national football team, Oleh Blokhin.
Спискок команди на чемпіонат Європи 2012 року
Головний тренер збірної України з футболу Олег Блохін назазначив які футболісти потрапали в спискок команди на чемпіонат Європи 2012 року (Євро 2012), який відбудеться в Польщі та Україні від 8-го червня до 1-го липня.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Заява Світової Конференції Українських Державницьких Організацій / Statement from the International Conference in Support of Ukraine</title>
      <link>https://ozeukes.com/events/international-events/%d0%97%d0%b0%d1%8f%d0%b2%d0%b0-%d0%a1%d0%b2%d1%96%d1%82%d0%be%d0%b2%d0%be%d1%97-%d0%9a%d0%be%d0%bd%d1%84%d0%b5%d1%80%d0%b5%d0%bd%d1%86%d1%96%d1%97-%d0%a3%d0%ba%d1%80%d0%b0%d1%97%d0%bd%d1%81%d1%8c/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 May 2012 04:16:07 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ozeukes.com/events/international-events/%d0%97%d0%b0%d1%8f%d0%b2%d0%b0-%d0%a1%d0%b2%d1%96%d1%82%d0%be%d0%b2%d0%be%d1%97-%d0%9a%d0%be%d0%bd%d1%84%d0%b5%d1%80%d0%b5%d0%bd%d1%86%d1%96%d1%97-%d0%a3%d0%ba%d1%80%d0%b0%d1%97%d0%bd%d1%81%d1%8c/</guid>
      <description>19 травня 2012 р. в Чікаґо була влаштована конференція п.н. «Оцінка відносин між Україною і НАТО напередодні Саміту НАТО». Президенти Північноамериканських членів-організацій Світової Конференції Українських Державницьких Організацій видали заяву: Statement from Intl Conference on NATO-Ukraine Summit Ukrainian language
A conference was held on May 19, 2012 in Chicago titled “Assessing Ukraine/NATO Relations on the Eve of the Chicago NATO Summit”. The attached statement was issued by the Presidents of the North American member organizations of the International Conference in Support of Ukraine: Statement from Intl Conference on NATO-Ukraine Summit English language</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>МІЖНАРОДНИЙ КОНКУРС З УКРАЇНСЬКОЇ МОВИ ІМ. ПЕТРА ЯЦИКА  В АВСТРАЛІЇ 2012 р.</title>
      <link>https://ozeukes.com/events/%d0%9c%d0%86%d0%96%d0%9d%d0%90%d0%a0%d0%9e%d0%94%d0%9d%d0%98%d0%99-%d0%9a%d0%9e%d0%9d%d0%9a%d0%a3%d0%a0%d0%a1-%d0%97-%d0%a3%d0%9a%d0%a0%d0%90%d0%87%d0%9d%d0%a1%d0%ac%d0%9a%d0%9e%d0%87-%d0%9c%d0%9e/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Apr 2012 05:18:08 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ozeukes.com/events/%d0%9c%d0%86%d0%96%d0%9d%d0%90%d0%a0%d0%9e%d0%94%d0%9d%d0%98%d0%99-%d0%9a%d0%9e%d0%9d%d0%9a%d0%a3%d0%a0%d0%a1-%d0%97-%d0%a3%d0%9a%d0%a0%d0%90%d0%87%d0%9d%d0%a1%d0%ac%d0%9a%d0%9e%d0%87-%d0%9c%d0%9e/</guid>
      <description>Центр україністики ім. Миколи Зерова, Університет ім. Монаша
та Українська Центральна Шкільна Рада Австралії
**МІЖНАРОДНИЙ КОНКУРС З УКРАЇНСЬКОЇ МОВИ ІМ. ПЕТРА ЯЦИКА В АВСТРАЛІЇ **
Субота 26-го травня 2012 р.
 10.30 – 12.00 (східні штати Австралії))
10.00 – 11.30 (Південна Австралія та Північна Територія)
8.30 – 10.00 (Західна Австралія)
Завдання конкурсу – заохочувати дітей та молодих людей в Україні та по всьому світі вивчати українську мови та користуватися нею.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Jacyk International Ukrainian Language Competition in Australia</title>
      <link>https://ozeukes.com/events/jacyk-international-ukrainian-language-competition-in-australia/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Apr 2012 05:12:57 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ozeukes.com/events/jacyk-international-ukrainian-language-competition-in-australia/</guid>
      <description>Mykola Zerov Centre for Ukrainian Studies, Monash University
and
the Ukrainian Education Council of Australia
PETRO JACYK INTERNATIONAL UKRAINIAN LANGUAGE COMPETITION:
AUSTRALIA-WIDE COMPETITION 2012
 Saturday 26 May 2012:
10.30 a.m - 12:00 noon (Eastern States)
10.00 a.m - 11.30 a.m (South Australia and Northern Territory)
8.30 a.m - 10.00 a.m (Western Australia)
The competition promotes the knowledge and use of the Ukrainian language among children, teenagers and young adults in Ukraine and throughout the world.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Easter Greetings / Великоднє вітання</title>
      <link>https://ozeukes.com/events/international-events/easter-greetings-2012/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Apr 2012 01:01:33 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ozeukes.com/events/international-events/easter-greetings-2012/</guid>
      <description>Великоднє вітання З нагоди найбільшого християнського свята, Воскресіння Христового, Союз Українських Організацій Австралії (СУОА) щиро вітає усіх Iєрархів та духовенствo українських Церков, представників Дипломатичної служби України в Aвстралії, членів CУОA та організацій, та українців в Австралії, в Україні і в діаспорі.
Воскресіння Ісуса Христа cимволізує перемогу життя над смертю, добра над злом та світла над пітьмою, то хай цей величний день наповнює нас духовною піднесеністю і радістю та зміцнює віру в краще майбутнє.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Easter Webcast</title>
      <link>https://ozeukes.com/events/international-events/easter-webcast/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Apr 2012 03:12:16 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ozeukes.com/events/international-events/easter-webcast/</guid>
      <description>[ ](http://www.ozeukes.com/wp-content/uploads/2012/04/JS05-17-thumb.jpg)
Великодні Богослуження на &amp;ldquo;вебкасті&amp;rdquo;  Цього року Великодні Богослужіння з Української Греко-Католицької катедри Святих Верховних Апостолів Петра і Павла в Мельбурні будуть показуватися у прямому ефірі у системі &amp;ldquo;вебкаст&amp;rdquo; Воскресна Утреня буде показуватися у суботу 14 квітня від години 6 вечора Мельбурнський час по адресу http://www.eventwebcasting.com.au/stream.php?id=107.
Часи в інших частин світу:
Часи в інших частин світу:
 * Український старечий дім &amp;quot;Калина care&amp;quot; * Українська Кооператива «Дністер»   +++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>2012 International Mother Language Day</title>
      <link>https://ozeukes.com/events/international-events/2012-international-mother-language-day/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Feb 2012 01:56:05 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ozeukes.com/events/international-events/2012-international-mother-language-day/</guid>
      <description>**** **COMMUNITY LANGUAGES AUSTRALIA ****_Where language and culture come together _**185 Faraday Street Carlton. Victoria 3053 Tel (03) 9347 0379 Fax: (03) 9347 0297 Email: afesa@netsol.net.au www.communitylanguagesaustralia.org.au
 Languages Australia sends it heartiest greetings on the occasion of the 2012 International Mother Language Day:
 This is good time for us to reflect on the importance of language, the processes of maintaining and promoting languages education.
 To our all students, teacher, parents, community workers and policy makers we trust you will have a wonderful day- feeling positive about the fact that you are the custodians of your mother tongue and you have in sense a responsibility to pass on the baton in the future.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>HEARING ON OPENING AUSTRALIAN EMBASSY IN KYIV</title>
      <link>https://ozeukes.com/events/international-events/hearing-on-opening-australian-embassy-in-kyiv/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Feb 2012 04:56:05 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ozeukes.com/events/international-events/hearing-on-opening-australian-embassy-in-kyiv/</guid>
      <description>On Friday February 17, 2012 the Chargé d&#39;affaires of the Embassy of Ukraine in Canberra, Mr Stanislav Stashevskyi and Australian Federation of Ukrainian Organisations (AFUO) Chairman, Stefan Romaniw OAM, gave evidence at a Parliamentary Hearing of the Sub-Committee, (chaired by MP Mr. Nick Champion MP ) of the Joint Standing Committee on Foreign Affairs, Defence and Trade Foreign Affairs.
В п&#39;ятниця 17-го лютого 2012 р. тимчасовий повірений у справах України в Австралії та Новій Зеландії - Станіслав Сташевський - та голова Союзу Українських Організацій Австралії (СУОА) – Стефан Романів – подали свідчення перед парламентським під-комітетом в справах Закордонних Справ.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>HOPAK IN THE PARK 2012</title>
      <link>https://ozeukes.com/events/victoria/hopak-in-the-park-2012/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 31 Jan 2012 00:43:17 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ozeukes.com/events/victoria/hopak-in-the-park-2012/</guid>
      <description>[ ](http://www.ozeukes.com/wp-content/uploads/2012/01/FINAL-Hopak-in-the-park-2012-thumb.jpg)
 UKRAINIAN COSSACK DANCE SPECTACULAR HOPAK IN THE PARK! 28 April 2012 – Melbourne Australia  The Australian Federation of Ukrainian Organisations (AFUO) which represents over 20 Ukrainian Organisations in Australia, invites you to this year&#39;s &amp;ldquo;Hopak in the Park&amp;rdquo;, which will be presented on Saturday 28 April 2012 at the Sidney Myer Music Bowl in Melbourne.
See our YouTube promotion for “Hopak in the Park”. Click here : http://www.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Australian Tennis Open 2012 – Ukrainian Players</title>
      <link>https://ozeukes.com/events/international-events/australian-tennis-open-2012-ukrainian-players/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 19 Jan 2012 06:43:39 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ozeukes.com/events/international-events/australian-tennis-open-2012-ukrainian-players/</guid>
      <description>The first tennis grand slam event of 2012, the Australian Open, got under way on Monday 16th January 2012 at Melbourne Park, Melbourne, Australia. A number of Ukrainian tennis players entered into the competition.
Ukrainian Men
Ukrainian Women
Results of the first 2 rounds of Singles competitions Men&#39;s Singles - 1st Round
Set score
Result
3
2
** **
3
2
Set scores
Result
_ _
3
2
** **</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hopak in the Park 2012 Launch</title>
      <link>https://ozeukes.com/events/international-events/hopak-in-the-park-2012-launch/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Dec 2011 06:03:49 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ozeukes.com/events/international-events/hopak-in-the-park-2012-launch/</guid>
      <description>[ ](http://www.ozeukes.com/wp-content/uploads/2011/12/zCYOA-Web-letterhead-color-600-pxls5.jpg)The Australian Federation of Ukrainian Organisations (AFUO)
launches its
**Hopak in the Park 2012 **
YouTube promotional video
http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=12n1_s9vRVA
 Hopak in the Park
Saturday April 28, 2012
Sidney Myer Music Bowl
 Tickets go on sale January 16, 2012.
** ****Performances by **
 * Dance ensembles from throughout Australia  ** ****Guest Artists - **
 * Return visit of **Hrim** from NY –USA  http://nashholos.blogspot.com/2011/06/new-york-ukrainian-polka-band-hrim.html * Theresa Sokyra - Canadian Idol Runner -up http://www.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Лінки до сайтів про роковини Голодомору / Links to sites about Holodomor commemoration events</title>
      <link>https://ozeukes.com/events/international-events/links-to-sites-about-holodomor-commemoration-events/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 Nov 2011 05:24:26 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ozeukes.com/events/international-events/links-to-sites-about-holodomor-commemoration-events/</guid>
      <description>Подаємо лінки до новинні тексти, відео та фото-репортажі про роковини Голодомору (Links to recent reports, videos and photographs about Holodomor commemoration events):
 На сторінці Центру досліджень визвольного руху
 http://www.cdvr.org.ua/content/5-%D1%82%D0%B8%D1%81%D1%8F%D1%87-%D0%BA%D0%B8%D1%8F%D0%BD-%D0%B2%D1%88%D0%B0%D0%BD%D1%83%D0%B2%D0%B0%D0%BB%D0%B8-%D0%B7%D0%B0%D0%B3%D0%B8%D0%B1%D0%BB%D0%B8%D1%85-%D0%B2%D1%96%D0%B4-%D0%B3%D0%BE%D0%BB%D0%BE%D0%B4%D1%83-%D0%B4%D1%96%D1%82%D0%B5%D0%B9
 Олеся Ісаюк. Дві пам&#39;яті.
 http://lb.ua/blog/isayuk_olesya/125669_dvi_pamyati.html
 Володимир В&#39;ятрович. Втрачені
 http://lb.ua/blog/isayuk_olesya/125669_dvi_pamyati.html Іван Вакарчук. Пам&#39;яті жертв Голодомору
 http://tsn.ua/analitika/pam-yati-zhertv-golodomoru-1932-1933-rokiv-v-ukrayini.html
 Ігор Дерев&#39;яний. Голодомор та Європа: уроки демократії
 http://www.unian.net/ukr/news/news-470468.html
 Олександр Ярмола. Українцям не було потрібне примусове залучення до радянського концтабору</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>International Holodomor Memorial Day</title>
      <link>https://ozeukes.com/events/international-events/international-holodomor-memorial-day/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 26 Nov 2011 00:32:44 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ozeukes.com/events/international-events/international-holodomor-memorial-day/</guid>
      <description>In memory of Holodomor victims
on Saturday, November 26, International Holodomor Memorial Day.
Keep the flame alive!
Light a candle in your home, your office, in a Church nearby you.
 Cубота 26-го листопада 2011
Запаліть свічку памяті -
Згадаймо жертв Голодомору
Україна Пам&#39;ятає Cвіт Визнає
 Change your profile photo to the candle image on your Facebook page</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Заклик CКУ до річниці Голодомору / UWC Statement on the anniversary of the Holodomor</title>
      <link>https://ozeukes.com/events/international-events/uwc-statement-on-the-anniversa/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Nov 2011 06:33:26 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ozeukes.com/events/international-events/uwc-statement-on-the-anniversa/</guid>
      <description>Cвітовий Конґреc Укрaїнців (СКУ) подав заклик з нагоди 78-ої річниці Голодомору 1932-33 рр. в Україні. Текст заклику в українські мові можна прочитати тут: Nov 16 2011 PR Holodomor Zaklyk SKU (Ukr )  The Ukrainian World Congress (UWC) has issued a statement on the occasion of the 78th anniversary of the Holodomor of 1932-33. The English-language version of the statement can be read here: Nov 16 2011 PR Holodomor Zaklyk SKU (Eng)</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Australian Presentation and Launch of the book &#34;Holodomor. The Great Famine in Ukraine 1932-1933&#34;  and the book series “Poland and Ukraine in the 1930s and 1940s” </title>
      <link>https://ozeukes.com/events/victoria/australian-presentation-and-launch-of-the-book-holodomor-the-great-famine-in-ukraine-1932-1933-and-the-book-series-%e2%80%9cpoland-and-ukraine-in-the-1930s-and-1940s%e2%80%9d/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 31 Oct 2011 02:48:27 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ozeukes.com/events/victoria/australian-presentation-and-launch-of-the-book-holodomor-the-great-famine-in-ukraine-1932-1933-and-the-book-series-%e2%80%9cpoland-and-ukraine-in-the-1930s-and-1940s%e2%80%9d/</guid>
      <description>Monash European and EU Centre
Mykola Zerov Centre for Ukrainian Studies, Monash University
Professor Iurii Shapoval (National Academy of Sciences of Ukraine) Members of the Institute of National Remembrance, Poland
**Holodomor. The Great Famine in Ukraine 1932-1933 **
**and the book series “Poland and Ukraine in the 1930s and 1940s”**Time: Thursday 10 November 2011, 6.30pm for 7.00pm
(refreshments from 6.30pm, proceedings 7.00-approx. 8.00pm)
Place: Lecture Theatre HB32, Building H, Monash University Caulfield Campus</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Хор з Мельбурну на поїздці в Україні</title>
      <link>https://ozeukes.com/events/international-events/ukrainian-choir-from-melbourne-in-ukraine/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Sep 2011 07:44:24 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ozeukes.com/events/international-events/ukrainian-choir-from-melbourne-in-ukraine/</guid>
      <description>[ ](http://www.ozeukes.com/wp-content/uploads/2011/09/Combined-Choir-1-Thumb.jpg)
Хор Черемош та Катедральний Хор з Мельбурну на поїздці в Україні. Спільні хори «Черемош» (при осередку СУМ) та «Катедральний Хор» (при парафії ссв. Петра і Павла) з Мельбурну вже в другому тиждні поїздки в Україну. Відеокліпи та знимки цієї поїздки можна переглянути через веб-сторінку: http://ukitour.shorturl.com/
Combined Cheremosh and Cathedral Choirs from Melbourne on tour in Ukraine. The combined choirs “Cheremosh” (affiliated to the Ukrainian Youth Association) and the Cathedral Choir (of Ss Peter and Paul Ukrainian Catholic Cathedral) from Melbourne are now in the second week of their tour of Ukraine.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Open Appeal to the Government of Ukraine</title>
      <link>https://ozeukes.com/events/international-events/open-appeal-to-the-government-of-ukraine/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Jul 2011 12:53:43 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ozeukes.com/events/international-events/open-appeal-to-the-government-of-ukraine/</guid>
      <description>Please read and sign the &amp;ldquo;Open Appeal to the Government of Ukraine&amp;rdquo;. Add your name to the Open Appeal by going to http://www.lucorg.com/signature.php?signature_id=9  The Open Appeal with all signatures will be transmitted to the Government of Ukraine and to the Government of Canada.
The Open Appeal is an initiative of the Canadian Conference in Support of Ukraine (CCSU) and is supported by the Ukrainian Canadian Congress (UCC).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>World Cadets Judo Championship</title>
      <link>https://ozeukes.com/events/international-events/world-cadets-judo-championship/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Jul 2011 02:00:24 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ozeukes.com/events/international-events/world-cadets-judo-championship/</guid>
      <description>The 2nd World Judo Championship for Cadets (boys and girls under the age of 17 years) will be held in Kyiv, Ukraine, between the 11th and 14th of August 2011.
The Australian Cadets Judo Team will be representing Australia in this world championship.
The Australian team comprises of 26 members and includes young athletes, their coaches, team officials, and some escorting parents.
This is a truly all Australian team with athletes from:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>15th Anniversary of Ukrainian Constitution / 15-та річниця Конституції України</title>
      <link>https://ozeukes.com/events/international-events/15th-anniversary-of-ukrainian-constitution/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Jul 2011 00:25:40 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ozeukes.com/events/international-events/15th-anniversary-of-ukrainian-constitution/</guid>
      <description>On June 28 2011 Ukraine celebrated the 15th anniversary of its constitution. Watch the last stages of the celebrations in Independence Square (Maidan Nezalezhnosti) in Kyiv.  28 червня 2011 в Україні відсвяткували 15-ту річницю Конституції України. Подивіться на заключну частину святкувань на Майдані Незалежності в Києві.
http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=ALMu324l2Rk</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Медичне Cтажування в Україні</title>
      <link>https://ozeukes.com/events/international-events/medical-training-in-ukraine/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jun 2011 00:52:37 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ozeukes.com/events/international-events/medical-training-in-ukraine/</guid>
      <description>[](http://www.ozeukes.com/wp-content/uploads/2011/06/sucho-at-neuro-295-pxls1.jpg)[![](http://www.ozeukes.com/wp-content/uploads/2011/06/logo0-150-picels.jpg) ](http://www.ozeukes.com/wp-content/uploads/2011/06/logo0-150-picels.jpg)
Cтепан Дума і Aндрій Cуховерський
 В днях 7го лютого до 4го березня цього року, Aндрій Cуховерський і Степан Дума поїхали в Україну на медичне стажування. Це стажування є частина наших студій в Cіднейському Університеті на Бакалавр Медицини та Хірургії. Ця подорож була вже друга подорож в Україну на медичну практику. Перша така подорож відбулася у грудні 2008р., де ми поїхали в Черкаси на три тиждні на стажування в Третій Міській Лікарні.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>СКУ Травнева акція / UWC May Appeal</title>
      <link>https://ozeukes.com/events/international-events/uwc-may-appeal/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 04 Jun 2011 02:29:59 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ozeukes.com/events/international-events/uwc-may-appeal/</guid>
      <description>Світовий Конґрес Українців (СКУ) традиційно проводить Травневу акцію - фінансову збірку на потреби СКУ. Ця акція почалась в травні, а продвжуватимесь до липня ц.р.
 Пожертви можна робити через мережу електронних платежів із сайту СКУ: www.ukrainianworldcongress.org або переслати поштою на адресу СКУ:
Ukrainian World Congress 145 Evans Ave., Suite 207, Toronto, Ontario M8Z 5X8 Canada.

The Ukrainian World Congress (UWC) conducts an annual May Appeal – a fund-raiser to support the needs of UWC.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Президент Укрaїни звільнив Поcлa в Aвcтрaлії тa Нової Зелaндії</title>
      <link>https://ozeukes.com/events/international-events/ukrainian-ambassodor-to-australia-dismissed/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 31 May 2011 01:05:55 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ozeukes.com/events/international-events/ukrainian-ambassodor-to-australia-dismissed/</guid>
      <description>﻿
30-го травня 2011
 ПРЕCОВЕ ПОВІДОМЛЕННЯ  ПРЕЗИДЕНТ УКРAЇНИ ЗВІЛЬНИВ ПОCЛA В AВCТРAЛІЇ ТA НОВОЇ ЗЕЛAНДІЇ ВAЛЕНТИНA AДОМAЙТІCA  Управа Cоюзу Українських Організацій Aвстралії (CУОA) передає інформацію, яка розміщена на головному сайті Президента України про звільнення Посла України в Aвстралії та Нової Зеландії Валентина Aдомайтіса.
 30-го травня Указами Президента, Президент України Віктор ЯНУКОВИЧ звільнив низку послів
 Управа CУОA з прикрістю подає цю вістку, тому, що Валентин Aдомайтіс старанно виконував обов&#39;язки, старався серед Aвстралійських політичних кругів пропагувати Україну та українську справу.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Attack on Memorial Society of Vasyl Stus in Kyiv</title>
      <link>https://ozeukes.com/events/international-events/attack-on-memorial-society-of-vasyl-stus-in-kyiv/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 28 May 2011 01:19:48 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ozeukes.com/events/international-events/attack-on-memorial-society-of-vasyl-stus-in-kyiv/</guid>
      <description>Over the past few weeks there has been another human rights scandal in Ukraine - an attack on the Memorial Society of Vasyl Stus which is a historical museum. A letter of complaint was lodged with authorities by a woman who has been a missing person for over two years and still cannot be found. This again is a blatant attack by authorities in the old Stalinist style - make up the facts and don&#39;t let the truth get in the way.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Привіть Донецькому обласному художньому музею</title>
      <link>https://ozeukes.com/events/international-events/%d0%9f%d1%80%d0%b8%d0%b2%d1%96%d1%82%d1%8c-%d0%94%d0%be%d0%bd%d0%b5%d1%86%d1%8c%d0%ba%d0%be%d0%bc%d1%83-%d0%be%d0%b1%d0%bb%d0%b0%d1%81%d0%bd%d0%be%d0%bc%d1%83-%d1%85%d1%83%d0%b4%d0%be%d0%b6%d0%bd/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 28 May 2011 01:03:51 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ozeukes.com/events/international-events/%d0%9f%d1%80%d0%b8%d0%b2%d1%96%d1%82%d1%8c-%d0%94%d0%be%d0%bd%d0%b5%d1%86%d1%8c%d0%ba%d0%be%d0%bc%d1%83-%d0%be%d0%b1%d0%bb%d0%b0%d1%81%d0%bd%d0%be%d0%bc%d1%83-%d1%85%d1%83%d0%b4%d0%be%d0%b6%d0%bd/</guid>
      <description>Управа СУОА довідалася, що в Донецькому обласному художньому музею відбудеться виставка під назвою «Пам’ять про життя» до 25-х роковин трагедії на ЧАЕС. З ціеї нагоди СУОА написали сердечне вітання до дирекції Донецького Обласного художньому музею.
Текст листа у формі PDF: Donetsk - Chornobyl (2)</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Національна радіокомпанія України - Заклкик до дії</title>
      <link>https://ozeukes.com/events/international-events/national-radio-company-of-ukraine/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 May 2011 00:58:34 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ozeukes.com/events/international-events/national-radio-company-of-ukraine/</guid>
      <description>26-го травня 2011
ПРЕCОВЕ ПОВІДОМЛЕННЯ ДAЛЬШІ НACТУПИ на «Всесвітну службу радіомовлення України» Національної радіокомпанії України Заклкик до дії  Управа CУОA сьогодні отримала інформацію про дальші наступи на українську редакцію _Іномовлення _
 Подаємо цю інформацію
 _В Україні триває волюнтаристський наступ чиновників на українські ЗМІ. __25 __травня, о 12. 00, Гендиректор Національної радіокомпанії України Тарас Аврахов, без жодних попередніх пояснень чи то зауважень, одноосібно розпорядився припинити мовлення української редакції Всесвітньої служби радіомовлення України.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Комунікат ХVIII Cвітового Конґресу CУМ</title>
      <link>https://ozeukes.com/events/international-events/communique-cym-18th-congress/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 May 2011 00:53:18 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ozeukes.com/events/international-events/communique-cym-18th-congress/</guid>
      <description>XVIII Світовий Конґрес СУМ відбувся від 13-го до 15-го травня 2011 року в домівці Осередку СУМ ім. полк. Дмитра Вітовського в Палатайн, США, недалеко від міста Чікаґо. Делеґати із десяти країн взяли участь в Конґресі.
Учасники Конґресу з Aвстралії були Петро Дума, Марко Ткачук, Павло Камінський, Cтепан Ткачук, Дарія Періг, Ярослав Дума, Наталка Попович, Христина Полатайко, Степан Дума, Cтефан Романів.
Вибрано на Голову Cвітової Управи CУМ - Петра Думу з Австралії.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>100 years of PLAST / 100-ліття ПЛАСТ-у</title>
      <link>https://ozeukes.com/events/international-events/100-years-of-plast-100-%d0%bb%d1%96%d1%82%d1%82%d1%8f-%d0%9f%d0%9b%d0%90%d0%a1%d0%a2-%d1%83/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 May 2011 10:56:58 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ozeukes.com/events/international-events/100-years-of-plast-100-%d0%bb%d1%96%d1%82%d1%82%d1%8f-%d0%9f%d0%9b%d0%90%d0%a1%d0%a2-%d1%83/</guid>
      <description>[](http://www.ozeukes.com/wp-content/uploads/2011/05/Pic0002-295-pxls.jpg)[![](http://www.ozeukes.com/wp-content/uploads/2011/05/150px-Plast.jpg) ](http://www.ozeukes.com/wp-content/uploads/2011/05/150px-Plast.jpg)
 The National Executive of PLAST in Australia invites all plastuny worldwide to celebrate 100 years of PLAST between 26/12/2011 and 3/01/2012 in Canberra, Australia. Крайова Пластова Старшина Австралії запрошує всіх пластунів світу відсвяткувати 100-ліття Пласту від 26.12.2011 до 3.01.2012 в Канберрі, Австралії.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Webcast - Hopak in the Park / Гопак у Парку</title>
      <link>https://ozeukes.com/events/international-events/webcast-hopak-in-the-park-%d0%93%d0%be%d0%bf%d0%b0%d0%ba-%d1%83-%d0%9f%d0%b0%d1%80%d0%ba%d1%83/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 May 2011 04:19:31 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ozeukes.com/events/international-events/webcast-hopak-in-the-park-%d0%93%d0%be%d0%bf%d0%b0%d0%ba-%d1%83-%d0%9f%d0%b0%d1%80%d0%ba%d1%83/</guid>
      <description>HOPAK IN THE PARK  What an impressive spectacle!! ГОПАК У ПАРКУ  Яке вражаюче видовище!! If you missed the show, you can see a full webcast replay:
Якщо пропустила цей спектакль, можна в повньому переглянути:
http://www.learnbywebcam.com.au/webcasting/stream.php?id=14</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ukraine beats Australia in Fed Cup tie</title>
      <link>https://ozeukes.com/events/international-events/ukraine-beats-australia-in-fed-cup-tie/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 17 Apr 2011 11:30:57 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ozeukes.com/events/international-events/ukraine-beats-australia-in-fed-cup-tie/</guid>
      <description>In an upset result Ukraine’s women tennis players have defeated Australia in a Fed Cup tie. The win gives Ukraine the right to remain in the elite Fed Cup World Group and relegates Australia to the lower tier World Group II.
Scores were level after the first two singles matches played at Glen Iris Valley Recreation Club in Mt. Waverley, Melbourne on Saturday 16 April 2011, and were level again after the two reverse singles rubbers on Sunday.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Феномен української музики на Womadelaide</title>
      <link>https://ozeukes.com/events/international-events/%d0%a4%d0%b5%d0%bd%d0%be%d0%bc%d0%b5%d0%bd-%d1%83%d0%ba%d1%80%d0%b0%d1%97%d0%bd%d1%81%d1%8c%d0%ba%d0%be%d1%97-%d0%bc%d1%83%d0%b7%d0%b8%d0%ba%d0%b8-%d0%bd%d0%b0-womadelaide/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Apr 2011 10:23:03 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ozeukes.com/events/international-events/%d0%a4%d0%b5%d0%bd%d0%be%d0%bc%d0%b5%d0%bd-%d1%83%d0%ba%d1%80%d0%b0%d1%97%d0%bd%d1%81%d1%8c%d0%ba%d0%be%d1%97-%d0%bc%d1%83%d0%b7%d0%b8%d0%ba%d0%b8-%d0%bd%d0%b0-womadelaide/</guid>
      <description>**Феномен української музики на Womadelaide**** **
 Зібрав матеріали та автор статтї, Ростислав Бекер
Цього-річний WOMADelaide фестиваль, котрий проходив з 11ого до 14ого березня, приніс море приємних вражень. Прекрасна погода, 85,000 глядачів, 500 артистів з 30 держав. Між ними виступав відомий ансамбль «Даха Браха», з України.
«Даха Браха» та Амаду і Маріям із Малі були запрошені відкрити фестиваль в п’ятницю 11ого березня перед представниками уряду та дуже великої кількості журналістів зі всіх галузів мідії.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>DakhaBrakha at WOMADelaide 2011</title>
      <link>https://ozeukes.com/events/international-events/dakhabrakha-at-womadelaide-2011/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Apr 2011 09:41:47 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ozeukes.com/events/international-events/dakhabrakha-at-womadelaide-2011/</guid>
      <description>**Six Days Of Ethno Chaos **
**DakhaBrakha at ****WOMADelaide ****2011 **
 _written by** ****Rostyslav Becker**** **_
** **
**Day One **
** **Ethno Chaos evokes notions of anarchic confusion and disharmony. Yet, as Marko Halanevych of DakhaBrakha articulately explains, chaos is the impulse for creation.
Being a stage performer as well as musician, Marko knows too well that performance risks and experimentation will take you on wildly unexpected yet often exhilarating turns.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Australia vs Ukraine Fed Cup Tennis Match</title>
      <link>https://ozeukes.com/events/international-events/australia-vs-ukraine-fed-cup-tennis-match/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Mar 2011 11:35:03 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ozeukes.com/events/international-events/australia-vs-ukraine-fed-cup-tennis-match/</guid>
      <description>Australia will host Ukraine in a Fed Cup tie in April for the right to stay in the World Group.
The Fed Cup was launched in 1963 to celebrate the 50th anniversary of the International Tennis Federation (ITF). It’s now the world’s largest annual international team competition in women’s sport, with 80 nations competing in 2010.
Details regarding the Australia versus Ukraine tie
Venue
The Glen Iris Valley Recreation Club 260-270 High Street Road Mount Waverley 3149</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Блаженніший Любомир (Гузар) залишає уряд Глави УГКЦ / His Beatitude Lubomyr (Husar) leaves the office of Head of the Ukrainian Greek Catholic Church</title>
      <link>https://ozeukes.com/events/international-events/husar-resignation/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 11 Feb 2011 05:29:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ozeukes.com/events/international-events/husar-resignation/</guid>
      <description>Блаженніший Любомир (Гузар) залишає уряд Глави УГКЦ 10 лютого на прес-конференції у Києві Блаженніший Любомир (Гузар) повідомив про те, що цього дня Папа Венедикт XVI прийняв його зречення з уряду Верховного Архиєпископа Української Греко-Католицької Церкви. Відповідне прохання до Святішого Отця Глава УГКЦ подав, коли йому виповнилося 75 років.
«Сьогодні, коли я вже не маю достатньо сил, хочу передати уряд своєму наступникові, який ефективно продовжуватиме цю працю. Бо це не моя праця і я не є ключем.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Australian Foreign Minister Rudd To Visit Ukraine In 2011</title>
      <link>https://ozeukes.com/events/international-events/australian-foreign-minister-rudd-to-visit-ukraine-in-2011/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Feb 2011 00:41:06 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ozeukes.com/events/international-events/australian-foreign-minister-rudd-to-visit-ukraine-in-2011/</guid>
      <description>The Ukrainian News Agency reports that Australia&#39;s Foreign Minister, Kevin Rudd, is to visit Ukraine this year, to be followed by a reciprocal visit by his Ukrainian counterpart, Kostiantyn Hryschenko. The text of the news item is as follows:
He said this in the meeting with his Ukrainian counterpart Kostiantyn Hryschenko within the framework of the Munich Conference on Security Policy on February 4.
The foreign ministers discussed urgent issues of Ukrainian - Australian relations, in particular, prospects of bilateral political dialogue, trade, economic, cultural and humanitarian cooperation, and development of a contractual legal framework of bilateral ties.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Euro 2012 Tickets On Sale only till 31 March 2011</title>
      <link>https://ozeukes.com/events/international-events/euro-2012-tickets-on-sale-only-till-31-march-2011/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Feb 2011 23:13:42 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ozeukes.com/events/international-events/euro-2012-tickets-on-sale-only-till-31-march-2011/</guid>
      <description>Ticket sales for UEFA EURO 2012 will start on 1 March 2011 through www.UEFA.com and end on 31 March 2011
Any application received after the application closing date will not be processed.
Assuming demand for tickets exceeds supply, a random lottery will determine the successful applications.
Please note: all correctly submitted and accepted applications received between 1 March and 31 March 2011 will be taken into consideration. It makes no difference whether you register early (on 1 March 2011) or later during the month.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>AUSTRALIAN OPEN 2011 – DOLGOPOLOV GOES DOWN FIGHTING</title>
      <link>https://ozeukes.com/events/australian-open-2011-%e2%80%93-dolgopolov-goes-down-fighting/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Jan 2011 23:56:17 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ozeukes.com/events/australian-open-2011-%e2%80%93-dolgopolov-goes-down-fighting/</guid>
      <description>As Alexandr Dolgopolov prepared himself for the biggest match of his life, hopes were held high for him to deliver a shock blow to 5th seeded Andy Murray, in their Quarter Final clash.
The match opened with ‘the most unpredictable player on the tour’ immediately forcing several back-to-back, break points against the heavily backed Scotsman. In true form, Murray overcame his initial quarter final jitters and proceeded to take both the first and second sets respectively, 7-5, 6-3.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>AUSTRALIAN OPEN 2011 - DOLGOPOLOV Versus MURRAY </title>
      <link>https://ozeukes.com/events/australian-open-2011-dolgopolov-versus-murray/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Jan 2011 06:12:47 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ozeukes.com/events/australian-open-2011-dolgopolov-versus-murray/</guid>
      <description>** THIS IS ONCE AGAIN A MASS CALL OUT TO ALL UKRAINIAN SUPPORTERS TO COME DOWN TO MELBOURNE PARK TOMORROW, 26th January, 2011 AND SUPPORT ONE OF OUR OWN!**
** **
Dolgopolov will need all the support he can get to make it through to the semis, so pack your picnic lunch and make a great day of it.
As the 3rd day match on Rod Laver arena, it is expected that the match won&#39;t start till after 2pm.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>AUSTRALIAN OPEN 2011 – DOLGOPOLOV TO PLAY ON AUSTRALIA DAY</title>
      <link>https://ozeukes.com/events/australian-open-2011-%e2%80%93-dolgopolov-to-play-on-australia-day/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Jan 2011 02:28:58 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ozeukes.com/events/australian-open-2011-%e2%80%93-dolgopolov-to-play-on-australia-day/</guid>
      <description>**“MARCHENKO GOES DOWN FIGHTING” **Marchenko was always going to have the odds stacked against him as he faced Murray in Round 2 on Thursday night. But with an enthusiastic 30 odd Ukrainian supporters cheering him on, hopes were held high. In what was a gallant battle, Murray proved too good for the up and coming Ukrainian, smashing him in 3 sets, 6-1, 6-3, 6-3.
**“DAY 10 – ANOTHER UKRAINIAN FACES MURRAY!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Congratulations to Alexander Dolgopolov</title>
      <link>https://ozeukes.com/events/international-events/congratulations-to-alexander-dolgopolov/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Jan 2011 12:13:16 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ozeukes.com/events/international-events/congratulations-to-alexander-dolgopolov/</guid>
      <description>Congratulations to Alexander Dolgopolov, the unseeded Ukrainian tennis player who today defeated the fourth-seeded Swede Robin Soderling in five sets 1-6 6-3 6-1 4-6 6-2 at the Australian Tennis Open.
Despite badly losing the first set, Alexander quietly and competently rallied to outsmart and out-play his larger and more-experienced opponent. The further the match progressed, the more positively did Alexander play, winning over the support of the vocal crowd. Alexander will next face Andy Murray in the quarter-finals.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Український гурт ДахаБраха виступатиме на Фестивалю WOMAD 2011 / Ukrainian Group DakhaBrakha From Ukraine аt WOMAD Festival 2011</title>
      <link>https://ozeukes.com/events/international-events/%d0%a3%d0%ba%d1%80%d0%b0%d1%97%d0%bd%d1%81%d1%8c%d0%ba%d0%b8%d0%b9-%d0%b3%d1%83%d1%80%d1%82-%d0%94%d0%b0%d0%b4%d1%85%d0%b0%d0%91%d1%80%d0%b0%d1%85%d0%b0-%d0%b2%d0%b8%d1%81%d1%82%d1%83%d0%bf%d0%b0/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Jan 2011 00:14:11 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ozeukes.com/events/international-events/%d0%a3%d0%ba%d1%80%d0%b0%d1%97%d0%bd%d1%81%d1%8c%d0%ba%d0%b8%d0%b9-%d0%b3%d1%83%d1%80%d1%82-%d0%94%d0%b0%d0%b4%d1%85%d0%b0%d0%91%d1%80%d0%b0%d1%85%d0%b0-%d0%b2%d0%b8%d1%81%d1%82%d1%83%d0%bf%d0%b0/</guid>
      <description>[](http://www.ozeukes.com/wp-content/uploads/2011/01/2011-web-tile_smal-72dpi.jpg)[![](http://www.ozeukes.com/wp-content/uploads/2011/01/2011-web-tile_smal-72dpi1.jpg) ](http://www.ozeukes.com/wp-content/uploads/2011/01/2011-web-tile_smal-72dpi1.jpg)Подаємо до відома, що до Aвстралії приїде група з України ДахаБраха. Група приїзджає на запрошення Міжнародного Фестивалю WOMAD в Aделайді між 11-14 березня 2011.
 DakhaBrakha, a music group from Ukraine, will perform at the WOMAD Festival in Adelaide between 11-14 March 2011.
 http://womad.org/ http://dakhabrakha.com.ua/
http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=ivIICD9_4Vg&amp;amp;feature=related
http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=qOJjUjGs2xA
http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=SWnao7yGu0I</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Перший табір СУМ-у в Новій Зеландії - First SUM (CYM) Camp in New Zealand</title>
      <link>https://ozeukes.com/events/international-events/%d0%9f%d0%b5%d1%80%d1%88%d0%b8%d0%b9-%d1%82%d0%b0%d0%b1%d1%96%d1%80-%d0%a1%d0%a3%d0%9c-%d1%83-%d0%b2-%d0%9d%d0%be%d0%b2%d1%96%d0%b9-%d0%97%d0%b5%d0%bb%d0%b0%d0%bd%d0%b4%d1%96%d1%97-first-sum-cym-c/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Jan 2011 08:14:57 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ozeukes.com/events/international-events/%d0%9f%d0%b5%d1%80%d1%88%d0%b8%d0%b9-%d1%82%d0%b0%d0%b1%d1%96%d1%80-%d0%a1%d0%a3%d0%9c-%d1%83-%d0%b2-%d0%9d%d0%be%d0%b2%d1%96%d0%b9-%d0%97%d0%b5%d0%bb%d0%b0%d0%bd%d0%b4%d1%96%d1%97-first-sum-cym-c/</guid>
      <description>Cоюз Українських Організацій Aвстралії (СУОА) вітає перший Табір Cпілки Української Молоді (CУМ) у Новій Зеландії.
The Australian Federation of Ukrainian Organisations (AFUO) sends its greetings to the inaugгral camp of the Ukrainian Youth Association in New Zealand.
 
січень 2011
Христос Раждається!
 ПРИВІТ З НAГОДИ ПЕРШОГО ТAБОРУ
CПІЛКИ УКРAЇНCЬКОЇ МОЛОДІ У НОВІЙ ЗЕЛAНДІЇ
 Cоюз Українських Організацій Aвстралії вітає перший Табір Cпілки Української Молоді (CУМ) у Новій Зеландії.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>MARCHENKO V. MURRAY - After 7pm 20/01/2011 Margaret Court Arena</title>
      <link>https://ozeukes.com/events/marchenko-v-murray-after-7pm-20012011-margaret-court-arena/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Jan 2011 05:08:17 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ozeukes.com/events/marchenko-v-murray-after-7pm-20012011-margaret-court-arena/</guid>
      <description>**THIS IS A CALL OUT TO ALL UKRAINIAN SUPPORTERS TO COME DOWN TO MELBOURNE PARK TOMORROW, 20th January, 2011 **
AND SUPPORT ONE OF OUR OWN!
MARCHENKO V. MURRAY - After 7pm 20/01/2011 Margaret Court Arena
Don on your Uki colours, grab your flags and warm up your vocal cords. We will aim to hold a few seats reserve in the arena, but best to get there early!
This is sure to be a huge match and with tickets only $20 after 5pm, we’re encouraging everyone and anyone to get down to Margaret Court for 7pm.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>AUSTRALIAN OPEN 2011 – DAY 2/3 HIGHLIGHTS/DAY FOUR SCHEDULE</title>
      <link>https://ozeukes.com/events/australian-open-2011-%e2%80%93-day-23-highlightsday-four-schedule/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Jan 2011 04:53:07 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ozeukes.com/events/australian-open-2011-%e2%80%93-day-23-highlightsday-four-schedule/</guid>
      <description>**AUSTRALIAN OPEN 2011 – **
**DAY 2/3 HIGHLIGHTS/DAY FOUR SCHEDULE **
“DAY TWO – 3 out of 4 aint bad!”
Bondarenko opened DAY TWO, against 54th ranked Chinese Shuai Peng. After a promising start, it turned into a tight 3-set battle, ending in Peng’s favour 2-6, 6-3, 8-6. Kateryna’s Open is far from over however, seeing her team up with Safina for the Women’s doubles later in the week.
Next up was Alexandr Dolgopolov, who blitzed his Kazakhstani opponent in straight sets, 6-3, 6-2, 6-4.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>AUSTRALIAN OPEN 2011 – DAY ONE HIGHLIGHTS/DAY TWO SCHEDULE</title>
      <link>https://ozeukes.com/events/victoria/australian-open-2011-%e2%80%93-day-one-highlightsday-two-schedule/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Jan 2011 06:53:22 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ozeukes.com/events/victoria/australian-open-2011-%e2%80%93-day-one-highlightsday-two-schedule/</guid>
      <description>**AUSTRALIAN OPEN 2011 – **DAY ONE HIGHLIGHTS/DAY TWO SCHEDULE
 “DAY ONE SUCCESS – Stakhovsky through to ROUND 2.”
 As we approach the end of Day 1, Ukraine already has one through to the second round, with Sergiy Stakhovsky breezing through in straight sets against German, Daniel Brands.
Stakhovsky must now face neighbouring Polish competitor, Lukasz Kubot, for round 2. Kubot’s victory over the 18th seeded American, Sam Querrey, indicates that he is in form, so Stakhovsky will need all the support he can get.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>AUSTRALIAN OPEN 2011 - Round 1 (DAY ONE)</title>
      <link>https://ozeukes.com/events/australian-open-2011-round-1-day-one/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Jan 2011 00:42:24 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ozeukes.com/events/australian-open-2011-round-1-day-one/</guid>
      <description>AUSTRALIAN OPEN 2011
CALLING ON ALL SPORTS FANS!
The wait is over – The 2011 Australian Open is finally here and we’re inviting you to come down and support our athletes**!**
Over the next 2 weeks, the AFUO will be providing regular updates of the successes and movements of all Ukrainian Athletes competing in this year’s 2011 Australian Open.
Each day a new playing schedule will be revised and released. We’ll aim to identify early when the Ukrainian athletes are competing, so that you can arrange a supporters group to come down and cheer on our athletes!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Petition to Ukraine&#39;s President Victor Yanukovych</title>
      <link>https://ozeukes.com/events/petition-to-ukraines-president-victor-yanukovych/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Nov 2010 00:53:06 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ozeukes.com/events/petition-to-ukraines-president-victor-yanukovych/</guid>
      <description>The Ukrainian World Congress (UWC) calls upon all people of good will to sign a petition to the President of Ukraine demanding his public recognition of the Holodomor of 1932-33 as an act of genocide against the Ukrainian people.
Sign the petition today!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Петиція до президента України Віктора Януковича</title>
      <link>https://ozeukes.com/events/%d0%9f%d0%b5%d1%82%d0%b8%d1%86%d1%96%d1%8f-%d0%b4%d0%be-%d0%bf%d1%80%d0%b5%d0%b7%d0%b8%d0%b4%d0%b5%d0%bd%d1%82%d0%b0-%d0%a3%d0%ba%d1%80%d0%b0%d1%97%d0%bd%d0%b8-%d0%92%d1%96%d0%ba%d1%82%d0%be%d1%80/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Nov 2010 00:52:27 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ozeukes.com/events/%d0%9f%d0%b5%d1%82%d0%b8%d1%86%d1%96%d1%8f-%d0%b4%d0%be-%d0%bf%d1%80%d0%b5%d0%b7%d0%b8%d0%b4%d0%b5%d0%bd%d1%82%d0%b0-%d0%a3%d0%ba%d1%80%d0%b0%d1%97%d0%bd%d0%b8-%d0%92%d1%96%d0%ba%d1%82%d0%be%d1%80/</guid>
      <description>[](http://www.ozeukes.com/wp-content/uploads/2010/11/holodomor_b_en2.jpg)[![](http://www.ozeukes.com/wp-content/uploads/2010/11/holodomor_b_ua.jpg) ](http://www.ozeukes.com/wp-content/uploads/2010/11/holodomor_b_ua.jpg)Світовий Конґрес Українців (СКУ) звертається до всіх людей доброї волі підписати петицію до президента України відносно визнання Голодомору 1932-33 років яко ґеноцидом українського народу.
Підпишіть петицію сьогодні!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Golden October in Lviv</title>
      <link>https://ozeukes.com/events/golden-october-in-lviv/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Sep 2010 13:32:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ozeukes.com/events/golden-october-in-lviv/</guid>
      <description>Yкраїнська - цікаво, весело, ефективно! Інтенсивний курс української мови та культури для іноземців &amp;ldquo;ЗОЛОТИЙ ЖОВТЕНЬ У ЛЬВОВІ 2010&amp;rdquo; (Львів, 4-15 ЖОВТНЯ).
Протягом курсу учасники будуть мати можливість:
 * відвідати найцікавіші місця Львова та цілої України * приготувати та спробувати українські страви * вивчити українські сучасні та народні пісні * брати участь в українських звичаях і традиціях * грати у сучасні та народні українські ігри  і це ще не все!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Learn Ukrainian in Ukraine and Experience &#34;Warm September in Lviv&#34;</title>
      <link>https://ozeukes.com/events/learn-ukrainian-in-ukraine-and-experience-warm-september-in-lviv/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 19 Aug 2010 20:42:56 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ozeukes.com/events/learn-ukrainian-in-ukraine-and-experience-warm-september-in-lviv/</guid>
      <description>Українська - цікаво, весело, ефективно! Інтенсивний курс української мови та культури для іноземців &amp;ldquo;ТЕПЛИЙ ВЕРЕСЕНЬ У ЛЬВОВІ 2010&amp;rdquo; (Львів, 30 серпня-10 вересня).
Протягом курсу учасники будуть мати можливість:
 * відвідати найцікавіші місця Львова та цілої України * приготувати та спробувати українські страви * вивчити українські сучасні та народні пісні * брати участь в українських звичаях і традиціях * грати у сучасні та народні українські ігри  і це ще не все!</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>