<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Sticky on AFUO - СУОА</title>
    <link>https://ozeukes.com/categories/sticky/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Sticky on AFUO - СУОА</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 11 Jun 2017 23:04:43 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://ozeukes.com/categories/sticky/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>XV National Ukrainian Festival – Zdvyh</title>
      <link>https://ozeukes.com/events/xv-national-ukrainian-festival-zdvyh/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Jun 2017 23:04:43 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ozeukes.com/events/xv-national-ukrainian-festival-zdvyh/</guid>
      <description>XV NATIONAL UKRAINIAN CONFERENCE – ZDVYH 7th – 9th July, Melbourne
The Australian Federation of Ukrainian Organisations proudly announces that all roads will lead to Melbourne this July as Ukrainians from all over Australia travel to the world’s most liveable city for the XV National Ukrainian Festival – Zdvyh.
Held every four years, the Zdvyh will bring together Australian Ukrainians of all ages and from all walks of life. They will come together to celebrate their language, culture and identity and to launch a two-year program of national celebrations commemorating 70 years of post-WW2 settlement in Australia.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Holodomor drama in cinemas Feb 23 / Драма про Голодомор - в кінотеатрах 23-лютого</title>
      <link>https://ozeukes.com/culture/holodomor-drama-in-cinemas-feb-23/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Jan 2017 11:40:35 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ozeukes.com/culture/holodomor-drama-in-cinemas-feb-23/</guid>
      <description>Historical drama _Bitter Harvest _is a love story set amidst Ukraine’s devastating Holodomor.
Starring Max Irons (Red Riding Hood, Woman in Gold), Samantha Barks (Les Miserables), Terence Stamp (The Adventures of Priscilla, Queen of the Desert) and Barry Pepper (Saving Private Ryan, The Green Mile), the film was shot on location in Ukraine and is the first major dramatic picture to convey the untold story of Europe’s most overlooked tragedies of the 20th century.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>UKRAINIAN LITERATURE IN ENGLISH</title>
      <link>https://ozeukes.com/culture/ukrainian-literature-in-english/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Dec 2015 06:19:24 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ozeukes.com/culture/ukrainian-literature-in-english/</guid>
      <description>www.ukrainianliterature.com Watch as the site grows each day and a world of Ukrainian literature translated into English unfolds before your eyes. From the old classics to current-day books about the war in Ukraine’s east.
Both prose and poetry.
Links to websites to buy books online. New and used.
Like us on Facebook at www.facebook.com/Ukralit
Donations welcome through PayPal to ytkacz@gmail.com</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Make tax-deductible donations to help Ukraine</title>
      <link>https://ozeukes.com/current-affairs/media-releases/make-tax-deductible-donations-to-help-ukraine/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 Jun 2015 12:47:28 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ozeukes.com/current-affairs/media-releases/make-tax-deductible-donations-to-help-ukraine/</guid>
      <description>For immediate release: Friday, June 19 2015
Make tax-deductible donations to help Ukraine
Thankfully we live in a rich and peaceful country but imagine if it wasn’t so. Imagine if Australia was involved in a conflict that resulted in 1.2 million people being displaced and over 3.5 million being war affected, requiring urgent aid. How would we as a rich country, deal with a humanitarian crisis of those proportions? If it went on for over a year it would strain our vast resources and we would likely require the assistance of our international friends to get by.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Australia-Ukraine Chamber of Commerce to Open in Kyiv</title>
      <link>https://ozeukes.com/current-affairs/media-releases/australia-ukraine-chamber-of-commerce-to-open-in-kyiv/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Jun 2015 12:02:52 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ozeukes.com/current-affairs/media-releases/australia-ukraine-chamber-of-commerce-to-open-in-kyiv/</guid>
      <description>MEDIA RELEASE
AUSTRALIA-UKRAINE CHAMBER OF COMMERCE TO OPEN IN KYIV
The Australia-Ukraine Chamber of Commerce will be fully operational by the end of 2015 to pursue business opportunities between Australia and Ukraine.
According to the Australian Federation of Ukrainian Organisations (AFUO), who have initiated the project, Dr. Petro Matiaszek, a lawyer who has a 20 year long background in Ukraine’s corporate and public affairs spheres, will act as the Kyiv-based President of the Australia-Ukraine Chamber of Commerce, and Pete Shmigel will be its Sydney-based Interim Chair.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>U-HELP: Your Chance To Help Ukraine</title>
      <link>https://ozeukes.com/community/u-help-your-chance-to-help-ukraine/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 Jul 2014 02:52:05 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ozeukes.com/community/u-help-your-chance-to-help-ukraine/</guid>
      <description>U-HELP (the Ukrainian Humanitarian Educational and Leadership Program) is announced by the Australian Federation of Ukrainian Organisations (AFUO) as the endorsed way for Australians to support Ukraine’s sovereignty, democracy and path to peace and prosperity.
The objectives of U-HELP, an official initiative of the AFUO, are:
 * To fund humanitarian and medical assistance for people injured in the self-defence of Ukraine, and; * To support educational and leadership initiatives that promote Ukraine’s democratisation and prosperity through increased Ukraine-Australia social, political and economic ties.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>