<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Current Affairs on AFUO - СУОА</title>
    <link>https://ozeukes.com/categories/current-affairs/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Current Affairs on AFUO - СУОА</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 08 Dec 2019 03:42:17 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://ozeukes.com/categories/current-affairs/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>#StopRussianAggression Campaign</title>
      <link>https://ozeukes.com/current-affairs/stoprussianaggression-campaign/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 08 Dec 2019 03:42:17 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ozeukes.com/current-affairs/stoprussianaggression-campaign/</guid>
      <description>Майбутнє України вирішується ЗАРАЗ. Не лишись осторонь, #ПІДТРИМАЙ УКРАЇНУ! #STANDWITHUKRAINE!
Напередодні зустрічі «нормандської четвірки» СКУ запрошує долучитися до мирної акції на підтримку України, яка відбудеться 8 грудня в Парижі. Акція організована спільно з українською громадою Франції та Європи.
Ми закликаємо світ: #ПідтримайУкраїну. Наші вимоги прості:
  Відведення російських військ та найманців з України
  Посилення санкцій проти Росії
  Понесення Росією відповідальності
  Повернення Криму Україні</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Media Release: NO DISCUSSIONS ABOUT UKRAINE WITHOUT UKRAINE  President Zelensky must not agree to Russian demands</title>
      <link>https://ozeukes.com/current-affairs/zelensky-not-agree-russia-demands/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 03 Oct 2019 03:15:51 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ozeukes.com/current-affairs/zelensky-not-agree-russia-demands/</guid>
      <description>This causes unnecessary tension in civil society . International partners and stakeholders are also calling for answers.
The Australian Federation of Ukrainian Organisations,( the peak body for Ukrainians in Australia ) joins with the Ukrainian World Congress (UWC) in asking for clarity and transparency from the government of Ukraine regarding any agreement to hold elections in areas of Ukraine currently occupied by Russia.
The AFUO reaffirms that Ukraine must never agree to Russian demands regarding Ukrainian elections, or Ukraine’s constitutionally mandated strategic course of NATO and EU integration.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Westpac has responded, apology to be issued and advertising removed</title>
      <link>https://ozeukes.com/current-affairs/westpac-response-advert/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Apr 2019 11:46:07 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ozeukes.com/current-affairs/westpac-response-advert/</guid>
      <description>Following the many community complaints to Westpac about the Fraud Guarantee advertisement which referred to Ukraine, and following numerous specific conversations with Martine Jager, Chief Digital &amp;amp; Marketing Officer of Westpac group, the advertisement will be withdrawn. Ms Jager apologised on behalf of Westpac and indicated the advertisement was not meant to offend.
We will share the full written response from Westpac when it arrives.
Thank you to all who have been active and responded to our call to action in the past few days, via all the various channels including social media and email.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Call to Action: Respond to the Westpac Advertisement</title>
      <link>https://ozeukes.com/current-affairs/respond-to-westpac-ad/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 27 Apr 2019 07:52:33 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ozeukes.com/current-affairs/respond-to-westpac-ad/</guid>
      <description>The Australian Federation of Ukrainian Organisations (AFUO) calls on members of the Ukrainian community and the broader Australian community to strongly protest the Westpac advertisement in today&#39;s Melbourne Herald Sun &amp;amp; Sydney Daily Telegraph promoting their Westpac Fraud Money Back Guarantee Policy and putting the focus on UKRAINE.____
__ __Issues of fraud and misuse of credit cards is an international phenomenon. __There is no need to isolate Ukraine.
__ If it was intended as a marketing ploy - it is in bad taste and derogatory.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Media Release: Putin commits another act of aggression against Ukraine</title>
      <link>https://ozeukes.com/current-affairs/russian-aggression-continues-2019/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Apr 2019 01:21:41 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ozeukes.com/current-affairs/russian-aggression-continues-2019/</guid>
      <description>__
MEDIA RELEASE
Russian President Vladimir Putin has once again committed an act of aggression against Ukraine by signing a decree setting out which groups of people are, for humanitarian reasons, entitled to apply for Russian citizenship through a simplified procedure in the Ukrainian regions of Donetsk and Luhansk currently under occupation by the Russian Army.____
According to the decree, the Russian president made the decision &amp;ldquo;in order to protect human and citizen rights and freedoms&amp;rdquo; based on &amp;ldquo;commonly recognised principles and norms of international law&amp;rdquo; in accordance with the Russian Law on citizenship from May 31, 2002.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Закликаємо до участи в міжнародній кампанії #УкраїнаПонадУсе | Support the Campaign</title>
      <link>https://ozeukes.com/current-affairs/ukraine-above-all/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Apr 2019 06:13:22 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ozeukes.com/current-affairs/ukraine-above-all/</guid>
      <description>Закликаємо до участи в міжнародній кампанії #УкраїнаПонадУсе
Управа Союзу Українських Організацій Австралії (CYOA) закликає складових частин СУОА та українське суспільство долучитися до міжнародної кампанії #УкраїнаПонадУсе
Кампанія - Просимо перечитати долучений інструктаж – та приступити до акції по соціяльних мережах та в пресі . Хто як не ми ?
Управа СУОА повiдомляє що слідуючій члени нашої спільноти в Австралії -
Софія Матіяш – ПА
Михайло Лаба – Вікторія
Денис Козак - Канберра</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Show your support for Dr Suprun</title>
      <link>https://ozeukes.com/current-affairs/show-your-support-for-dr-suprun/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Feb 2019 08:43:08 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ozeukes.com/current-affairs/show-your-support-for-dr-suprun/</guid>
      <description>The Administrative Court in Kyiv issued a ruling endeavouring to ban Ukraine&#39;s acting health minister Dr. Ulana Suprun from performing her Ministerial functions.
This is an outrageous and politically motivated act - against an individual who has done nothing but positive actions for Ukraine&#39;s reforms in Health care. See our letter to Ambassador Melissa O&#39;Rourke below.
 * A working group has been formed on the issue * This group has secured President, PM and many others to support (when up until Friday little interest) * Many Governments have taken a watchful position * We have sparked the international social media campaign and activity in a range of countries * A quick decision made after seeing support to put her up for vote in VR * A fraction headed via Andreij Levus MP have now posted on agenda for VR  You can show your support on social media for Dr Ulana Suprun by using the hashtag #SupportSuprun and sharing posts like:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Australians not fooled by Russia’s scandalous propaganda</title>
      <link>https://ozeukes.com/current-affairs/australia-not-fooled-propaganda/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Jan 2019 02:09:35 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ozeukes.com/current-affairs/australia-not-fooled-propaganda/</guid>
      <description>Despite most of the international community criticising Russia for its aggression in Ukraine and for flaunting international conventions, the country’s embassy in Canberra has paid for an advertisement in which it condemns Australia for contributing to “Russophobia”.____
In the advertisement, published in The Canberra Times, it also blames Russia’s critics for not accepting Russian foreign policy and dismisses as absurd claims Russia had any involvement in the downing of Malaysia Airlines flight MH17 and the almost fatal nerve agent poisoning of British-based former double agent Sergei Skripal and his daughter.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Canberra Times Publishes AFUO Protest to Russian Ambassador&#39;s Paid Ad.</title>
      <link>https://ozeukes.com/current-affairs/canberra-times-publishes-afuo-protest-to-russian-ambassadors-paid-ad/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Dec 2018 05:38:55 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ozeukes.com/current-affairs/canberra-times-publishes-afuo-protest-to-russian-ambassadors-paid-ad/</guid>
      <description>Unacceptable ad
At a time when Australia and the international community has joined in condemning the seizure of Ukrainian naval personnel and their vessels and reaffirmed world support for Ukraine&#39;s sovereignty and integrity, it is unacceptable for an Australian newspaper to carry a paid advertisement from Russia defending what are currently disputed war crimes (The Canberra Times, December 21, p15).
The advertisement mocks the international findings that a Russian missile downed Malaysia Airlines flight MH17, killing 298 innocent souls including 38 Australians.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Australia’s Ukrainian community calls for International Condemnation of Russia  after latest attacks on Ukraine</title>
      <link>https://ozeukes.com/current-affairs/international-condemnation-for-ru/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Nov 2018 09:54:35 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ozeukes.com/current-affairs/international-condemnation-for-ru/</guid>
      <description>On November 25, 2018, Ukrainian Naval vessels were attacked by Russian forces as they were departing from the area of the Kerch Strait and moving back into the Black Sea. Ukrainian President Petro Poroshenko has announced that &amp;ldquo;Russian special forces have taken over some [Ukrainian] ships.&amp;rdquo; Over a half-dozen Ukrainian service members have been injured, and up to 20 are being held captive by Russian forces.
This was a premeditated and deliberate act of aggression against Ukraine by Russia.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Luke Foley raises Sentsov plight and Team Ukraine in NSW Parliament</title>
      <link>https://ozeukes.com/politics/foley-motion-sentsov-invictus/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Oct 2018 00:06:14 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ozeukes.com/politics/foley-motion-sentsov-invictus/</guid>
      <description>On the 23rd of October 2018, Luke Foley MP, tabled a Private Members Statement, which raised the matter of Oleg Sentsov and welcomed Team Ukraine to Australia for the Invictus Games.
On the matter of Sentsov, Mr Foley stated: &amp;ldquo;I add my voice to the many thousands of voices around the world calling for the immediate release of Oleg Sentsov from his frozen Russian prison. In recent months many Australians of Ukrainian background from my electorate of Auburn and beyond have raised with me the plight of Oleg Sentsov.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>UKRAINE HAS USED ITS GOD-GIVEN TALENTS TO DRIVE AGENDAS, NOT BURY THEM</title>
      <link>https://ozeukes.com/current-affairs/chairman-message-independence/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Oct 2018 09:52:46 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ozeukes.com/current-affairs/chairman-message-independence/</guid>
      <description>**Message from the Chairman of the Australian Federation of Ukrainian Organisations – ** Stefan Romaniw OAM
On the occasion of the 27th Anniversary of Ukraine’s Independence
Embassy of Ukraine – 27 September 2018
My Lord Bishops, Reverend Fathers, Your Excellency Ambassador of Ukraine in Australia Mr Kulinich and Mrs Kulinich, Members of the Diplomatic and Consular Corps, Representatives of the Australian Parliament, Members of the Australian Federation of Ukrainian Organisations, ladies and gentlemen.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>УКРАЇНЦІ В АВСТРАЛІЇ ЗАСУДЖУЮТЬ НЕЗАКОННОГО УТРИМАННЯ  РОСІЙСЬКОЮ ФЕДЕРАЦІЄЮ  УКРАЇНСЬКОГО ЖУРНАЛІСТА РОМАНА СУЩЕНКА</title>
      <link>https://ozeukes.com/current-affairs/free-sushenko/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Oct 2018 01:38:13 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ozeukes.com/current-affairs/free-sushenko/</guid>
      <description>__
Минає два роки з часу незаконного утримання під вартою в РФ українського журналіста Романа Сущенка.
Нещодавно кремлівський режим засудив його до 12 років колонії строгого режиму за надуманими звинуваченнями у шпіонажі.
Союз Українських Організацій Австралія (СУОА) приєднується до всіх украінських громад світу у засудженні дій РФ і закликає своїх членів та австралійський уряд посилити тиск на РФ у справі звільнення всіх незаконно арештованих українських політичних в&#39;язнів.
Пригадується сьогодні чудовий малюнок Сущенка - австралійський Сідней.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Open Letter from Ukrainians in Australia opposing conversation event with Ambassador of Russia in Perth.</title>
      <link>https://ozeukes.com/current-affairs/open-letter-ambassador/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Sep 2018 08:10:27 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ozeukes.com/current-affairs/open-letter-ambassador/</guid>
      <description>Three Open Letters from the Ukrainian Association of Western Australia , Dr Lesa Melnyczuk and the Australian Federation of Ukrainian Organisations to the PROPOSED EVENT IN WA, A Conversation with the Russian Ambassador to Australia
To:
Curtin Alumni
Curtin Media Officers
AIIA WA BRANCH
YOUNG AUSTRALIANS in INTERNATIONAL AFFAIRS
How quickly we forget the atrocities that Russia has promulgated?
How quickly we forget the &amp;ldquo;tongue lashing&amp;rdquo; that Julie Bishop (then the Foreign Minister) served up to the Russian Ambassador G Logvinov (Ref.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>AFUO Communique</title>
      <link>https://ozeukes.com/current-affairs/afuocommunique/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Aug 2018 12:26:56 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ozeukes.com/current-affairs/afuocommunique/</guid>
      <description>This is a Communique (Official Statement) prepared by the Australian Federation of Ukrainian Organisations, signed and supported by the State Hromady (Associations) Presidents&amp;rsquo; Forum held in Adelaide 4 August 2018. It outlines community mission, activities, structures and policies.
Signed and endorsed by: Stefan Romaniw OAM - Chairman Australian Federation of Ukrainian Organisations Frank Fursenko - President Association of Ukrainians in SA Slawko Kohut- President Association of Ukrainians in Victoria Stephen Chomyn - Ukrainian Community of Queensland Inc.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Нарада СУОА з головами Громад | AFUO Forum with State Presidents</title>
      <link>https://ozeukes.com/community/afuo-forum-state-presidents/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Aug 2018 01:31:03 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ozeukes.com/community/afuo-forum-state-presidents/</guid>
      <description>_AFUO Forum with State Presidents _
An AFUO-organised meeting of the Heads of State community associations was held in Adelaide on Saturday 4 August 2018. The 5-hour forum was chaired by Stefan Romaniw, the Head of AFUO (Australian Federation of Ukrainian Organisations) or, in Ukrainian, CYOA (Союз Українських Організацій Австралії). Participating in the forum were 15 delegates – 13 attending and 2 participating via phone hook-up. Seven of the delegates were from South Australia and all were members of the AUSA management committee.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>AFUO joins STOP REVANSH campaign</title>
      <link>https://ozeukes.com/current-affairs/stop-revansh/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Aug 2018 23:42:45 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ozeukes.com/current-affairs/stop-revansh/</guid>
      <description>СУОА приєднується до міжнародної кампанії СТОП РЕВАНШ, яка закликає стримувати про- російську антиукраїнську діяльність в Україні.
Акція протесту що телеканалу &amp;ldquo;Інтер&amp;rdquo; надається нову розширену ліцензія, в той час коли валсниками є - проросійські олігархи. Інтер це доставка проросійської пропаганди. Управа СУОА написала посолу України в Австралії Микола Кулініч, висловлюючи протест української громади в Австралії . AFUO закликає Посла довести українській влади наш протес та закликату уряд прийняти рішення та знайти юридичний механізм щодо ліквідації «Телеканалу «Інтер» та припинення його мовлення.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Australia&#39;s peak Ukrainian body set to slap Vladimir Putin with series of red cards.</title>
      <link>https://ozeukes.com/media/australias-peak-ukrainian-body-set-to-slap-vladimir-putin-with-series-of-red-cards/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Jun 2018 23:20:16 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ozeukes.com/media/australias-peak-ukrainian-body-set-to-slap-vladimir-putin-with-series-of-red-cards/</guid>
      <description>For the duration of the 2018 football World Cup hosted by the Russian Federation, the Australian Federation of Ukrainian Organisations (AFUO) will participate in the worldwide #RedCard4Putin campaign.
An initiative of the International Coalition for Human Rights (ICHR) the campaign will systematically issue red cards to Vladimir Putin’s regime calling out the host country’s crimes and violations of international law. Each red card will be publicised through social and traditional media, news releases, and civic activism.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>АКЦІЯ – STOP  PUTIN – STOP WAR</title>
      <link>https://ozeukes.com/events/international-events/stop-putin-stop-war/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Jan 2018 11:31:54 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ozeukes.com/events/international-events/stop-putin-stop-war/</guid>
      <description>January 19, 2018
АКЦІЯ – STOP PUTIN – STOP WAR Управа Союзу Українських Організацій Австралії (СУОА) звертає Вашу увагу на міжнародну акцію STOP PUTIN – STOP WAR, яка покликана не допустити проведення Чемпіонату світу з футболу у Росії.
22 січня пройде уже п’ятий етап акції STOP PUTIN – STOP WAR.
Її метою є намагання привернути увагу світової громадськості до Російської загарбницької війни, яка четвертий рік триває в Україні та не допустити щоб Чемпіонат світу з футболу пройшов на спортивних майданчиках країни-агресора.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>INTERNATIONAL FLASH MOB UNITED UKRAINE</title>
      <link>https://ozeukes.com/politics/international-flash-mob-united-ukraine/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Jan 2018 06:12:39 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ozeukes.com/politics/international-flash-mob-united-ukraine/</guid>
      <description>INTERNATIONAL FLASH MOB UNITED UKRAINE **100 Years of Ukraine’s Statehood … **
Focus – War and Russian aggression in Ukraine - 4 years on and continuing
We stand united internationally
Banners are attached below or download https://goo.gl/2JJ8ZC – Print – Take a photo – Post on your Facebook page
Post to
https://www.facebook.com/events/167345314031715
unitedukraine2018@gmail.com
Be creative – Encourage others** **
ОБІЖНИК СУОА
Ч. 18. 2015 – 2018
11 січня 2018 р.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Applications for Karpaty Grants &amp; Scholarships can now be made online. Apply today.</title>
      <link>https://ozeukes.com/community/applications-for-karpaty-grants-scholarships-can-now-be-made-online-apply-today/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Sep 2017 14:16:03 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ozeukes.com/community/applications-for-karpaty-grants-scholarships-can-now-be-made-online-apply-today/</guid>
      <description>** **The Board &amp;amp; Trustees of The Karpaty Foundation have pleasure in announcing that Applications for Grants and Scholarships have now been enabled to be completed by editable text directly online. This will substantially simplify the operation and will no longer require an applicant to download the pdf form, complete it in hand-writing, scan and then forward it back to the Directors for review.
Applicants can now go directly to the web-page at https://www.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ДО 100-РІЧНОГО ЮВІЛЕЮ ПАНА МАЛИМОНЕНКА</title>
      <link>https://ozeukes.com/community/malymonenko-100-year-anniversary/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Jul 2017 07:31:24 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ozeukes.com/community/malymonenko-100-year-anniversary/</guid>
      <description>11 липня 2017
ДО 100-РІЧНОГО ЮВІЛЕЮ ПАНА МАЛИМОНЕНКА Шановний пане Малимоненко!
Від імені Союзу Українських Організацій Австралії (СУОА) сердечно вітаємо Вас з нагоди славного 100-літнього ювілею!
Висловлюємо подяку за віддану багаторічну громадську діяльність для добра української спільноти Австралії.
Ваш життєвий досвід століття – це книжка історії життєвої мудрості, це пережиття подій воєнного та післявоєнного часу Другої світової війни, це еміґрація та закладення міцного фундаменту для нового життя в Австралії, а разом з тим це - збереження української культури, традицій, мови та релігії на новій не обжитій землі.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Australia-Ukraine Parliamentary Friendship Group being formed</title>
      <link>https://ozeukes.com/politics/australia-ukraine-parliamentary-friendship-group-being-formed/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Jul 2017 12:33:08 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ozeukes.com/politics/australia-ukraine-parliamentary-friendship-group-being-formed/</guid>
      <description>July 5, 2017
AUSTRALIA-UKRAINE PARLIAMENTARY FRIENDSHIP GROUP BEING FORMED – LEADERSHIP TEAM HAS ACCEPTED AFUO PROPOSAL TO FORM GROUP

Chris Crewther MP Member for Dunkley has agreed to accept the Australian Federation of Ukrainian Organisation&#39;s (AFUO) proposal to Chair the Australia - Ukraine Parliamentary Friendship Group (AUPFG).
Senator Catryna Bilyk (Tasmania) had also agreed to stay on as deputy chair.
Both are very strong supporters of Ukraine and Australia&#39;s Ukrainian community.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ЗАЯВА СТЕЙТОВИХ  ГРОМАД ТА СУОА ПРО РОЛЬ ТА ВАЖЛИВІСТЬ СТЕЙТОВИХ ГРОМАД ТА ПРЕДСТАВЛЕННЯ УКРАЇНСЬКОЇ СПІЛЬНОТИ</title>
      <link>https://ozeukes.com/community/statement-by-state-hromady-and-the-afuo-on-the-role-an-importance-of-state-hromady-associations-and-community-representation-ukr/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Jun 2017 10:30:04 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ozeukes.com/community/statement-by-state-hromady-and-the-afuo-on-the-role-an-importance-of-state-hromady-associations-and-community-representation-ukr/</guid>
      <description>ЗАЯВА СТЕЙТОВИХ ГРОМАД ТА СУОА ПРО РОЛЬ ТА ВАЖЛИВІСТЬ СТЕЙТОВИХ ГРОМАД ТА ПРЕДСТАВЛЕННЯ УКРАЇНСЬКОЇ СПІЛЬНОТИ
Українські громади Австралії можуть пишатися тим, що вони привітні й толерантні. Це дає можливість обговорювати всякі речі в атмосфері взаємоповаги. Громади включають різні хвилі поселенців, і це завжди так було – починаючи з тих, хто прибув наприкінці 1940-х років, після Другої світової війни, до тих, хто прибув з колишньої Югославії-Боснії, з Польщі та з інших частин світу, включно з Україною.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>STATEMENT BY STATE HROMADY AND THE AFUO ON THE ROLE AN IMPORTANCE OF STATE HROMADY–ASSOCIATIONS AND COMMUNITY REPRESENTATION</title>
      <link>https://ozeukes.com/community/statement-by-state-hromady-and-the-afuo-on-the-role-an-importance-of-state-hromady-associations-and-community-representation/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Jun 2017 10:23:57 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ozeukes.com/community/statement-by-state-hromady-and-the-afuo-on-the-role-an-importance-of-state-hromady-associations-and-community-representation/</guid>
      <description>STATEMENT BY STATE HROMADY AND THE AFUO ON THE ROLE AN IMPORTANCE OF STATE HROMADY – ASSOCIATIONS AND COMMUNITY REPRESENTATION
Australia’s Ukrainian community prides itself with being warm and inclusive. It offers opportunity for respectful discussion and expression of ideas. The community accommodates waves of settlement and always has – From those who came post WWII at the end of 1940’s to those from Former Yugoslavia – Bosnia, Poland, and other parts of the world.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Governor’s Multicultural Awards - 2 big wins for the Ukrainian community</title>
      <link>https://ozeukes.com/culture/governors-multicultural-awards-2-big-wins-for-the-ukrainian-community/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Mar 2017 06:20:50 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ozeukes.com/culture/governors-multicultural-awards-2-big-wins-for-the-ukrainian-community/</guid>
      <description>The presentation of 2016 Governor’s Multicultural awards was held on Tuesday 21 March on the grounds of Government House. A large crowd of more than 400 people – see photo - attended this ceremony. The attendees included the Lieutenant Governor of South Australia, Professor Brenda Wilson; Jay Weatherill, Premier of South Australia; Hon Zoe Bettison, MP, Minister of Multicultural Affairs; Hon Jing Lee MLC, Shadow Parliamentary Secretary for Multicultural Affairs – representing the Leader of the Opposition; Hon Michael Atkinson, Speaker of the House of Assembly; several state MPs; Martin Haese, Lord Mayor of Adelaide; the mayors of nine city councils; and the heads of most ethnic community associations.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Back to Ballarat reunion</title>
      <link>https://ozeukes.com/community/back-to-ballarat-reunion/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 11 Mar 2017 21:00:12 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ozeukes.com/community/back-to-ballarat-reunion/</guid>
      <description>12 March 2017
 Best wishes to all attending the Back to Ballarat reunion event today. This was a great AUV Branch and community for many years. The AFUO is proud to be able to assist in enshrining the contribution of Ukrainians in Ballarat&#39;s development. In addition, to mark the 70th Anniversary of Ukrainian settlement in Australia by providing commemorative plaque, which will be placed in a public area in the region.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ПОСОЛЬСТВО УКРАЇНИ В АВСТРАЛІЇ І СУОА ПІДПИСАЛИ МЕМОРАНДУМ СПІВПРАЦІ</title>
      <link>https://ozeukes.com/politics/embassy-of-ukraine-in-australia-and-afuo-sign-memorandum-of-understanding/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 31 Oct 2016 11:44:22 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ozeukes.com/politics/embassy-of-ukraine-in-australia-and-afuo-sign-memorandum-of-understanding/</guid>
      <description>ПОСОЛЬСТВО УКРАЇНИ В АВСТРАЛІЇ І СУОА ПІДПИСАЛИ МЕМОРАНДУМ СПІВПРАЦІ Управа СУОА та Посольство України в Австралії сьогодні підписали Меморандум Співпраці та План Дії. В Меморандумі зазначено загальні положення та напрямні для ефективної справпраці. Меморандум підписано підчас наради управи СУОА з участю членів СУОА. Текст Меморандуму та допис про нараду будуть опубліковані. Цей Меморандум будується на підставі підписано Меморандуму між СКУ та Кабінет Міністром України.
EMBASSY OF UKRAINE IN AUSTRALIA AND AFUO SIGN MEMORANDUM OF UNDERSTANDING Australian Federation of Ukrainian Organisations and The Embassy of Ukraine in Australia today signed a Memorandum of Cooperation and Work Plan to formalise and further the effective work of Australia’s Ukrainian Community and The Embassy.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>AUSTRALIAN FEDERATION OF UKRAINIAN ORGANISATIONS JOINS INTERNATIONAL CALL TO RELEASE UKRAINIAN POLITICAL PRIOSNERS ILLEGALLY IMPRISONED BY RUSSIA</title>
      <link>https://ozeukes.com/politics/australian-federation-of-ukrainian-organisations-joins-international-call-to-release-ukrainian-political-priosners-illegally-imprisoned-by-russia/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Oct 2016 11:58:26 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ozeukes.com/politics/australian-federation-of-ukrainian-organisations-joins-international-call-to-release-ukrainian-political-priosners-illegally-imprisoned-by-russia/</guid>
      <description>October 10, 2016
MEDIA RELEASE
AUSTRALIAN FEDERATION OF UKRAINIAN ORGANISATIONS JOINS INTERNATIONAL CALL TO RELEASE UKRAINIAN POLITICAL PRIOSNERS ILLEGALLY IMPRISONED BY RUSSIA The Australian Federation of Ukrainian Organisations) is calling on the Australian Ukrainian community to join the appeal of the Ukrainian World Congress (UWC) to the international community to put pressure on Russia to release illegally imprisoned Ukrainian citizens, including journalists Roman Sushchenko and Mykola Semena.
Currently the are the 20 Ukrainian citizens illegally imprisoned by Russia including Oleg Sentsov, Oleksander Kolchenko, Stanislav Klikh, Mykola Karpyuk and Akhtem Chiygoz.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>РОСІЯ ЗАТРИМАЛА УКРАЇНСЬКОГО ЖУРНАЛІСТА В МОСКВІ</title>
      <link>https://ozeukes.com/politics/ukrainian-journalist-detained-unlawfully/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Oct 2016 05:52:05 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ozeukes.com/politics/ukrainian-journalist-detained-unlawfully/</guid>
      <description>3-го жовтня 2016
ПРЕС РЕЛІЗ
РОСІЯ ЗАТРИМАЛА УКРАЇНСЬКОГО ЖУРНАЛІСТА В МОСКВІ ЩЕ ОДНЕ ПОРУШЕНННЯ ЛЮДСЬКИХ ПРАВ
Український журналіст Укрінформу, Роман Сущенко був незаконно затриманий в Москві російськими чиновниками. В російських ЗМІ Появилася інформація щодо звинувачень його у “шпигунстві”. ФСБ звинувачує Романа Сущенка в зборі інформації про російську армію.
Після прибуття в Москву з приватним візитом 30 вересня цр Сущенко був затриманий російськими властями. Його арешт не був доведений сім&#39;ї або будь-якого органу влади, що є порушенням міжнародного права.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Інтерв’ю на SBS Ukrainian Radio</title>
      <link>https://ozeukes.com/culture/interview-sbs-ukrainian-sep-oct-2016/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Oct 2016 10:46:21 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ozeukes.com/culture/interview-sbs-ukrainian-sep-oct-2016/</guid>
      <description>[ ](http://www.sbs.com.au/yourlanguage/ukrainian/uk/content/tak-nasha-pisnya-iednaie-sviti?language=uk)“ТАК, НАША ПІСНЯ ЄДНАЄ СВІТИ…”
БОГДАН РУДНИЦЬКИЙ ВЕДЕ РОЗМОВУ ІЗ ЗАСЛУЖЕНИМ ДІЯЧЕМ МИСТЕЦТВ УКРАЇНИ ВОЛОДИМИРОМ ГОЛОВКОМ ІЗ МЕЛЬБУРНА
http://www.sbs.com.au/yourlanguage/ukrainian/uk/content/tak-nasha-pisnya-iednaie-sviti?language=uk
  [ ](http://www.sbs.com.au/yourlanguage/ukrainian/uk/content/50-littya-ukrayinskogo-tancyuvalnogo-ansamblyu-verhovina?language=uk)50-ЛІТТЯ УКРАЇНСЬКОГО ТАНЦЮВАЛЬНОГО АНСАМБЛЮ &amp;ldquo;ВЕРХОВИНА&amp;rdquo;
Богдан Рудницький веде розмову із знаними сумівками Лесею Рудевич і Тамарою Моравською зі Спілки Української Молоді в Австралії та Українського танцювального ансамблю &amp;ldquo;ВЕРХОВИНА&amp;rdquo; із Мельбурна.
http://www.sbs.com.au/yourlanguage/ukrainian/uk/content/50-littya-ukrayinskogo-tancyuvalnogo-ansamblyu-verhovina?language=uk</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>AUSTRALIA EXTENDS DIPLOMATIC PRESENCE IN UKRAINE</title>
      <link>https://ozeukes.com/politics/australia-extends-diplomatic-presence-in-ukraine/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Sep 2016 21:01:06 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ozeukes.com/politics/australia-extends-diplomatic-presence-in-ukraine/</guid>
      <description>September 29, 2016
MEDIA RELEASE
Australian Embassy in Kyiv to continue AFUO Welcomes Australian Government Decision
The Australian Federation of Ukrainian Organisations (AFUO) welcomes the Australian Government’s decision to extend Australia’s diplomatic presence in Ukraine by retaining the Embassy of Australia in Kyiv for a further two years.
http://ukraine.embassy.gov.au/kyiv/200.html
The position of Australia’s Ambassador in Kyiv has also been advertised.
“This announcement is a strong indicator that the Australian Government continues to stand firm in supporting Ukraine.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>AUSTRALIA’S UKRAINIAN COMMUNITY CONTINUES TO SUPPORT UKRAINIAN SOLDIERS AND VOLUNTEERS FIGHTING RUSSIAN AGGRESSION IN EASTERN UKRAINE</title>
      <link>https://ozeukes.com/politics/australias-ukrainian-community-continues-to-support-ukrainian-soldiers-and-volunteers-fighting-russian-aggression-in-eastern-ukraine/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Sep 2016 06:51:10 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ozeukes.com/politics/australias-ukrainian-community-continues-to-support-ukrainian-soldiers-and-volunteers-fighting-russian-aggression-in-eastern-ukraine/</guid>
      <description>25 вересня 2016
УКРАЇНСЬКА ГРОМАДА АВСТРАЛІЇ ПРОДОВЖУЄ ПІДТРИМУВАТИ УКРАЇНСЬКИХ СОЛДАТІВ І ВОЛОНТЕРІВ, ЯКІ ВОЮЮТЬ ПРОТИ РОСІЙСЬКОЇ АГРЕСІЇ НА СХОДІ УКРАЇНИ Подаємо Грамоту Подяки для СУОА на потреби програми Захист Патріотів з дня 24.9.2016 - за пожертву в сумі $23,000 США (серпнеь 2016).
Управа СУОА дякує всім жертводавцям.
Програма допомоги бійцям, які воюють проти Російської агресії продовжуються .
Вашу пожертву можна вплатити на конто СУОА U-HELP в Кооп. Дністер
BSB: 704-235 Account Number: 00015958</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>AFUO holds discussions with DFAT on furthering Australia-Ukraine relations</title>
      <link>https://ozeukes.com/politics/afuo-holds-discussions-with-dfat-on-furthering-australia-ukraine-relations/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Sep 2016 11:32:31 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ozeukes.com/politics/afuo-holds-discussions-with-dfat-on-furthering-australia-ukraine-relations/</guid>
      <description>September, 2016
AUSTRALIAN FEDERATION OF UKRAINIAN ORGANISATIONS HOLDS DISCUSSIONS WITH DEPARTMENT OF FOREIGN AFFAIRS AND TRADE ON FURTHERING AUSTRALIA-UKRAINE RELATIONS The Australian Federation of Ukrainians Organisations Chairman Stefan Romaniw recently met with Deputy Secretary of the Australian Government’s Department Foreign Affairs and Trade and Chair of the UN Security Council, Gary Quinlan.
The following issues were discussed:
 * The AFUO call on to Prime Minister Turnbull to ensure the issue of Russian aggression in Eastern Ukraine and annexation of Crimea be raised at the G20 and that the PM to lead the conversation about excluding Russia from the G20.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Celebrating 70 years of settlement of Ukrainians in Australia</title>
      <link>https://ozeukes.com/events/victoria/celebrating-70-years-of-settlement-of-ukrainians-in-australia/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Sep 2016 12:28:10 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ozeukes.com/events/victoria/celebrating-70-years-of-settlement-of-ukrainians-in-australia/</guid>
      <description>19-го вересня 2016
ОБІЖНИК СУОА
Ч. 8. 2015 – 2018
**Відзначення 70-ліття Поселення Українців в Австралії Зміцни майбутнє, пізнай минуле!**
**I. XV Здвиг Українців Австралії відбудеться 8 - 9 липня 2017 р. **
Мистецька програма XV Здвигу відбудеться у недію, 9-го липня, 2017, Melbourne Town Hall (це період шкільних канікул у всіх штатах Австралії).
ІІ. Відзначення 70-ліття Поселення Українців в Австралії.
 1. Управа Союзу Українських Організацій Австралії готує план заходів з підготовки та відзначення 70-ліття поселення українців в Австралії.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>CYOA Registered with &#34;Our Community&#34;</title>
      <link>https://ozeukes.com/community/cyoa-registered-with-our-community/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Sep 2016 12:39:16 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ozeukes.com/community/cyoa-registered-with-our-community/</guid>
      <description>14-го вересня 2016
CYOA Registered with Our Community - CYOA member organisations registered for FUNDING INFORMATION
Управа СУОА зареєструвалася в організації Our Cоmmunity www.ourcommunity.com.au
Ця структура допомагає організаціям які визнані як Non for Profit, подаючи інформацію про різні заходи, форуми, курси ітп, щоб покращити ефективність праці.
Управа СУОА також оплатила входову дотацію та зареєструвалася для додаткових прислуг в сфері ґрантів.
Зареєструвано 10 точок в спільноті - включаючи адрес Стейтових громад, молодечих організацій, шкільництво, жіночі організації.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Австралійські Українці отримали ювілейні медалі - Australian Ukrainians receive Jubilee Medals in Ukraine</title>
      <link>https://ozeukes.com/politics/australian-ukrainians-receive-jubilee-medals-in-ukraine/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Aug 2016 12:07:21 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ozeukes.com/politics/australian-ukrainians-receive-jubilee-medals-in-ukraine/</guid>
      <description>УКАЗ ПРЕЗИДЕНТА УКРАЇНИ №340/2016
Про відзначення державними нагородами України громадян іноземних держав
За вагомий особистий внесок у зміцнення міжнародного авторитету Української держави, популяризацію її історичної спадщини і сучасних надбань та з нагоди 25-ї річниці незалежності України п о с т а н о в л я ю
Нагородити відзнакою Президента України – ювілейною медаллю &amp;ldquo;25 років незалежності України&amp;rdquo;
БОТТЕ Валерія Генріховича - почесного консула України в м.Мельбурн, Австралія
РОМАНІВА Стефана Ільковича - голову Союзу українських організацій Австралії, генерального секретаря Світового конгресу українців, м.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Лист подяки від посла України, д-ра Миколи Кулініча</title>
      <link>https://ozeukes.com/politics/a-letter-of-thanks-from-the-ambassador-of-ukraine-dr-mykola-kulinich/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 31 May 2016 07:32:17 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ozeukes.com/politics/a-letter-of-thanks-from-the-ambassador-of-ukraine-dr-mykola-kulinich/</guid>
      <description>Лист подяки від посла України, д-ра Миколи Кулініча за організацію його робочого візиту до штату Вікторії.
Ми дякуємо д-ру Кулінічу за візит до Вікторії і за завзяті зусилля, щоб зустрітися з такою кількістю різних груп в нашій спільноті!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Australian-Ukrainians relieved at release of pilot Nadiya Savchenko</title>
      <link>https://ozeukes.com/politics/australian-ukrainians-relieved-at-release-of-pilot-nadiya-savchenko/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 May 2016 22:22:07 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ozeukes.com/politics/australian-ukrainians-relieved-at-release-of-pilot-nadiya-savchenko/</guid>
      <description>27 May 2016
MEDIA RELEASE **Australian—Ukrainians relieved at release of pilot Nadiya Savchenko ** The Australian Federation of Ukrainian Organisations (AFUO) welcomes the release of pilot Nadiya Savchenko after two years of political imprisonment by the Russian Federation.
The thirty five year old Savchenko was handed a 22-year sentence when a Russian court convicted her of directing artillery fire that killed two Russian journalists during combat in eastern Ukraine in June 2014.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>UKRAINE’S AMBASSADOR TO AUSTRALIA VISITING VICTORIA TO PROMOTE  MESSAGE OF GRATITUDE AND THAT UKRAINE IS OPEN FOR BUSINESS</title>
      <link>https://ozeukes.com/politics/ukraines-ambassador-to-australia-visiting-victoria-to-promote-message-of-gratitude-and-that-ukraine-is-open-for-business/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 May 2016 03:34:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ozeukes.com/politics/ukraines-ambassador-to-australia-visiting-victoria-to-promote-message-of-gratitude-and-that-ukraine-is-open-for-business/</guid>
      <description>**May 26, 2016 **
MEDIA RELEASE UKRAINE’S AMBASSADOR TO AUSTRALIA VISITING VICTORIA TO PROMOTE MESSAGE OF GRATITUDE AND THAT UKRAINE IS OPEN FOR BUSINESS Ukraine’s Ambassador to Australia, His Excellency Mykola Kulinich commences his official Victorian visit today May 26, 2016.
The visit is being facilitated and hosted by the Australian Federation of Ukrainian Organisations(AFUO) and the Association of Ukrainians in Victoria.(AUV)
The AFUO has facilitated a wide-ranging list of meetings for the Ambassador during his stay which include meetings with:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Community Meeting with His Excellency Dr Mykola Kulinich</title>
      <link>https://ozeukes.com/events/community-meeting-with-his-excellency-dr-mykola-kulinich/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 May 2016 07:28:49 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ozeukes.com/events/community-meeting-with-his-excellency-dr-mykola-kulinich/</guid>
      <description>Community Meeting with His Excellency Dr. Mykola Kulinich Ambassador of Ukraine to Australia. The Association of Ukrainians in Victoria invite all to attend a presentation from His Excellency on the topic of developing Ukrainian Australian relations and also the Embassy and Community in partnership.
All welcome with an opportunity for questions and discussion.
Sunday, May 29 at 2 PM Ukrainian House | 3-11 Russell Street Essendon
Facebook event page: https://www.facebook.com/events/1549516285353158/</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>UKRAINE’S POSITION AND THE UKRAINIAN COMMUNITY IN AUSTRALIA’S SUPPORT FOR UKRAINE</title>
      <link>https://ozeukes.com/politics/ukraines-position-and-the-ukrainian-community-in-australias-support-for-ukraine/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 May 2016 07:32:39 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ozeukes.com/politics/ukraines-position-and-the-ukrainian-community-in-australias-support-for-ukraine/</guid>
      <description>May 9, 2016
PRESENTING UKRAINE’S POSITION AND THE UKRAINIAN COMMUNITY IN AUSTRALIA’S SUPPORT FOR UKRAINE TO JOINT STANDING COMMITTEE OF FOREIGN AFFAIRS, DEFENCE AND TRADE On Wednesday May 4, 2016 The Ambassador of Ukraine Dr Mykola Kulinich and Mr. Stefan Romaniw Chairman of the Australian Federation of Ukrainian Organizations (AFUO) presented about the situation in Ukraine to the Australian Parliament’s Joint Standing Committee of Foreign Affairs, Defence and Trade. They advocated for the Australian Government to support Ukraine in moving forward and standing against Russian aggression.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Світовий Конґрес Українців запрошує громаду долучитися до оновлення архіву</title>
      <link>https://ozeukes.com/community/ukrainian-world-congress-invites-community-to-contribute-to-archives/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 May 2016 07:21:28 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ozeukes.com/community/ukrainian-world-congress-invites-community-to-contribute-to-archives/</guid>
      <description>20 квітня 2016 р.
ЗАКЛИК ДО ГРОМАДИ
Світовий Конґрес Українців запрошує громаду долучитися до оновлення архіву
Світовий Конґрес Українців (СКУ) відзначає своє 50-річчя у 2017 р. серією ювілейних заходів з метою залучити українців і неукраїнців діаспори та України до святкування цієї надзвичайної події.
У рамках підготовки до цього свята ми оновлюємо архіви СКУ, щоб забезпечити належним чином збереження задокументованих історичних матеріалів СКУ для майбутніх поколінь.
З цього приводу ми звертаємося до громади з проханням.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Victor Rudewych receives his O.A.M.</title>
      <link>https://ozeukes.com/community/victor-rudewych-receives-his-o-a-m/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Apr 2016 07:13:49 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ozeukes.com/community/victor-rudewych-receives-his-o-a-m/</guid>
      <description>(Re-posted from http://catholicukes.org.au/victor-rudewych-receives-o-m/)
The Governor of Victoria, Her Excellency the Honourable Linda Dessau, on Friday April 15, 2016 investitured Victor Ivan Rudewych with his Order of Australia Medal (O.A.M.).
About 100 Victorians received their awards as well in 10 separate categories. There were about 400 guests in the Grand Hall for the occasion.
Victor’s wife, Marijka and his children Juliana and Timothy were present as well as Bishop Peter Stasiuk, who represented the Ukrainian community at the event.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>#ourcommunity campaign</title>
      <link>https://ozeukes.com/community/ourcommunity-campaign/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 17 Apr 2016 13:30:57 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ozeukes.com/community/ourcommunity-campaign/</guid>
      <description>17-го квітня 2016
#ourcommunity campaign Українська громада в Австралії – Жива – Жвава – Цікава Нова кампанія через соціальні мережі __Українська спільнота в Австралії, жвава, цікава, різна, яка постійно розвивається. Maємо різні віровизнання.
У ній знайдете різні організації, структури та зайняття. Кожна людина може знайти себе та своє місце.
При управі Союзу Українських Організацій Австралії ( СУОА ) маємо творчу референтуру Комунікації – Керівником Соцмережі, є молода енергійна людина, Соня Рамза, яка запропонувала цікаву програму, щоб можна було висвілити позитивні елементи нашої громади в Австралії.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Strengthening ties with the Ukrainian Embassy</title>
      <link>https://ozeukes.com/gallery/strengthening-ties-with-the-ukrainian-embassy/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Apr 2016 07:25:16 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ozeukes.com/gallery/strengthening-ties-with-the-ukrainian-embassy/</guid>
      <description>Dnister team members had the pleasure of meeting with His Excellency, Ukrainian Ambassador to Australia, The Honourable Dr Mykola Kulinich and his Embassy team in Canberra this past week, 6th April 2016.
Read the full story here.
View the photos from the event here.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>AFUO CHAIRMAN&#39;S UKRAINE VISIT UPDATE 14-20 MARCH 2016</title>
      <link>https://ozeukes.com/politics/afuo-chairmans-ukraine-visit-update-14-20-march-2016/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Mar 2016 10:03:24 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ozeukes.com/politics/afuo-chairmans-ukraine-visit-update-14-20-march-2016/</guid>
      <description>AFUO CHAIRMAN&#39;S UKRAINE VISIT UPDATE 14-20 MARCH 2016 I am currently in Kyiv for a working week of meetings. As part of Ukrainian World Congress (UWC) Delegation we have had a series of meetings as outlined below.
Issues raised are also listed in point form below.
Currently the issue of Ukraine’s political leadership is at the forefront. It is anticipated that there will be a change of PM on one hand, yet others are taking the line that there is stability and no need for change.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>AFUO CALL TO ACTION - CRIMEA BELONGS TO UKRAINE</title>
      <link>https://ozeukes.com/politics/afuo-call-to-action-crimea-belongs-to-ukraine/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Mar 2016 21:51:35 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ozeukes.com/politics/afuo-call-to-action-crimea-belongs-to-ukraine/</guid>
      <description>AFUO CALL TO ACTION WRITE, RING, VISIT YOUR FEDERAL MEMBER OF PARLIAMENT OVER THE NEXT WEEK CRIMEA BELONGS TO UKRAINE
The internationally recognised Ukrainian territory of Crimea was annexed by the Russian Federation on 18 March 2014.
Окупація Автономної Республіки Крим та м. Севастополя Росією — збройна агресія Росії спрямована на насильницьке протиправне відторгнення Кримської автономії та Севастополя від України та їх приєднання до Російської Федерації на правах суб&#39;єктів Російської Федерації, що було здійснено протягом березня 2014 року.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ukrainian community to hold Flash Mob Rally at Russian Embassy in Canberra</title>
      <link>https://ozeukes.com/politics/ukrainian-community-to-hold-flash-mob-rally-at-russian-embassy-in-canberra/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Mar 2016 21:00:51 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ozeukes.com/politics/ukrainian-community-to-hold-flash-mob-rally-at-russian-embassy-in-canberra/</guid>
      <description>**March 9, 2016 **
MEDIA RELEASE Ukrainian community to hold Flash Mob Rally at Russian Embassy Canberra demanding the release of Nadiya Savchenko #FreeSavchenko
The Australian Federation of Ukrainian Organisations (AFUO) will coordinate a small **Flash Mob Rally outside the Russian Embassy in Canberra –Wednesday March 9, 2016 at 10.45am ** to demand the release of former Ukrainian Air Force pilot, Nadiya Savchenko
The AFUO Chairman Stefan Romaniw will also endeavour to hand the Russian Ambassador Mr Vladimir Moroz or his staff a protest letter demanding:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Надія є! #FreeSavchenko! Заява Проводу ОУН (б)</title>
      <link>https://ozeukes.com/politics/freesavchenko-statement-by-ounb/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Mar 2016 20:57:09 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ozeukes.com/politics/freesavchenko-statement-by-ounb/</guid>
      <description>**Надія є! ****#**FreeSavchenko!
Для країн Заходу людське життя є найвищою цінністю. Так, зокрема під час бойових дій американський, німецький чи ізраїльський уряди готові на відчайдушні кроки, щоб визволити бранців, що перебувають в руках ворога. Україна, яка перебуває в стані війни, має не один десяток осіб, що перебувають в полоні російсько-терористичного режиму та їх маріонеток «днр-лнр». Савченко, Сенцов, Карпюк… Список наших громадян, незаконно ув’язнених в Росії, є набагато більшим, а отже поточна ціль української держави – в будь який спосіб визволити їх.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>AUSTRALIA’S UKRAINIAN COMMUNITY CALL TO ACTION #FreeSavchenko</title>
      <link>https://ozeukes.com/politics/australias-ukrainian-community-call-to-action-freesavchenko/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 Mar 2016 05:50:03 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ozeukes.com/politics/australias-ukrainian-community-call-to-action-freesavchenko/</guid>
      <description>March 7,2016
AUSTRALIA’S UKRAINIAN COMMUNITY CALL TO ACTION #FreeSavchenko The Australian Federation of Ukrainian Organisations urges the international community, including human rights organisations and women’s organisations to demand the immediate release by Russian authorities of former Ukrainian Air Force pilot, Member of Ukrainian Parliament and delegate to the Parliamentary Assembly of the Council of Europe, Lieutenant Nadiya Savchenko, who remains imprisoned for political considerations.
The AFUO has called on the Prime Minister of Australia to make representation to PM Putin and the Minister for Foreign Affairs to make representation to the Embassy of the Russian Federation on Canberra demanding Savchenko’s immediate release and condemn this act of violation of human rights.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ОБІЖНИК СУОА Ч. 5. 2015-2018 - ЗВІДОМЛЕННЯ УПРАВИ СУОА ПРО ЗБІРКИ ТА ПРОГРАМИ</title>
      <link>https://ozeukes.com/community/obiznyk-cyoa-no-5-2015-2018/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Feb 2016 06:15:46 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ozeukes.com/community/obiznyk-cyoa-no-5-2015-2018/</guid>
      <description>29 лютого 2016
ОБІЖНИК СУОА Ч. 5. 2015 – 2018 ЗВІДОМЛЕННЯ УПРАВИ СУОА ПРО ЗБІРКИ ТА ПРОГРАМИ:
 * **U-HELP** * **ROTARY - CARITAS TAX DEDUCTABILITY** * **СКУ - ПРОГРАМА ЗАХИСТ ПАТРІОТІВ ТА ГУМАНІТАРНІ ІНІЦІЯТИВИ**  Управа Союзу Українських Організацій Австралії повідомляє, що далі продовжуються збіркові акції:
 * **U-HELP HUMANITARIAN - EDUCATIONAL - LEADERSHIP PROGRAM** * **ROTARY - CARITAS - Tax Deductable Program**  Війна на сході України продовжується, наслідки цієї кривавої війни катастрофічні.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Управа CУОA вітає  Віктора Рудевича з отриманням Ордена Aвстралії ОAМ</title>
      <link>https://ozeukes.com/community/afuo-congratulates-victor-rudewych-on-receiving-order-of-australia-medal/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Jan 2016 19:40:12 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ozeukes.com/community/afuo-congratulates-victor-rudewych-on-receiving-order-of-australia-medal/</guid>
      <description>26.1.2016
Управа CУОA вітає  Віктора Рудевича з отриманням Ордена Aвстралії ОAМ Управа CУОA вітає Віктора Рудевича з отриманням Ордена Aвстралії за заслуги в праці в українській громаді.
Віктор Рудевич, громадський діяч, та активіст. Разом з дружиною Марійлою є великими меценатами на різні цілі.
Бажаємо дальших успіхів.
AFUO CONGRATULATES VICTOR RUDEWYCH ON RECEIVING ORDER OF AUSTRALIA MEDAL The Australian Federation of Ukrainian Organisations congratulates
VICTOR RUDEWYCH **** ОAМ
on receiving and Order of Australia medal for services to the Ukrainian community.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Інтерв’ю на SBS Ukrainian Radio</title>
      <link>https://ozeukes.com/media/interview-sbs-ukrainian-jan-2016/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 24 Jan 2016 23:04:36 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ozeukes.com/media/interview-sbs-ukrainian-jan-2016/</guid>
      <description>[ ](http://www.sbs.com.au/yourlanguage/ukrainian/uk/content/ukrayina-avstraliya-poglyad-v-minule-ta-u-maybuttya?language=uk)УКРАЇНА – АВСТРАЛІЯ: ПОГЛЯД В МИНУЛЕ ТА У МАЙБУТТЯ&amp;hellip;
Інтерв&#39;ю з др. Миколою Кулінічем, Надзвичайним і Повноважним Послом України в Австралії.
http://www.sbs.com.au/yourlanguage/ukrainian/uk/content/ukrayina-avstraliya-poglyad-v-minule-ta-u-maybuttya?language=uk
  [ ](http://www.sbs.com.au/yourlanguage/ukrainian/uk/content/folkneri-z-kiieva-do-melburna?language=uk)&amp;quot;ФОЛЬКНЕРИ&amp;rdquo;: З КИЄВА ДО МЕЛЬБУРНА
Українські музиканти гурту &amp;ldquo;Фолькнери&amp;rdquo; Ярина Квітка і Володимир Муляр на велосипедax доїхали до Австралії. Запланований маршрут розтягнувся на 25 тис кілометрів&amp;hellip;
http://www.sbs.com.au/yourlanguage/ukrainian/uk/content/folkneri-z-kiieva-do-melburna?language=uk</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>GATEWAY TRAVEL – CRIMEAN TOURS – AFUO PROTEST FOLLOW UP</title>
      <link>https://ozeukes.com/politics/gateway-travel-crimean-tours-afuo-protest-follow-up/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Jan 2016 12:02:26 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ozeukes.com/politics/gateway-travel-crimean-tours-afuo-protest-follow-up/</guid>
      <description>GATEWAY TRAVEL – CRIMEAN TOURS – AFUO PROTEST FOLLOW UP Further to our recent media release in relation to Gateway Travel plans to organise Tours to Crimea in 2016 the Australian Federation of Ukrainian Organisations has
a) written to the CEO and Manager of Gateway Ms Tonia Kisliakov stating that the AFUO deplores their plan for these tours. The letter was cc to Department of Foreign Affairs and Trade and also Australian Federation of Travel Agents (AFTA).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sydney travel firm offering Crimea tour accused of &#39;selling out&#39; to MH17 accused</title>
      <link>https://ozeukes.com/politics/sydney-travel-firm-offering-crimea-tour-accused-of-selling-out-to-mh17-accused/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Jan 2016 11:26:16 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ozeukes.com/politics/sydney-travel-firm-offering-crimea-tour-accused-of-selling-out-to-mh17-accused/</guid>
      <description>An Australian travel company has been accused of “selling out” to those blamed for the shooting down of flight MH17 after announcing plans to organise tours of Crimea, which was annexed by Russia two years ago.
Read the full story at theguardian&amp;hellip;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Former PM Tony Abbott mobbed after shirtfront mention as he receives Ukrainian freedom gong in Melbourne</title>
      <link>https://ozeukes.com/media/former-pm-tony-abbott-mobbed-after-shirtfront-mention-as-he-receives-ukrainian-freedom-gong-in-melbourne/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 Dec 2015 06:38:09 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ozeukes.com/media/former-pm-tony-abbott-mobbed-after-shirtfront-mention-as-he-receives-ukrainian-freedom-gong-in-melbourne/</guid>
      <description>FORMER PM Tony Abbott was mobbed by Ukrainian community supporters today after he recalled his famous “shirtfront” comment against Russian President Vladimir Putin.
Mr Abbott received a hero’s welcome at an Australia-Ukraine business forum in Carlton where he was given an inaugural freedom award for his support of Ukraine against Russian aggression.
Read more&amp;hellip;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>AFUO XVII TRIENNIAL GENERAL MEETING ELECTS NEW LEADERSHIP - ВІДБУВCЯ XVII ЗЇЗД CОЗЮУ УКРAЇНCЬКИХ ОРГAНІЗAЦІЙ AВCТРAЛІЇ - ЖИВA І БУДЮЧA AТМОCФЕРA</title>
      <link>https://ozeukes.com/events/afuo-xvii-triennial-general-meeting-elects-new-leadership/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Dec 2015 12:37:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ozeukes.com/events/afuo-xvii-triennial-general-meeting-elects-new-leadership/</guid>
      <description>December 5, 2015
MEDIA RELEASE
AFUO XVII TRIENNIAL GENERAL MEETING ELECTS NEW LEADERSHIP The AFUO held its XVII Zjizd today in Melbourne. Delegates received reports for 2012-2015 period and elected its new leadership for 2015-2018.
A new Executive headed by Stefan Romaniw was elected.
Other elected members for 2015-2018: Stephen Chomyn, Orysia Stefyn, Iryna Andreeva, Jarema Polatajko, Yurij Tkacz, Luba Pryshlak, Taras Galas, Lydia Gibala.
Audit Committee: Chair: George Fedyszyn; Members: Eugene Stefyn Maria Verbovetski, Roman Rozek</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>В гостях у «Фонду оборони країни» українець з Австралії Дмитро Легейда</title>
      <link>https://ozeukes.com/community/v-gostyah-u-fondu-oboroni-krayini-ukrayinets-z-avstraliyi-dmitro-legeyda/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Jul 2015 12:20:34 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ozeukes.com/community/v-gostyah-u-fondu-oboroni-krayini-ukrayinets-z-avstraliyi-dmitro-legeyda/</guid>
      <description>У «Фонд оборони країни» завітав наш добрий товариш Дмитро Легейда з Австралії. Саме він минулого року організував збір коштів серед української громади Західної Австралії та її друзів з інших штатів та країн світу для закупки препарату Celox для українських бійців.
Про рік війни, сучасну обстановку на Сході нашої країни, плани «Фонду» та подальшу співпрацю з Дмитром говорили Павло Хазан – голова «Фонду» та Наталя Хазан – волонтер «Фонду». Дмитро був захоплений кількістю проектів, якими успішно займається «Фонд»: «Я вражений тим, що крім медичної допомоги, «Фонд оборони країни» успішно втілює у життя надзвичайно широкий діапазон проектів: це і встановлення найсучаснішого зв’язку безпосередньо в зоні АТО, і відео спостереження на стратегічних об’єктах, організація і розгортання координаційно-командних центрів, і створення зони відпочинку для військових, що їдуть через Дніпропетровськ, а також пропаганда «України в Україні» серед населення на підконтрольних Україні територіях в зоні АТО».</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Подяка від &#34;Захисту Патріотів&#34;</title>
      <link>https://ozeukes.com/community/patriot-defence-podiaka/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Jul 2015 07:04:12 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ozeukes.com/community/patriot-defence-podiaka/</guid>
      <description>Світовий Конґрес Українців
Гуманітарна ініціатива &amp;ldquo;Захист Патріотів&amp;rdquo;
_висловлює подяку _
окремим особам та українським організаціям Австралії
За сприяння у розвитку тактичної медицини в Україні шляхом підготовки військовослужбовців, що захищають територіальну цілісність й недоторканність України та забезпечення індивідуальними аптечками-IFAK за стандартами НАТО для збереження їх життів.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Інтерв&#39;ю на SBS Ukrainian Radio</title>
      <link>https://ozeukes.com/community/sbs_ukrainian_radio_interviews_feb_mar_2015/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Mar 2015 06:32:16 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ozeukes.com/community/sbs_ukrainian_radio_interviews_feb_mar_2015/</guid>
      <description>**ВІЙНА В УКРАЇНІ, ФОКСТЕЛ З ФЕIРФАКС І УКРАЇНСЬКА СПІЛЬНОТА В АВСТРАЛІЇ**
Богдан Рудницький веде розмову із Головою Союзу Українських Організацій Австралії (СУОА) Стефаном Романівим. Мова йде про війну в Україні та, зокрема, і про російський телеканал Russia Today, який транслюється через Фокстел. СУОА не сприймає позицію Фокстела щодо російської пропаґанди на австралійських глядачів&amp;hellip;
Частина 1: http://www.sbs.com.au/yourlanguage/ukrainian/highlight/page/id/394283/t/THE-WAR-IN-UKRANE-FOXTEL-WITH-FAIRFAX-AND-UKRAINIAN-COMMUNITY-IN-AUSTRALIA
Частина 2: http://www.sbs.com.au/yourlanguage/ukrainian/highlight/page/id/395820/t/2.-THE-WAR-IN-UKRANE,-FOXTEL-WITH-FAIRFAX-AND-UKRAINIAN-COMMUNITY-IN&amp;ndash;AUSTRALIA/
**МІЖНАРОДНИЙ КОНКУРС З УКРАЇНСЬКОЇ МОВИ ІМ. П. ЯЦИКА В АВСТРАЛІЇ У 2015 РОЦІ**</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Інтерв&#39;ю на SBS Ukrainian Radio</title>
      <link>https://ozeukes.com/media/sbs_ukrainian_radio_interviews_oct_2014/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Oct 2014 10:26:39 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ozeukes.com/media/sbs_ukrainian_radio_interviews_oct_2014/</guid>
      <description>ЦИРК ДЮ СОЛЕЙЛ ЗНОВУ ПРИБУВАЄ ДО АВСТРАЛІЇ
Богдан Рудницький веде розмову із артистом Жаном Йордановим з України, який тепер працює у Цирку дю Солейл і разом з цим колективом прибуває до Австралії, де у Сіднеї з 28-го жовтня розпочнуться їхні виступи&amp;hellip;
http://www.sbs.com.au/yourlanguage/ukrainian/highlight/page/id/365698/t/CIRQUE-DU-SOLEIL-IS-RETURNING-TO-AUSTRALIA
ПРО ЖИТТЯ ПЛАСТУ В СВІТІ
Богдан Рудницький веде розмову із п-і Мартою Кузьмович, головою Головної Пластової Булави із США - речницею світової молодечої організації ПЛАСТ&amp;hellip;
http://www.sbs.com.au/yourlanguage/ukrainian/highlight/page/id/362637/t/ABOUT-THE-PLAST-AROUND-THE-WORLD
«КОЛИ Я ЗАЙМАЮСЯ ЖИВОПИСОМ, ТО ПРАЦЮЮ ДО ОСТАННІХ СИЛ, А ІНОДІ НАВІТЬ ДО ЗНЕМОГИ&amp;hellip;»</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Do You Want To Help Ukraine?</title>
      <link>https://ozeukes.com/community/do-you-want-to-help-ukraine/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Sep 2014 02:44:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ozeukes.com/community/do-you-want-to-help-ukraine/</guid>
      <description>Богдан Рудницький веде розмову із провідником української спільноти Стефаном Романівим, котрий є головою Управи Союзу Українських Організацій Австралії та Генеральним Секретарем Світового Конґресу Українців - мова про ситуацію в Україні та як можна допомогти Україні&amp;hellip;
http://www.sbs.com.au/yourlanguage/ukrainian/highlight/page/id/361102/t/DO-YOU-WANT-TO-HELP-UKRAINE-/</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>U-HELP Update</title>
      <link>https://ozeukes.com/current-affairs/u-help-update/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Sep 2014 02:40:15 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ozeukes.com/current-affairs/u-help-update/</guid>
      <description>UHELP UPDATE  * **Nearly 4500 personnel trained in Combat Life Saving** * **Some 3500 IFAKs (Improved First Aid Kits) distributed**  The AFUO’s UHELP (Ukrainian Humanitarian, Educational and Leadership Program) has raised some $30,000 to date in Australia to support the first aid training of Ukrainian service personnel and to provide advanced first aid equipment as part of Ukraine’s self-defence.
This has helped to fund nearly 4500 personnel being trained in Combat Life Saving, and some 3500 IFAKs (Improved First Aid Kits) being distributed – which means that lives have been saved by your support during the most recent invasion by Mr Putin’s forces.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>АКЦІЯ СУОА Неділя 24 серпня –День Незалежності та Синьо - Жовтий День</title>
      <link>https://ozeukes.com/current-affairs/%d0%b0%d0%ba%d1%86%d1%96%d1%8f-%d1%81%d1%83%d0%be%d0%b0-%d0%bd%d0%b5%d0%b4%d1%96%d0%bb%d1%8f-24-%d1%81%d0%b5%d1%80%d0%bf%d0%bd%d1%8f-%d0%b4%d0%b5%d0%bd%d1%8c-%d0%bd%d0%b5%d0%b7%d0%b0%d0%bb/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Aug 2014 00:45:30 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ozeukes.com/current-affairs/%d0%b0%d0%ba%d1%86%d1%96%d1%8f-%d1%81%d1%83%d0%be%d0%b0-%d0%bd%d0%b5%d0%b4%d1%96%d0%bb%d1%8f-24-%d1%81%d0%b5%d1%80%d0%bf%d0%bd%d1%8f-%d0%b4%d0%b5%d0%bd%d1%8c-%d0%bd%d0%b5%d0%b7%d0%b0%d0%bb/</guid>
      <description>АКЦІЯ СУОА Неділя 24 серпня – День Незалежності та Синьо - Жовтий День Дорогі Друзі! Союз Українських Організацій Австралії закликає підтримати заклик президента України Петра Порошенка напередодні Дня Незалежності зробити жовто - блакитним увесь світ, підтримати ініціативу “Наші Кольори”, яка присвячується українському прапору.
Прикрашайте синьо – жовтими кольорами свої будинки, автомобілі, офіси, одягайте жовто – блакитний одяг, забарвлюйте цими кольрами місця перебування.
Адже навіть у Москві невідомі розфарбували зірку на шпилі одного із сталінських висоток у кольори українського прапора та встановили на ній прапор України.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Media Release: PRESIDENT OF UKRAINE AND AUSTRALIA&#39;S PRIME MINISTER DISCUSS POTENTIAL OF OPENING AUSTRALIAN EMBASSY IN KYIV</title>
      <link>https://ozeukes.com/current-affairs/media-release-president-of-ukraine-and-australias-prime-minister-discuss-potential-of-opening-australian-embassy-in-kyiv/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 16 Aug 2014 00:29:47 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ozeukes.com/current-affairs/media-release-president-of-ukraine-and-australias-prime-minister-discuss-potential-of-opening-australian-embassy-in-kyiv/</guid>
      <description>**MEDIA RELEASE: **
**PRESIDENT OF UKRAINE AND AUSTRALIA&#39;S PRIME MINISTER **DISCUSS POTENTIAL OF OPENING AUSTRALIAN EMBASSY IN KYIV From the Office of the President of Ukraine
** Australia is willing to provide assistance to the regions of the Donbas affected by the actions of militants**
President of Ukraine Petro Poroshenko had a phone conversation with Prime Minister of Australia Tony Abbott.
The Australian Prime Minister expressed gratitude to Ukraine and personally to the President for the assistance that Ukraine gave in the course of the international investigation of Malaysia Airlines aircraft tragedy which ended up with 38 Australian citizens dead.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Condolence statement from the leadership of the Ukrainian Catholic Church</title>
      <link>https://ozeukes.com/community/condolence-statement-from-the-leadership-of-the-ukrainian-catholic-church/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 Jul 2014 05:31:37 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ozeukes.com/community/condolence-statement-from-the-leadership-of-the-ukrainian-catholic-church/</guid>
      <description>Condolences from the Ukrainian Catholic Church to the Family and Friends of the Victims of Flight MH17 The incredible has happened to Australian citizens and so many of other countries, including the Netherlands, Malaysia, Indonesia, the United Kingdom, Germany, Belgium, Philippines, New Zealand, Canada, and the United States of America.
The terrorist attack on the Malaysian Airlines Flight 17 has violently ended the promising, creative, fruitful lives of hundreds of innocent people.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Urgent action regarding Russia-backed terrorism</title>
      <link>https://ozeukes.com/current-affairs/urgent-action-regarding-russia-backed-terrorism/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 25 Jul 2014 06:10:21 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ozeukes.com/current-affairs/urgent-action-regarding-russia-backed-terrorism/</guid>
      <description>24 July 2014
** His Excellency Tony Abbott** ** Prime Minister of Australia** ** G20 President**
Parliament House Canberra ACT 2600 Australia
Dear Prime Minister:
** Re: Urgent action regarding Russia-backed terrorism**
****On behalf of the Ukrainian World Congress and the Ukrainian diaspora, please accept our condolences following the tragic deaths of some 30 Australian citizens and residents on Malaysian Airlines Flight MH17. It is an unspeakable loss for your nation.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Matthew Guy Backs Ukrainian Australian Program U-Help</title>
      <link>https://ozeukes.com/current-affairs/matthew-guy-backs-ukrainian-australian-program-u-help/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 25 Jul 2014 05:28:41 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ozeukes.com/current-affairs/matthew-guy-backs-ukrainian-australian-program-u-help/</guid>
      <description>Read the full article on the Herald Sun website -
http://www.heraldsun.com.au/news/victoria/matthew-guy-backs-ukrainian-australian-program-uhelp-to-assist-victims-of-ukraine-conflict/story-fni0fit3-1226998861737?nk=594d07dd2514fbc43f6a78a6221bc7c5</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Call to Action: Update on the Current Situation in Ukraine</title>
      <link>https://ozeukes.com/current-affairs/call-to-action-update-on-the-current-situation-in-ukraine/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Jul 2014 01:59:17 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ozeukes.com/current-affairs/call-to-action-update-on-the-current-situation-in-ukraine/</guid>
      <description>AN UPDATE FROM THE AUSTRALIAN FEDERATION OF UKRAINIAN ORGANISATIONS ON THE CURRENT SITUATION IN UKRAINE
Call to ACTION The Australian Federation of Ukrainian Organisations (AFUO) has been actively involved in setting and supporting humanitarian aid for Ukrainian Armed Forces and Volunteers in the form of battle first aid training, first aid packs and other equipment . In the current tension and climate this area of support has been acknowledged as area of need by officials in Ukraine.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Media Release: Ukrainian Peak Body Supports Prime Minister Abbott</title>
      <link>https://ozeukes.com/current-affairs/media-release-ukrainian-peak-body-supports-prime-minister-abbott/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 19 Jul 2014 02:16:55 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ozeukes.com/current-affairs/media-release-ukrainian-peak-body-supports-prime-minister-abbott/</guid>
      <description>MEDIA RELEASE
** **
UKRAINAN PEAK BODY SUPPORTS PRIME MINISTER ABBOTT
&amp;ldquo;Let me conclude with this, the bullying of small countries by big ones, the trampling of justice and decency in the pursuit of national aggrandisement and reckless indifference to human life should have no place in our world.&amp;rdquo; – Prime Minister of Australia, the Hon. Tony Abbott MP (July 18, Canberra, Australia)
The peak body for the Ukrainian community in Australia says that the appropriate stance by Prime Minister Tony Abbott in response to MH17 is being strongly acknowledged in Ukraine and is a good model for world leaders.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Open Letter the Honourable Trade Ministers participating in the G20 Trade Ministers meeting in Sydney, Australia, on 19 July 2014</title>
      <link>https://ozeukes.com/current-affairs/open-letter-the-honourable-trade-ministers-participating-in-the-g20-trade-ministers-meeting-in-sydney-australia-on-19-july-2014/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 19 Jul 2014 02:13:22 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ozeukes.com/current-affairs/open-letter-the-honourable-trade-ministers-participating-in-the-g20-trade-ministers-meeting-in-sydney-australia-on-19-july-2014/</guid>
      <description>18 July 2014
OPEN LETTER
Honourable Trade Ministers
participating in the G20 Trade Ministers meeting
in Sydney, Australia, 19 July 2014
Attention: G20 Taskforce
Department of the Prime Minister and Cabinet
PO Box 6500
Canberra ACT 2600
Australia
G20info@pmc.gov.au
Honourable Ministers: Re: Urgent action regarding Russia-backed terrorism in Eastern Ukraine As you convene in Sydney, Australia, on 19 July 2014 to discuss the trade actions G20 members are taking as part of their comprehensive growth strategies, the Ukrainian World Congress urges you,</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PLANE TRAGEDY: UKRAINIANS IN AUSTRALIA EXPRESS SYMPATHY; CONDEMN ACT BY PUTIN&#39;S TERRORISTS; CALL ON AUSTRALIAN GOVT TO BAN PUTIN</title>
      <link>https://ozeukes.com/current-affairs/9168/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Jul 2014 13:14:25 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ozeukes.com/current-affairs/9168/</guid>
      <description>MEDIA RELEASE PLANE TRAGEDY: UKRAINIANS IN AUSTRALIA EXPRESS SYMPATHY; CONDEMN ACT BY PUTIN&#39;S TERRORISTS; CALL ON AUSTRALIAN GOVT TO BAN PUTIN The Australian Federation of Ukrainian Organisations (AFUO) offers its most sincere condolences to the families and friends of the innocent civilians who lost their lives today at the hands of Putin-backed terrorists, following the downing of Malaysian Airlines flight MH 17 over eastern Ukraine.
AFUO calls on Australian Government to take a lead on banning Russian Federation representation at G20 discussions this weekend in Sydney and the G20 Summit in Brisbane in November.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>U-HELP: Your Chance To Help Ukraine</title>
      <link>https://ozeukes.com/community/u-help-your-chance-to-help-ukraine/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 Jul 2014 02:52:05 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ozeukes.com/community/u-help-your-chance-to-help-ukraine/</guid>
      <description>U-HELP (the Ukrainian Humanitarian Educational and Leadership Program) is announced by the Australian Federation of Ukrainian Organisations (AFUO) as the endorsed way for Australians to support Ukraine’s sovereignty, democracy and path to peace and prosperity.
The objectives of U-HELP, an official initiative of the AFUO, are:
 * To fund humanitarian and medical assistance for people injured in the self-defence of Ukraine, and; * To support educational and leadership initiatives that promote Ukraine’s democratisation and prosperity through increased Ukraine-Australia social, political and economic ties.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Media Release: Condemnation of Racial Attack on Ukrainian Catholic Church in Lidcombe</title>
      <link>https://ozeukes.com/current-affairs/media-release-condemnation-of-racial-attack-on-ukrainian-catholic-church-in-lidcombe/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Jun 2014 03:22:05 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ozeukes.com/current-affairs/media-release-condemnation-of-racial-attack-on-ukrainian-catholic-church-in-lidcombe/</guid>
      <description>**MEDIA RELEASE - **JOINT MEDIA RELEASE
** CRAIG LAUNDY MP** ** Federal Member for Reid**
THE HON. BARBARA PERRY State Member for Auburn
22 June 2014
CONDEMNATION OF RACIAL ATTACK ON UKRAINIAN CATHOLIC CHURCH IN LIDCOMBE The racially motivated vandalism and desecration of St. Andrew’s Ukrainian Catholic Church in Lidcombe was jointly condemned today by the Federal Member for Reid, Craig Laundy MP, and the State Member for Auburn, the Hon.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Removal of Graffiti from Ukrainian Catholic Church Lidcombe</title>
      <link>https://ozeukes.com/community/removal-of-graffiti-from-ukrainian-catholic-church-lidcombe/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Jun 2014 03:06:11 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ozeukes.com/community/removal-of-graffiti-from-ukrainian-catholic-church-lidcombe/</guid>
      <description>МАРІЧКА ГАЛАБУРДА - ЧИГРИН
Люди, які були в неділю 22.6.2014 в церкві, були у шоку від побаченого знечещення будинку церкви, залі, вікон, стін, ітд., що сталося в ночі з п&amp;quot;ятниці 20.6 на суботу 21.6. Деякі плакали. Одне бачити по телебаченню, всі же телевізійні канали подавали субота 21.6. по новинах кадри з нашої церкви, й інтервю з отцем Симоном Цькуєм, Славком Думою, Петром Шміґелом - а бачити на власні очі йнакше&amp;hellip;Це все жах !</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Open Letter In Response to Church Vandalism Lidcome NSW</title>
      <link>https://ozeukes.com/community/open-letter-in-response-to-church-vandalism-lidcome-nsw/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Jun 2014 22:51:42 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ozeukes.com/community/open-letter-in-response-to-church-vandalism-lidcome-nsw/</guid>
      <description>****
OPEN LETTER
FROM
THE CHAIRMAN OF THE AUSTRALIAN FEDERATION
OF UKRAINIAN ORGANISATIONS
IN RESPONSE TO UN AUSTRALIAN ACT - THE CHURCH VANDALISM , LIDCOMBE NSW
Australia&#39;s Ukrainian community is deeply distressed and disgusted at the desecration of St Andrew&#39;s Ukrainian Catholic Church in Lidcombe Sydney last night.
Vandals painted anti Ukrainian slogans on the walls of the Church.
The disgust of this act is now being expressed by the broader Australian community.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Media Release - Rally in Canberra</title>
      <link>https://ozeukes.com/current-affairs/media-release-rally-in-canberra/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 May 2014 02:21:15 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ozeukes.com/current-affairs/media-release-rally-in-canberra/</guid>
      <description>The Australian Federation of Ukrainian Organisations (AFUO) has released a press statement in regards of the &amp;lsquo;Pro-Ukraine, Anti-Putin&amp;rsquo; rally held in Canberra on May 25th 2014.
Text of statement: Media Release Canberra Anti-Putin Rally</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ukrainian Protest Rally in Canberra - Media coverage</title>
      <link>https://ozeukes.com/events/act/ukrainian-protest-rally-in-canberra-media-coverage/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 May 2014 01:49:07 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ozeukes.com/events/act/ukrainian-protest-rally-in-canberra-media-coverage/</guid>
      <description>Scores of cars from Brisbane, Melbourne and Sydney carrying Ukrainian flags drove to Canberra to take part in an AutoMaidan round the streets of Australia’s capital city on Sunday May 25th 2014, the day of Presidential elections in Ukraine. The AutoMaidan terminated in front of the Russian embassy where hundreds of peaceful protesters expressed their support for Ukraine and strong opposition to Putin’s aggression in Ukraine.
Earlier in the day many of the protesters who had Ukrainian citizenship had taken the opportunity to vote at the Ukrainian Embassy.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Media Release: Presidential Elections in Ukraine / Прес-реліз: щодо виборів Президента України</title>
      <link>https://ozeukes.com/politics/media-release-presidential-elections-in-ukraine/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 May 2014 08:01:38 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ozeukes.com/politics/media-release-presidential-elections-in-ukraine/</guid>
      <description>Media Release: On the early Presidential Elections in Ukraine The Embassy of Ukraine in Australia has issued a media release regarding the early Presidential Elections in Ukraine. The English-language version of the media release can be read here: MR (early presidential elections)
Прес-реліз: щодо позачергових виборів Президента України Посольство України в Австралії випустило прес-реліз щодо позачергових виборів Президента України. Текст прес-релізу українською мовою можна прочитати тут: ПР (позачергові вибори президента)</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>WA Ukrainian community joins National Rally</title>
      <link>https://ozeukes.com/events/western-australia/wa-ukrainian-community-joins-national-rally/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 May 2014 07:42:50 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ozeukes.com/events/western-australia/wa-ukrainian-community-joins-national-rally/</guid>
      <description>CYM (Ukrainian Youth Association of WA) and the Ukrainian Association of Western Australia (UAWA) calls on all concerned Australians to attend the FAIR ELECTIONS mean A FREE UKRAINE - PERTH RALLY The rally will voice its strong opposition to Putin’s aggression in South East Ukraine (namely Sloviansk, Donetsk, Luhansk, Mariupol, Odessa, and many other cities where the &amp;ldquo;green men&amp;rdquo; have stepped in and made fear and death a reality in Ukraine!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>National Rally in Support of Ukraine - from Sydney</title>
      <link>https://ozeukes.com/events/new-south-wales/national-rally-in-support-of-ukraine-from-sydney/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 18 May 2014 04:18:07 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ozeukes.com/events/new-south-wales/national-rally-in-support-of-ukraine-from-sydney/</guid>
      <description>AFUO-UCNSW Canberra Rally Sydney Bus May 25th 
Bookings for Sydney Bus to Canberra Rally and Ukrainian Elections Sunday May 25th 8.00am, St Andrew&#39;s Ukrainian Catholic Church, 57 Church St, Lidcombe. $25 Employed Adults, $10 pensioners/ students/ children + $1.50 booking fee each. Bus will also be picking up from Cabramatta Ukrainian Hall. Queries 0410 866 820.
Замовлення на автобус з Сіднею на акцію і на украінські вибори в Канберрі 25-го травня.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>National Rally in Support of Ukraine</title>
      <link>https://ozeukes.com/events/national-rally-in-support-of-ukraine/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 May 2014 01:18:23 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ozeukes.com/events/national-rally-in-support-of-ukraine/</guid>
      <description>The Australian Federation of Ukrainian Organisations (AFUO) calls on all concerned Australians to participate in a National Rally in Support of Ukraine.
The rally will express its strong opposition to Putin’s aggression in Ukraine.
The final stage of the rally will be culminate at the Embassy of the Russian Federation in Australia in Canberra on Sunday May 25, 2014 at 1.00pm, the day of the Presidential elections in Ukraine.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ukraine Under Attack – Issue 16</title>
      <link>https://ozeukes.com/politics/ukraine-under-attack-issue-16/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 May 2014 05:32:26 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ozeukes.com/politics/ukraine-under-attack-issue-16/</guid>
      <description>Issue #16 of the bulletin “Ukraine Under Attack”, produced by the Ukrainian Ministry of Foreign Affairs, is now available. This issue provides summaries of events in Ukraine last week (5th-10th May 2014), including the tragic events in Odessa.
Ukraine Under Attack #16</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Joint Statement of Peak Councils of NSW on the escalating violence in Ukraine</title>
      <link>https://ozeukes.com/politics/joint-statement-of-peak-councils-of-nsw-on-the-escalating-violence-in-ukraine/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 10 May 2014 05:16:46 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ozeukes.com/politics/joint-statement-of-peak-councils-of-nsw-on-the-escalating-violence-in-ukraine/</guid>
      <description>Following a meeting of representatives of Peak Councils of a number of New South Wales Eastern and Central European communities on 5 May 2014, at which serious concerns were raised and affirmed on the alarming situation in Ukraine, a statement was released.
Text of statement: Joint Statement of Peak Councils 5 May 2014 - FINAL</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ukraine Under Attack – Issue 15</title>
      <link>https://ozeukes.com/politics/ukraine-under-attack-issue-15/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 May 2014 05:43:25 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ozeukes.com/politics/ukraine-under-attack-issue-15/</guid>
      <description>Issue #15 of the bulletin “Ukraine Under Attack”, produced by the Ukrainian Ministry of Foreign Affairs, is now available. This issue mentions increasing sanctions imposed by both western and eastern powers against Putin’s inner circle, and identifies some of the main conspirators in Russia’s ongoing expansionist campaign.
Ukraine Under Attack #15</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ukraine Under Attack – Issue 14</title>
      <link>https://ozeukes.com/politics/ukraine-under-attack-issue-14/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Apr 2014 01:27:46 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ozeukes.com/politics/ukraine-under-attack-issue-14/</guid>
      <description>Issue #14 of the bulletin “Ukraine Under Attack”, produced by the Ukrainian Ministry of Foreign Affairs, is now available. This issue summarises the most recent happenings regarding the pro-Russian separatist movements in eastern Ukraine and Russia’s continuing failure to abide by the recent Geneva Agreement.
Ukraine Under Attack #14</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ukraine Under Attack – Issue 13</title>
      <link>https://ozeukes.com/politics/ukraine-under-attack-issue-13/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 25 Apr 2014 10:41:58 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ozeukes.com/politics/ukraine-under-attack-issue-13/</guid>
      <description>Issue #13 of the bulletin “Ukraine Under Attack”, produced by the Ukrainian Ministry of Foreign Affairs, is now available. This issue provides updates on the lack of progress of the 4-party Geneva Agreement signed in mid April, provides a little insight into some of the personalities assuming puppet powers in Crimea, and has a facsimile of the anti-Jewish letter being circulated by the pro-Russian separatists in eastern Ukraine.
Ukraine Under Attack #13</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ukraine Under Attack – Issues 11 and 12</title>
      <link>https://ozeukes.com/politics/ukraine-under-attack-issues-11-and-12/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Apr 2014 01:47:45 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ozeukes.com/politics/ukraine-under-attack-issues-11-and-12/</guid>
      <description>Issues #11 and #12 of the bulletin “Ukraine Under Attack”, produced by the Ukrainian Ministry of Foreign Affairs, are now available. These issues provide updates on the ongoing aggressive nature of the Russian government towards Ukraine and more international reaction to the continuing destabilisation attempts in Ukraine.
crimea_bulletin_11
Ukraine Under Attack #12</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Crimea Bulletin 10</title>
      <link>https://ozeukes.com/politics/crimea-bulletin-10/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 Apr 2014 02:45:33 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ozeukes.com/politics/crimea-bulletin-10/</guid>
      <description>Issue #10 of the Crimea bulletin “Ukraine Under Attack”, produced by the Ukrainian Ministry of Foreign Affairs, has now been released by the Ukrainian Embassy in Canberra. This issue reviews further international reaction to the ongoing destabilisation attempts in Ukraine.
crimea bulletin #10</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>AFUO Media Release: Putin grabs more of Ukraine / Australia needs to do more</title>
      <link>https://ozeukes.com/events/international-events/afuo-media-release-putin-grabs-more-of-ukraine-australia-needs-to-do-more/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 Apr 2014 02:41:41 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ozeukes.com/events/international-events/afuo-media-release-putin-grabs-more-of-ukraine-australia-needs-to-do-more/</guid>
      <description>The Australian Federation of Ukrainian Organisations (AFUO) has issued a media release regarding the latest attempts by the Putin regime to make further aggressive incursions into Ukraine. The statement also calls upon the Australian government to make more concerted actions to condemn these internationally illegal activities by the Russian government.  Media statement: AFUO Media Release on Donetsk intervention
In addition, the AFUO has written directly to the Minister for Foreign Affairs, the Hon.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Crimea Bulletin 9</title>
      <link>https://ozeukes.com/politics/crimea-bulletin-9/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 Apr 2014 02:21:04 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ozeukes.com/politics/crimea-bulletin-9/</guid>
      <description>Issue #9 of the Crimea bulletin “Ukraine Under Attack”, produced by the Ukrainian Ministry of Foreign Affairs, is now available. This issue summarises some of the international reactions to the illegal actions of the Russian government, and further destabilisation attempts in eastern Ukraine.
crimea bulletin 9</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>UWC Press Release / Пресове Повідомлення СКУ - 10-04-2014</title>
      <link>https://ozeukes.com/politics/uwc-press-release-10-04-2014/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 11 Apr 2014 01:33:53 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ozeukes.com/politics/uwc-press-release-10-04-2014/</guid>
      <description>The Ukrainian World Congress (UWC) calls for substantial UN peacekeeping and OSCE observer missions as tensions escalate in Ukraine.
UWC Press Release 10 April 2014
Світовий Конґрес Українців (СКУ) закликає до численних місій миротворців ООН та спостерігачів ОБСЄ у зв’язку зі зростанням напруженості в Україні.
СКУ Пресове Повідомлення 10 квітня 2014 р Media Contact: Irene Mycak UKRAINIAN WORLD CONGRESS 145 Evans Ave., Suite 207 Toronto, ON M8Z 5X8 Canada Tel. (416) 323-3020 Fax (416) 323-3250 e-mail: congress@look.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Statement of the MFA of Ukraine/Заява МЗС України_08.04.2014</title>
      <link>https://ozeukes.com/politics/statement-of-the-mfa-of-ukraine_08-04-2014/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 11 Apr 2014 00:46:32 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ozeukes.com/politics/statement-of-the-mfa-of-ukraine_08-04-2014/</guid>
      <description>[ ](http://www.ozeukes.com/wp-content/uploads/2014/04/MFA_Ukraine-thumb.jpg)Statement of the MFA of Ukraine on intervention by Russia in the internal affairs of Ukraine
The Ministry of Foreign Affairs (MFA) of Ukraine has issued a statement regarding the current situation in parts of eastern and southern Ukraine. Statement of the MFA of Ukraine_08 04 2014
Заява МЗС України щодо втручання РФ у внутрішні справи України Міністерство Закордонних Справ України (МЗС) видало заяву відносно поточного стану в частинах східної і південної України.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Crimea Bulletin 8</title>
      <link>https://ozeukes.com/politics/crimea-bulletin-8/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 03 Apr 2014 00:44:41 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ozeukes.com/politics/crimea-bulletin-8/</guid>
      <description>Issue #8 of the Crimea bulletin “Ukraine Under Attack”, produced by the Ukrainian Ministry of Foreign Affairs, is now available. This issue summarises events of 31 March to 1 April 2014, and covers some of the humanitarian and economic consequences of the illegal invasion and occupation of Crimea.
crimea bulletin 8</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SBS Radio Ukrainian – Дві Радіопередачі</title>
      <link>https://ozeukes.com/culture/sbs-radio-ukrainian-two-broadcasts/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 03 Apr 2014 00:32:27 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ozeukes.com/culture/sbs-radio-ukrainian-two-broadcasts/</guid>
      <description>[ ](http://www.ozeukes.com/wp-content/uploads/2014/04/150px-SBS-Ukrainian.jpg)SBS Radio Ukrainian – Дві Радіопередачі
SBS Radio Ukrainian в останному часі передала дві радіопередачі, одну із Сіднею про доповідь професора Нормана Дейвіса, а другу із Мельбурну про відзначення 200-ліття з дня народження Тараса Шевченка.
ПРОФЕСОР НОРМАН ДЕЙВІС: УКРАЇНА ПОМІЖ ЄВРОСОЮЗОМ І РОСІЄЮ Ірина Білик із Сіднею розповідає про доповідь професора Нормана Дейвіса на тему «УКРАЇНА ПОМІЖ ЄВРОСОЮЗОМ І РОСІЄЮ».
Professor Norman Davies was educated at Bolton School, Magdalen College, Oxford, the University of Sussex and at several continental universities including Grenoble, Perugia and Kraków.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Crimea Bulletin 7</title>
      <link>https://ozeukes.com/politics/crimea-bulletin-7/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Apr 2014 00:26:53 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ozeukes.com/politics/crimea-bulletin-7/</guid>
      <description>Issue #7 of the Crimea bulletin “Ukraine Under Attack”, produced by the Ukrainian Ministry of Foreign Affairs, has been released by the Ukrainian Embassy in Canberra. This issue summarises events of 26-27 March 2014, including the overwhelming vote by the United Nations General Assembly endorsing Ukraine’s territorial integrity, and further support for Ukraine from other governments and organisations.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Crimea Bulletin 6</title>
      <link>https://ozeukes.com/politics/crimea-bulletin-6/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Mar 2014 03:23:31 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ozeukes.com/politics/crimea-bulletin-6/</guid>
      <description>Issue #6 of the Crimea bulletin “Ukraine Under Attack” has been released by the Ukrainian Embassy in Canberra. This issue summarises events of 24-25 March 2014 and includes excerpts from the “Hague Declaration” issued by the G-7 group of nations, the European Council and European Commission.
crimea bulletin 6</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>КРИМ ТА УКРАЇНЦІ АВСТРАЛІЇ</title>
      <link>https://ozeukes.com/current-affairs/crimea-and-ukrainians-in-australia/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Mar 2014 10:28:31 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ozeukes.com/current-affairs/crimea-and-ukrainians-in-australia/</guid>
      <description>Богдан Рудницький веде розмову із головою Управи Союзу Українських Організацій Австралії Стефаном Романівим
Bogdan Rudnytski leads a discussion with Stefan Romaniw, the chairman of the Australian Federation of Ukrainians (AFUO), about the Crimean crisis and what the Ukrainian community in Australia can do to help.
 http://www.sbs.com.au/yourlanguage/ukrainian/highlight/page/id/325545/t/CRIMEA-AND-UKRAINIANS-IN-AUSTRALIA/</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Crimea Bulletin 5</title>
      <link>https://ozeukes.com/politics/crimea-bulletin-5/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Mar 2014 06:34:34 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ozeukes.com/politics/crimea-bulletin-5/</guid>
      <description>Issue #5 of the Crimea bulletin “Ukraine Under Attack” has been released by the Ukrainian Embassy in Canberra. This issue summarises events of 20-21 March 2014 and includes steps that the Ukrainian Government is undertaking to respond to Russian aggression.
crimea bulletin 5</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Crimea Bulletin 4</title>
      <link>https://ozeukes.com/politics/crimea-bulletin-4/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Mar 2014 01:03:59 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ozeukes.com/politics/crimea-bulletin-4/</guid>
      <description>The Ukrainian Embassy in Canberra has released issue #4 of the Crimea bulletin “Ukraine Under Attack”. This issue summarises events of 18-19 March 2014 and includes other short related articles.
crimea bulletin 4</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Conclusions on Recent Events in Ukraine</title>
      <link>https://ozeukes.com/politics/conclusions-on-recent-events-in-ukraine/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Mar 2014 06:13:21 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ozeukes.com/politics/conclusions-on-recent-events-in-ukraine/</guid>
      <description>The Ukrainian Embassy in Canberra has released two recent documents concerning the crisis in Europe, with specific determinations regarding the illegal and invalid nature of the so-called “referendum” in Crimea and its outcomes.
The first document is the “Conclusion of the Council of the European Union” dated 17th March 2014: Council conclusions on Ukraine
The second document is a translation of “Judgement of the Constitutional Court of Ukraine”, dated 14th March 2014: JUDGMENT OF THE CONSTITUTIONAL COURT OF UKRAINE</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>US State Department Fact Sheet</title>
      <link>https://ozeukes.com/politics/us-state-department-fact-sheet/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Mar 2014 03:05:58 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ozeukes.com/politics/us-state-department-fact-sheet/</guid>
      <description>The US Department of State has produced the first iteration of a new “Public Diplomacy Tool Kit on Ukraine” that it will be deploying to its Department messengers to assist them in promoting accurate narratives about the crisis in the Ukraine. The document contains excellent information regarding the true facts about events in Ukraine, as well as containing links to other valuable supporting sites.
A PDF copy of the Tool Kit can be viewed here: US Toolkit on Ukraine Narratives 2014-03-14</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SBS Radio: Інтерв&#39;ю із п. Петром Шміґелем / Interview with Peter Shmigel</title>
      <link>https://ozeukes.com/politics/sbs-radio-interview-with-peter-shmigel/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Mar 2014 02:56:36 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ozeukes.com/politics/sbs-radio-interview-with-peter-shmigel/</guid>
      <description>[ ](http://www.ozeukes.com/wp-content/uploads/2014/03/150px-SBS-Ukrainian.jpg)AUSTRALIA AND UKRAINE: RUSSIAN AGGRESSION
Bogdan Rudnytski interviewed Pete Shmigel, who is the Public Affairs Director for the Australian Federation of Ukrainian Organisations (AFUO). Australians of Ukrainian and other backgrounds condemn military intervention by Vladimir Putin in independent Ukraine and call on the Australian Prime Minister to join the international community in opposing Putin’s illegal and unprovoked aggression…
АВСТРАЛІЯ І УКРАЇНA: РОСІЙСЬКА АҐРЕСІЯ Богдан Рудныцкий веде радіорозмову із п. Петром Шміґелем, який є референтом зовнішних зв’язків Союзу Українських Організацій Австралії (СУОА).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Crimean Bulletins 2 and 3</title>
      <link>https://ozeukes.com/politics/crimean-bulletins-2-and-3/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Mar 2014 08:47:43 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ozeukes.com/politics/crimean-bulletins-2-and-3/</guid>
      <description>The Ukrainian Government, through its embassies, has issued the next two releases of its newsletter “Ukraine under Attack”
Issue 2: 2014.03.14_Ukraine_under_attack_No._2
Issue 3: crimea bulletin 3</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Порівняльна характеристика забезпечення прав меншостей / Comparative Data on Ethnic Minority Rights</title>
      <link>https://ozeukes.com/politics/comparative-data-on-ethnic-minority-rights/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Mar 2014 08:42:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ozeukes.com/politics/comparative-data-on-ethnic-minority-rights/</guid>
      <description>**Порівняльна характеристика забезпечення прав **меншостей
Міністерство закордонних справ України подало інформаційну довідку «Порівняльна характеристика забезпечення прав українців у Росії та росіян в Україні» : Порівняльна характеристика-скорочена (2)
Comparative** ****Data**** ****on**** ****Ethnic**** ****Minority**** ****Rights******
The Ministry of Foreign Affairs (Ukraine) has released a brief information sheet entitled “Comparative Data on Protection of Russian Ethnic Minority’s Rights in Ukraine and Ukrainian Ethnic Minority’s Rights in Russia”: Comparison of the rights of Ukrainians in Russia and Russians in Ukraine</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ukrainian Government Newsletter</title>
      <link>https://ozeukes.com/current-affairs/ukrainian-government-newsletter/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Mar 2014 09:39:46 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ozeukes.com/current-affairs/ukrainian-government-newsletter/</guid>
      <description>The Ukrainian Government, through its embassies, has issued a four-page newsletter summarising events in Ukraine, in particular in Crimea, over the last fortnight. In addition, the newsletter provides links to other sites which provide further information. Newsletter (in English): Ukraine Under Attack</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rally in Canberra – Feb 2014</title>
      <link>https://ozeukes.com/community/rally-in-canberra-feb-2014/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Mar 2014 07:00:06 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ozeukes.com/community/rally-in-canberra-feb-2014/</guid>
      <description>The Ukrainian community of Canberra held a rally on 18th February, 2014 as part of the world-wide campaign by the Ukrainian diaspora supporting the EuroMaidan movement in the Ukrainian capital Kyiv. EuroMaidan started as a protest movement against the last-minute decision by the Yanukovych regime to abandon the signing of the Association Agreement with the European Union, then progressed to a vehement disapproval of the signing of a series of laws severely curtailing civil liberties and political rights in Ukraine.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Perth Western Australia Rally - &#34;Putin ! Hands Off Ukraine !&#34;</title>
      <link>https://ozeukes.com/events/western-australia/perth-western-australia-rally-putin-hands-off-ukraine/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Mar 2014 00:40:48 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ozeukes.com/events/western-australia/perth-western-australia-rally-putin-hands-off-ukraine/</guid>
      <description>Western Australians of all backgrounds will send a loud and strong message to Putin that his military invasion of Ukraine is unacceptable and illegal, and that the world will act against him in defense of Ukraine&#39;s democracy and independence. It&#39;s up to us to make the difference. Join with us:
When: Sunday, March 9 from 1:30pm Where: Wesley Church (cnr of Hay and William Sts) Perth
Wear Ukrainian shirts, blouses, your favourite Ukrainian T-shirt.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Refuting Putin’s lies</title>
      <link>https://ozeukes.com/politics/refuting-putins-lies/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Mar 2014 02:46:35 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ozeukes.com/politics/refuting-putins-lies/</guid>
      <description>A growing number of fact sheets, letters, briefing documents etc. are available from reliable sources refuting Putin’s false “reasons” for the illegal invasion of Ukraine’s sovereign territory. A small sample is provided here:
From the US Department of State comes a Fact Sheet titled “President Putin&#39;s Fiction: 10 False Claims about Ukraine”: US Department of State - President Putin&#39;s Fiction** ** (source http://www.state.gov/r/pa/prs/ps/2014/03/222988.htm )
Also a more detailed document provided for US Embassy staff in Moscow titled “Setting the Record Straight on Ukraine (March 4, 2014)”: US Embassy in Moscow****</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Press Release: Visa extensions for Ukrainian citizens in Australia</title>
      <link>https://ozeukes.com/current-affairs/press-release-visa-extensions-for-ukrainian-citizens-in-australia/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Mar 2014 09:50:22 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ozeukes.com/current-affairs/press-release-visa-extensions-for-ukrainian-citizens-in-australia/</guid>
      <description>JOINT MEDIA RELEASE - MINISTER BISHOP &amp;amp; MINISTER MORRISON
Ukrainian nationals who are currently in Australia on a visa due to expire and who may be affected by the unrest in the Ukraine will be able to approach the Department of Immigration and Border Protection to make an application for an extension of their visa for a temporary period.
Full media release: Joint Media Release - Bishop Morrison - Ukraine Visa</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Press release from Ukrainian Embassy</title>
      <link>https://ozeukes.com/current-affairs/press-release-from-ukrainian-embassy/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Mar 2014 05:59:42 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ozeukes.com/current-affairs/press-release-from-ukrainian-embassy/</guid>
      <description>The Ukrainian Embassy in Canberra is providing a number of press releases and status updates regarding the current crisis in Ukraine brought about by the illegal armed invasion by Russia and its continuing occupation of Crimea. The statements are provided in both Ukrainian and English.
 0403_Crimean_issue_1000 (3 - Ukrainian)
0403_Crimean_issue_1900 (4 - Ukrainian)
0403_Crimean_issue_1900
Information about situation in Crimea (04032014)</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Photos - Ukraine Crisis Rally (3)</title>
      <link>https://ozeukes.com/gallery/photos-ukraine-crisis-rally-3/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Mar 2014 05:33:09 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ozeukes.com/gallery/photos-ukraine-crisis-rally-3/</guid>
      <description>Photos from the march and rally held in Melbourne on 4th March 2014 supporting Ukraine against Putin’s illegal invasion of Ukraine._ _
Photos courtesy of Bogdan Rudnytski</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Photos - Ukraine Crisis Rally (2)</title>
      <link>https://ozeukes.com/gallery/photos-ukraine-crisis-rally-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Mar 2014 05:18:45 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ozeukes.com/gallery/photos-ukraine-crisis-rally-2/</guid>
      <description>Photos from the march and rally held in Melbourne on 4th March 2014 supporting Ukraine against Putin’s illegal invasion of Ukraine._ _
Photos courtesy of Bogdan Rudnytski
__</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Photos - Ukraine Crisis Rally (1)</title>
      <link>https://ozeukes.com/gallery/photos-ukraine-crisis-rally-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Mar 2014 05:01:36 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ozeukes.com/gallery/photos-ukraine-crisis-rally-1/</guid>
      <description>Photos from the march and rally held in Melbourne on 4th March 2014 supporting Ukraine against Putin’s illegal invasion of Ukraine.
Photos courtesy of Bogdan Rudnytski</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Media coverage of rally in Melbourne over Ukraine crisis</title>
      <link>https://ozeukes.com/media/media-coverage-of-rally-in-melbourne-over-ukraine-crisis/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Mar 2014 02:26:02 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ozeukes.com/media/media-coverage-of-rally-in-melbourne-over-ukraine-crisis/</guid>
      <description>The Ukrainian community of Melbourne along with several other communities offering their support staged a rally in the CBD on 4th March 2014 protesting against the illegal invasion of Ukraine by Russian forces. Over 500 demonstrators took part in a march and assembly. The event was covered by TV news channels, radio stations, print and internet media. Links to a small sample of these are provided here:
Herald Sun: http://www.heraldsun.com.au/news/victoria/hundreds-of-protesters-rally-in-melbourne-over-ukraine-crisis/story-fni0fit3-1226845259926</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Media article: &#34;The Justifying Myths of Russian Intervention&#34;</title>
      <link>https://ozeukes.com/politics/media-article-the-justifying-myths-of-russian-intervention/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Mar 2014 01:06:07 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ozeukes.com/politics/media-article-the-justifying-myths-of-russian-intervention/</guid>
      <description>Peter Shmigel, Public Affairs Director for the Australian Federation of Ukrainian Organisations (AFUO), has written an article exposing some of the malicious lies, fabrications and disinformation put about by Putin and his gang in a xenophobic attempt to “justify” his illegal invasion of Ukraine. The published article can be read at: http://www.onlineopinion.com.au/view.asp?article=16077
Pete Shmigel has worked at the highest levels of Australian politics, business and the consulting sector.
As an AFUO Board Director, he coordinates the Ukrainian Australian community’s public affairs and advocacy agenda.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Запис із спільної «Молитви за мир і спокій»</title>
      <link>https://ozeukes.com/community/recording-of-prayer-for-peace/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Mar 2014 09:25:30 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ozeukes.com/community/recording-of-prayer-for-peace/</guid>
      <description>Запис із спільної Молитви за мир і спокій в Україні, яка відбулася у Катедрі Св. Патрика у Мельбурні 26 лютого 2014 р&amp;hellip;.
http://www.sbs.com.au/yourlanguage/ukrainian/highlight/page/id/321166/t/MELBOURNE:-PRAYER-FOR-PEACE-IN-UKRAINE/</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Melbourne Protest Against Putin</title>
      <link>https://ozeukes.com/events/victoria/melbourne-protest-against-putin/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Mar 2014 02:08:21 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ozeukes.com/events/victoria/melbourne-protest-against-putin/</guid>
      <description>All Australians concerned about Vladimir Putin&#39;s neo-imperial military intervention in Ukraine should show their concern and let their voices be heard.

Melbourne Ukrainians are again taking to the streets in protest.
WHEN: Tuesday 4 March at 6pm
WHERE: Meet – Alexandra Gardens, St Kilda Road, Melbourne - opposite the Arts Centre – (see map below)
MARCH: Down Swanston Street to the City Square where a rally will take place</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PROTEST IN SYDNEY - &#34;PUTIN - HANDS OFF UKRAINE&#34;</title>
      <link>https://ozeukes.com/events/new-south-wales/protest-in-sydney-putin-hands-off-ukraine/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Mar 2014 01:46:17 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ozeukes.com/events/new-south-wales/protest-in-sydney-putin-hands-off-ukraine/</guid>
      <description>&amp;ldquo;PUTIN - HANDS OFF UKRAINE&amp;rdquo; 
PROTEST IN SYDNEY Monday 3rd March 2014 at 6:15 pm Russian Consulate Sydney, 5-7 Fullerton Street, Woollahra All Australians concerned about Vladimir Putin&#39;s neo-imperial military intervention in Ukraine should show their concern and let their voices be heard.
Media will be alerted.
Bring Australian flags in particular, Ukrainian flags, and signs/banners condemning Putin&#39;s actions and calling for international solution&amp;hellip;.
Remember: we protest against Putin. Russians in Ukraine have supported the Maidan Movement and Russians in Russia want the democratic reform that they have witnessed in Kyiv.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Громадська зустріч з Д-р Володимиром Зарицьким</title>
      <link>https://ozeukes.com/events/victoria/meeting-with-dr-walter-zaryckyj/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Mar 2014 01:54:45 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ozeukes.com/events/victoria/meeting-with-dr-walter-zaryckyj/</guid>
      <description>Українська Громада Вікторії (УГВ) запрошує на громадську зустріч з Д-р Володимиром Зарицьким з Ню Йорку, Екзекутивний Директор Центру Відносин США- УКРАЇНА.

The Association of Ukrainians in Victoria (AUV) invites all for a meeting with Dr. Walter Zaryckyj from New York, Executive director of the Center for US-Ukrainian Relations (CUSUR).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Знимки - Моління за мир в Україні / Photos - Prayer for Peace in Ukraine</title>
      <link>https://ozeukes.com/community/photos-prayer-for-peace-in-ukraine/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Feb 2014 09:23:14 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ozeukes.com/community/photos-prayer-for-peace-in-ukraine/</guid>
      <description>Більше знимок із «Моління за мир в Україні» 26 лютого 2014 р. в Катедрі Св. Патрика.
More photos from the “Prayer for Peace in Ukraine**” **held on the 26th February 2014 at St Patrick’s Cathedral.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Моління за мир в Україні / Prayer for Peace in Ukraine</title>
      <link>https://ozeukes.com/events/victoria/prayer-for-peace-in-ukraine-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Feb 2014 00:06:46 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ozeukes.com/events/victoria/prayer-for-peace-in-ukraine-2/</guid>
      <description>26 лютого 2014 р. в Катедра Св. Патрика зібралося понад 400 людей різних віровизнань та різних народів разом з українською спільнотою помолитися за відновлення миру та справедливості в Україні.
On the 26th February 2014 over 400 people of various religious faiths and multicultural backgrounds joined with the Ukrainian community at St Patrick’s Cathedral in praying for the restoration of peace and justice in Ukraine.

Video:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Моління за мир в Україні / Prayer for Peace in Ukraine</title>
      <link>https://ozeukes.com/events/victoria/prayer-for-peace-in-ukraine/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 23 Feb 2014 08:48:42 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ozeukes.com/events/victoria/prayer-for-peace-in-ukraine/</guid>
      <description>[ ](http://www.ozeukes.com/wp-content/uploads/2014/02/Maidan1.jpg)
Всеавстралійське моління за мир в Україні Середа 26 лютого 2014 р., 7-8 год. вечора. Катедра Св. Патрика, 1 Cathedral Place, East Melbourne. Українська Греко-Католицька Церква та Українська Православна Церква в Австралії, з підтримкою Ради Церков Вікторії та під егідою СУОА, запрошують людей усіх віровизнань, членів усіх громад, разом з українською спільнотою молитися за відновлення миру та справедливості в Україні.
Порядок включає тиху одночасну молитву всіх, відповідно до власної духовної традиції.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ЗАМОРОЖІТЬ ГРОШІ БАНДИ Й ОЛІГАРХІВ</title>
      <link>https://ozeukes.com/events/new-south-wales/freeze-the-assets-of-the-gang/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 23 Feb 2014 02:01:54 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ozeukes.com/events/new-south-wales/freeze-the-assets-of-the-gang/</guid>
      <description>МАРІЧКА ГАЛАБУРДА - ЧИГРИН
Сідней 22.2.2014
ЗАМОРОЖІТЬ ГРОШІ БАНДИ Й ОЛІГАРХІВ
Відбули ми сьогодні в суботу 22.2.2014 в Сіднеї усішну демонстрацію перeд готелем, де відбувалася конференція міністрів фінансів країн членів G 20.

Поліція дала дозвіл на проведення демонстрації й висловилася прихильні і до нас і з нами жахалися від подій в Україні - зокрема мертви, яких вбили Януковича бандити, за його наказом чи то його вислужника Захарченка.
Демонстрація була організована за ініціятивою Управи СУОА, ОУГ і Сіднейського Евро-Майданівського комітету.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Збірка на Майдан</title>
      <link>https://ozeukes.com/community/maidan-donations/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Feb 2014 00:11:12 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ozeukes.com/community/maidan-donations/</guid>
      <description>**[ ](http://www.ozeukes.com/wp-content/uploads/2014/02/Kyiv-Maidan1.jpg)Збірка на Майдан**
На Майдані потрібно тепер допомогу. В грудні 2013р. управа CУОA проголосила збірку на Потреби Майдану.
Всі пожертви пересилати на:
Dnister Account AFUO
 **Закликаємо Вас не пересилати гроші на приватні адреси в Україні **
** **
Maidan Fund The Maidan needs your help.
In December 2013 the AFUO committee announced a collection for the Needs of the Maidan.
Please send your donations to:
Dnister Account AFUO</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Pako Festa Ukrainian Parade</title>
      <link>https://ozeukes.com/events/victoria/pako-festa-ukrainian-parade/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Feb 2014 23:37:24 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ozeukes.com/events/victoria/pako-festa-ukrainian-parade/</guid>
      <description>&amp;ldquo;Prayer for Peace&amp;rdquo; and Rally at the Hall at 1pm.

Geelong and Melbourne Ukrainians are proud to use the EuroMaidan in Ukraine as their inspiration for the “Weaving Cultures” metaphor at Pako Festa.
Deepak Chopra has said, “Once the fabric of a just society is undone, it takes generations to weave it back together.” And the situation in Ukraine today can be seen as an example of the power of the people attempting to darn the holes in the fabric of its society by fighting for unity, freedom, equality and a fair and just system.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Appeal from Myroslav Marynovych</title>
      <link>https://ozeukes.com/politics/appeal-from-myroslav-marynovych/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Feb 2014 02:24:38 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ozeukes.com/politics/appeal-from-myroslav-marynovych/</guid>
      <description>Myroslav Marynovych is the vice-rector of the Ukrainian Catholic University in Lviv, founder of Amnesty International Ukraine, and a founding member of the Ukrainian Helsinki Group.
In 1978, Manynovych was sentenced to 7 years of hard labour and 5 years in exile for Anti Soviet Agitation and Propaganda because of his membership of the Ukrainian Helsinki Group. He returned to Ukraine in 1987.
He has worked as a writer and journalist and, in addition to his duties as vice-rector of the Ukrainian Catholic University, he is a lecturer, a leading intellectual and prominent social activist.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>AFUO Update: Condemnation of violence in Ukraine</title>
      <link>https://ozeukes.com/community/afuo-update-condemnation-of-violence-in-ukraine/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Feb 2014 06:39:23 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ozeukes.com/community/afuo-update-condemnation-of-violence-in-ukraine/</guid>
      <description>The Australian Federation of Ukrainian Organisations (AFUO) has issued an update regarding the most recent events in Ukraine. Included in the update:
 * A sincere expression of condolences to the families of all those who have died so tragically in the last 24 hours * A brief summary of AFUO activity related to events in Ukraine * An outline of funds delivered to Ukraine for EuroMaidan related activities.  Text of update: AFUO UPDATE 19 2</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Labor Opposition statement about events in Ukraine</title>
      <link>https://ozeukes.com/politics/labor-opposition-statement-about-events-in-ukraine/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Feb 2014 06:19:37 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ozeukes.com/politics/labor-opposition-statement-about-events-in-ukraine/</guid>
      <description>The Hon Tanya Plibersek MP, Deputy Leader of the Opposition and Shadow Minister for Foreign Affairs and International Development, has issued a statement on behalf of the Federal Labor Opposition expressing concerns about the most recent events in Kyiv, Ukraine.
 The Hon Tanya Plibersek MP
  Deputy Leader of the Opposition
  Shadow Minister for Foreign Affairs and International Development
  Events in the Ukraine
 The Labor Opposition expresses deep concern about the violence in Ukraine’s capital, Kiev.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>URGENT UKRAINE UPDATE No2</title>
      <link>https://ozeukes.com/politics/urgent-ukraine-update-no2/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Feb 2014 02:57:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ozeukes.com/politics/urgent-ukraine-update-no2/</guid>
      <description>February 19, 2014
Ukraine, 01:00 (Gmt +2) 
At least 14 people reported dead (plus 7unconfirmed) at this moment.
 3 dead bodies at the Officers house at Hrushevskogo street (photo proofed)  2 older people (man and woman) found dead at the barricadres at the Institutska streeet (near the entrance to the Khreschatyk metro station) (photo proofed)  1 man died near the National Bank building (photo proofed)  1 protestor was founded with had cut near the Parliament building (BBC journalists report)  5 people killed during the Maidan crackdown (The Mirrow of Week journalist report)  2 dead people just brought to the Kyiv city hospital #17 (information from MP Iryna Geraschenko)  7 people brought to the Kyiv city morgue (to be confirmed) At least 3 people died of bullet wounds.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What Future for Ukraine?</title>
      <link>https://ozeukes.com/events/victoria/what-future-for-ukraine/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 08 Feb 2014 00:54:53 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ozeukes.com/events/victoria/what-future-for-ukraine/</guid>
      <description>A public roundtable discussion will take place at Monash University on 19th February 2014. The discussion will address the origins and main features of the Ukrainian crisis of 2013-14, and contemplate possible developments of politics and political culture in Ukraine, as well as the country’s geopolitical orientation.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Melbourne March &amp; Rally – More Photographs (2)</title>
      <link>https://ozeukes.com/gallery/melbourne-march-rally-more-photographs-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Feb 2014 23:27:22 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ozeukes.com/gallery/melbourne-march-rally-more-photographs-2/</guid>
      <description>More photographs from the march &amp;amp; rally held on Tuesday 4th February 2014 in Melbourne. The rally was the continuation of a series of rallies in support of EuroMaidan and Democracy in Ukraine.
Photos courtesy of Hubert Weisrock.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Melbourne March &amp; Rally – More Photographs (1)</title>
      <link>https://ozeukes.com/gallery/melbourne-march-rally-more-photographs-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Feb 2014 23:04:05 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ozeukes.com/gallery/melbourne-march-rally-more-photographs-1/</guid>
      <description>More photographs from the march &amp;amp; rally held on Tuesday 4th February 2014 in Melbourne. The rally was the continuation of a series of rallies in support of EuroMaidan and Democracy in Ukraine.
Photos courtesy of Hubert Weisrock.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Melbourne March &amp; Rally</title>
      <link>https://ozeukes.com/events/victoria/melbourne-march-rally/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Feb 2014 02:31:15 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ozeukes.com/events/victoria/melbourne-march-rally/</guid>
      <description>Melbourne March &amp;amp; Rally - Democracy for Ukraine. 
Approximately 400 members of the Ukrainian community turned out in Melbourne on Tuesday 4th February 2014. They were joined by the Hon. Matthew Guy, priests from the Ukrainian Catholic Church as well as many other nationalities - Polish, Slovaks, Italians and Georgians.

The rally commenced with a march from Treasury Gardens (near Parliament) to the City Square (opposite Melbourne Town Hall).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ВІЧЕ в Сіднею на Підтримку Майдану в Україні!</title>
      <link>https://ozeukes.com/events/new-south-wales/community-rally-in-sydney-to-support-maidan/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Feb 2014 00:11:56 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ozeukes.com/events/new-south-wales/community-rally-in-sydney-to-support-maidan/</guid>
      <description>ВІЧЕ в Сіднею на Підтримку Майдану в Україні! Сіднейський Комітет для підтримки Майдану (під патронатом Об’єднання Українських Громад НПВ – ОУГ НПВ та у співучасті з Союзом Українських Організацій Австралії - СУОА) провели Громадське Віче останньої неділі, 2 лютого 2014 в Домі Української Молоді Лідкомбі.

На підтримку антиурядових демонстрацій в Україні, в цьому Віче взяло участь понад 150 австралійських громадян українського походження, чия мета була в тому, щоб висловити свою стурбованість нашим австралійським парламентарям в надії, що ми могли б зробити більше для підтримки тих, хто на Майдані.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>EuroMaidan – A Video Overview</title>
      <link>https://ozeukes.com/events/international-events/euromaidan-a-video-overview/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Feb 2014 05:57:12 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ozeukes.com/events/international-events/euromaidan-a-video-overview/</guid>
      <description>[ ](http://www.ozeukes.com/wp-content/uploads/2014/02/Kyiv-Maidan.jpg)**EuroMaidan - An Overview of the Crisis in Ukraine **
First aired at the EuroMaidan Rally in Sydney on 2nd February 2014 Compiled by: Andrew Duma
ЄвроМайдан - короткий перегляд кризи на Україні Вперше висвітлене в Сіднеї на мітинґу 2 лютого 2014 року на підтримку ЄвроМайдану Упорядник: Aндрій Дума
 </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Високодостойний Дейвід Джон КЛАРК про Україну</title>
      <link>https://ozeukes.com/community/the-hon-david-john-clarke-about-ukraine/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Feb 2014 05:20:17 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ozeukes.com/community/the-hon-david-john-clarke-about-ukraine/</guid>
      <description>Високодостойний Дейвід Джон КЛАРК про Україну та українців у скрутний час боротьби за демократію
Із виступу Високодостойногопарламентського секретаря з правових питань, члена Законодавчої Ради Дейвіда Джона Кларка з Ліберальної партії на мітинґу українців Нової Південної Валії у Сіднеї 2 лютого 2014 року на підтримку протестуючої України за Волю і Демократію в Українській державі&amp;hellip;****
The Hon David John Clarke about Ukraine and Ukrainians at this difficult time in the Fight for Democracy</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Melbourne Maidan March &amp; Rally</title>
      <link>https://ozeukes.com/events/victoria/melbourne-maidan-march-rally/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Feb 2014 02:06:21 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ozeukes.com/events/victoria/melbourne-maidan-march-rally/</guid>
      <description>**MELBOURNE Maidan &amp;amp; Rally******
Association of Ukrainians in Victoria
Support democracy and human rights for Ukraine on Tuesday 4th February 2014. 
Melbourne Ukrainians are taking to the streets in protest against the Yanukovych regime and demanding support form the Australian Government
To show solidarity and support for Ukrainians in Kyiv and across Ukraine, the meeting will gather at the Treasury Gardens to march down to Collins Street to the City Square to pray for peace and end to violence.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Демонстрація в Канберрі</title>
      <link>https://ozeukes.com/events/act/rally-in-canberra-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 Jan 2014 22:53:59 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ozeukes.com/events/act/rally-in-canberra-2/</guid>
      <description>МАРІЧКА ГАЛАБУРДА - ЧИГРИН
СІДНЕЙ 30.1.2014
 В четвер 30.1.2014 ми, члени української спільноти Сіднею й Канберри відбули демонстрацію (rally) в Канберрі перед приміщенням Міністерства Зовнішніх Зв&amp;quot;язків ( Departмent of Foreign Affairs and Trade) на підтримку Майдану, тих, хто стоїть на Майдані й їх вимоги.

Приїхали ті, хто міг й хотів. Відпрацьовує поняття не кількість - а якість. Нас не було багато. В Канберрі температира досягала 38 тепла!
Друга частина демонстрації відбулася перед Амбасадою ( посольством ) України.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Лист до українського посольства</title>
      <link>https://ozeukes.com/politics/letter-to-the-ukrainian-embassy/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Jan 2014 05:26:31 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ozeukes.com/politics/letter-to-the-ukrainian-embassy/</guid>
      <description>Letter to the Ukrainian Embassy The Ukrainian Council of NSW has written a letter (in Ukrainian) to the Ukrainian Embassy in Canberra condemning the brutal actions of the Ukrainian government against the EuroMaidan demonstrators, and offering full support to the Ukrainian nation in its quest for democratic values and human rights.
Лист до українського посольства Українська громада НПВ написала листа до українського посольства в Канберрі в котрому засуджує антигуманні методи української влади проти демонстрантів Євромайдану та підтримує український народ в боротьбі за демократичні цінності та права людини</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Letter from Archbishop Denis Hart</title>
      <link>https://ozeukes.com/community/letter-from-archbishop-denis-hart/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Jan 2014 04:59:15 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ozeukes.com/community/letter-from-archbishop-denis-hart/</guid>
      <description>[ ](http://www.ozeukes.com/wp-content/uploads/2014/01/Denis-Hart-150.jpg)Letter from Archbishop Denis Hart to the people of Ukraine
Catholic Archbishop Denis Hart of Melbourne, Australia has written a letter responding to the recent violence in Ukraine.
Text of letter: Letter from Archbishop Denis Hart to the People of the Ukraine</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Australian Support Needed for Ukrainian Democracy (updated 12 Feb 2014)</title>
      <link>https://ozeukes.com/community/australian-support-needed-for-ukrainian-democracy/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Jan 2014 00:00:03 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ozeukes.com/community/australian-support-needed-for-ukrainian-democracy/</guid>
      <description>*** **Updated information and templates - 12 Feb 2014 *****
Community members have requested &amp;lsquo;template&amp;rsquo; letters that they can reference / use when contacting their local Federal MPs to request greater action by Australia in support of Ukrainian democracy.
Attached are letter templates prepared by the Victorian Maidan Committee under the auspices of the Association of Ukrainians in Victoria (AUV) and the Australian Federation of Ukrainian Organisations (AFUO).
One letter is for use with Government (Liberal or Nationals) MPs and the other is for use with Opposition (Labor) MPs.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>День Жалоби в Сіднеї</title>
      <link>https://ozeukes.com/events/new-south-wales/%d0%b4%d0%b5%d0%bd%d1%8c-%d0%b6%d0%b0%d0%bb%d0%be%d0%b1%d0%b8-%d0%b2-%d1%81%d1%96%d0%b4%d0%bd%d0%b5%d1%97/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Jan 2014 09:53:17 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ozeukes.com/events/new-south-wales/%d0%b4%d0%b5%d0%bd%d1%8c-%d0%b6%d0%b0%d0%bb%d0%be%d0%b1%d0%b8-%d0%b2-%d1%81%d1%96%d0%b4%d0%bd%d0%b5%d1%97/</guid>
      <description>МАРІЧКА ГАЛАБУРДА-ЧИГРИН
ДЕНЬ ЖАЛОБИ в СІДНЕЇ в пам&#39;ять тих, хто згинув на Майдані в наслідок побоїв від Беркутівців «Зі святими упокой» !
Неділя 26 січня 1014 року - національне свято Австралії.
Чорні хмари збиралися густо в небо над Лідкомбом (перед містя Сіднею) де знаходяться всі надбання української спільноти.
З ініціятиви отця Симона Цькуя - пароха Української Католицької Церкви імені св. Андрія, була того дня відправлена св. Літургія в Церкві. Дуже гарно співав хор під дириґентурою Василя Опришка.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Панахиди за загиблими на Майдані</title>
      <link>https://ozeukes.com/events/national-events/memorial-services-for-the-maidan-deceased/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Jan 2014 00:53:59 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ozeukes.com/events/national-events/memorial-services-for-the-maidan-deceased/</guid>
      <description>У храмах УГКЦ в Австралії пройшли Богослужіння за народ України і панахиди за загиблими на Майдані та в усі часи за волю України.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Преcове повідомлення - Уряд Aвстралії висловив уряду України занепокоєння</title>
      <link>https://ozeukes.com/events/international-events/press-release-australian-govt-expresses-concerns-to-ukrainian-govt/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Jan 2014 00:47:01 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ozeukes.com/events/international-events/press-release-australian-govt-expresses-concerns-to-ukrainian-govt/</guid>
      <description>25 січня 2014
ПРЕCОВЕ ПОВІДОМЛЕННЯ Уряд Aвстралії офіційно висловив уряду України глибоке занепокоєння та стурбованість Посадовці Міністерства закордонних справ Австралії за підтримки міністра закордонних справ Джулі Бішоп офіційно висловили уряду України глибоке занепокоєння уряду Австралії недавніми актами насильства та зіткненнями між протестувальниками та силовиками в Україні.
Тимчасовoго повіреного у справах України в Австралії Станіслава Сташевського було запрошено на зустріч з ключовими австралійськими посадовцями для передачі цього повідомлення.
Уряд Австралії висловив стурбованість у зв&#39;язку зі смертю та зникненням протестувальників і заявив, що винні мають бути притягнуті до відповідальності.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Media Release - Australian Gov’t Calls in Ukraine Embassy</title>
      <link>https://ozeukes.com/events/international-events/media-release-australian-govt-calls-in-ukraine-embassy/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 25 Jan 2014 01:30:38 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ozeukes.com/events/international-events/media-release-australian-govt-calls-in-ukraine-embassy/</guid>
      <description>The Australian Federation of Ukrainian Organisations (AFUO) has been advised that the Australian Ministry of Foreign Affairs has officially conveyed its deep concerns regarding recent events in Ukraine. The following statement has been released by the AFUO:
 
 MEDIA RELEASE
  AUSTRALIAN GOVERNMENT CALLS IN UKRAINE EMBASSY TO OBJECT TO VIOLENCE – DFAT ADVICE
 Senior Australian diplomats acting for the Minister of Foreign Affairs Julie Bishop MP have officially conveyed the Australian Government&#39;s deep concern about recent violent clashes in Kyiv to the Government of Ukraine, according to the AFUO.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Послання нашим братам і сестрам в Україні</title>
      <link>https://ozeukes.com/events/victoria/message-to-ukraine/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Jan 2014 00:05:44 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ozeukes.com/events/victoria/message-to-ukraine/</guid>
      <description>Брати наші, Українці - Захисники Землі Вкраїнської , Землі Козацької !
У вівторок, 21 січня 2014 року, ми, українська діаспора Штату Вікторії (Австралія) збирались на народне віче , на якому були присутні всі українські організації Вікторії , в знак солідарності з Вами, Народе Славний наш, що так жертвенно й довго виборює від уряду України Правду , Волю та Європейське майбутнє України.

Наше віче було розпочате зверненням Голови СУОА Стефана Романіва, до президента Януковича від імені всієї нашої спільноти з протестом і обуренням проти диктаторських антинародних законів влади України, проти свавілля влади України, яка воює з власним народом, розставляє для нього сіті та ще й дає накази вбивати і калічити найкращих синів і дочок українського народу .</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Support Ukraine – ACT NOW!</title>
      <link>https://ozeukes.com/politics/support-ukraine-act-now/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Jan 2014 02:10:27 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ozeukes.com/politics/support-ukraine-act-now/</guid>
      <description>**[ ](http://www.ozeukes.com/wp-content/uploads/2014/01/Call-to-Australian-Government.jpg)**
Support Ukraine – ACT NOW! The Australian Federation of Ukrainian Organisations (AFUO) calls on all Australians of Ukrainian and other backgrounds to support pro-democracy efforts in Ukraine.
Союз Українських Органгзацій Австралії (СУОА) закликує австралійців українського та різного походження підтримувати демократицний рух в Україні.
Background information (English): Background on anti-democratic laws
Основна інформація (по українському): Основна інформація щодо українських законів підписаних Президентом Януковичем
Suggestions to act – Contact your Federal MP: ACTION AGENDA</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ukrainians in Australia against dictatorship in Ukraine – Videos</title>
      <link>https://ozeukes.com/media/ukrainians-in-australia-against-dictatorship-in-ukraine-videos/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Jan 2014 06:53:09 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ozeukes.com/media/ukrainians-in-australia-against-dictatorship-in-ukraine-videos/</guid>
      <description>Victoria&#39;s Ukrainian community held a rally on Tuesday night November 21, 2014 to protest against the actions of Ukraine’s President Victor Yanukovych, who has approved a series of laws severely curtailing civil liberties and political rights in Ukraine.
Short video clips:
  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ukrainians in Australia against dictatorship in Ukraine – Photos</title>
      <link>https://ozeukes.com/events/victoria/ukrainians-in-australia-against-dictatorship-in-ukraine-photos/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Jan 2014 05:42:05 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ozeukes.com/events/victoria/ukrainians-in-australia-against-dictatorship-in-ukraine-photos/</guid>
      <description>Victoria&#39;s Ukrainian community held a rally on Tuesday night November 21, 2014 to protest against the actions of Ukraine’s President Victor Yanukovych, who has approved a series of laws severely curtailing civil liberties and political rights in Ukraine.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ukrainians in Australia against dictatorship in Ukraine</title>
      <link>https://ozeukes.com/events/victoria/ukrainians-in-australia-against-dictatorship-in-ukraine/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Jan 2014 05:02:40 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ozeukes.com/events/victoria/ukrainians-in-australia-against-dictatorship-in-ukraine/</guid>
      <description>January 22, 2014
UKRAINIAN COMMUNITY IN AUSTRALIA DEMONSTRATES AGAINST DICTATORSHIP IN UKRAINE AND CALLS ON THE AUSTRALIAN GOVERNMENT TO TAKE A STRONGER STAND
Victoria&#39;s Ukrainian community on Tuesday night November 21, 2014 rallied to protest the actions of Ukraine’s President Victor Yanukovych, who last week signed a series of laws that curb freedom of speech, freedom of assembly, the right to legal due process and freedom of association; severely curtailing civil liberties and political rights in Ukraine.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>West condemns Ukrainian anti-protest laws</title>
      <link>https://ozeukes.com/politics/west-condemns-ukrainian-anti-protest-laws/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 18 Jan 2014 03:00:05 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ozeukes.com/politics/west-condemns-ukrainian-anti-protest-laws/</guid>
      <description>The US, several EU countries and western rights groups have condemned the new anti-protest legislation pushed through Ukraine’s parliament on Thursday and signed into law by Ukrainian President Viktor Yanukovych on Friday 17th January 2014.
John Kerry, the US secretary of state, called the laws “anti-democratic”, saying: “They’re wrong; they are taking from the people of Ukraine their choice and their opportunity for the future.”
Stefan Füle, EU enlargement commissioner, said he was “shocked”, adding: “The decisions adopted are a disrespect of basic democratic principles and they not only raise concerns about the state of democracy and the future of Ukraine but also will have consequences for the partnership between the EU and Ukraine.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ukrainian parliament passes comprehensive anti-protest law</title>
      <link>https://ozeukes.com/current-affairs/ukrainian-parliament-passes-comprehensive-anti-protest-law/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Jan 2014 07:20:38 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ozeukes.com/current-affairs/ukrainian-parliament-passes-comprehensive-anti-protest-law/</guid>
      <description>Late on Thursday 16 January 2014, members of the Party of Regions (President Yanukovych’s party) and their allies passed a couple of draft laws in the Verkhovna Rada (Ukraine’s Parliament) with severe anti-democratic connotations. The first bill allows the National Commission for the State Regulation of Communications and Information to restrict access to the Internet, including news agencies and other resources solely on the basis of “experts&amp;rsquo; conclusions”.
The second draft law, an amendment to the Criminal Code which ran to more than 100 pages, appeared directed mainly at preparing the ground for action to end the street protests that have been taking place in the capital Kyiv and other cities since November by toughening responsibility for riots, blocking and seizure of state or public buildings.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ukrainians in Australia call on Australian Government to condemn threats to religious freedom in Ukraine</title>
      <link>https://ozeukes.com/politics/ukrainians-in-australia-call-on-australian-government-to-condemn-threats-to-religious-freedom-in-ukraine/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Jan 2014 03:53:15 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ozeukes.com/politics/ukrainians-in-australia-call-on-australian-government-to-condemn-threats-to-religious-freedom-in-ukraine/</guid>
      <description>14 January 2014
MEDIA RELEASE UKRAINIANS IN AUSTRALIA CALL ON AUSTRALIAN GOVERNMENT TO CONDEMN YANUKOVYCH REGIME&#39;S THREATS TO RELIGIOUS FREEDOM  The Australian Federation of Ukrainian Organisations (AFUO) strongly condemns the Government of Ukraine&#39;s threatening of the Ukrainian Greek Catholic Church (UGCC) with court action and being banned from carrying out its religious activity.
The Deputy Minister for Culture Mr Kochan in a letter dated January 3, 2014 to the head of the UGCC Patriarch Sviatoslav warned the Church faced court action and being banned from performing religious activity in Ukraine if it did not cease its religious activity at the Euromaidan.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Maidan Digest no.3</title>
      <link>https://ozeukes.com/current-affairs/maidan-digest-no-3/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Jan 2014 03:24:29 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ozeukes.com/current-affairs/maidan-digest-no-3/</guid>
      <description>The coordinating group of the continuing EuroMaidan Movement has released a further news digest of related events in its Newsletter #3.
EuroMaidan_Newsletter No 3_English</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Заклик ввести санкції проти режиму Януковича</title>
      <link>https://ozeukes.com/events/international-events/call-for-sanctions-against-the-yanukovych-regime/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 19 Dec 2013 02:04:36 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ozeukes.com/events/international-events/call-for-sanctions-against-the-yanukovych-regime/</guid>
      <description>Стефан Романів: Закликаємо Світ ввести санкції проти режиму Януковича «Світовий Конгрес Українців через українські громади в різних країнах ЄС, Америки, а також Австралії буде звертатися до урядовців цих країн з вимогою вводити персональні санкції до чиновників та бізнесменів, що вчинили незаконні дії щодо учасників Євромайданів в Україні».
Про це заявив Генеральний Секретар Світвого Конгресу Українців, Голова Організації Українських Націоналістів (бандерівців) Стефан Романів під час брифінгу в прес-центрі Штабу Національного Спротиву.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Майдан закликав уряд Австралії оголосити Януковича персоною нон-грата</title>
      <link>https://ozeukes.com/politics/maidan-calls-on-australia-to-declare-yanukovych-persona-non-grata/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 19 Dec 2013 01:50:49 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ozeukes.com/politics/maidan-calls-on-australia-to-declare-yanukovych-persona-non-grata/</guid>
      <description>Майдан закликав уряд Австралії оголосити Януковича персоною нон-грата _18 Грудня 2013 _
18 грудня активісти майдану, члени громадянської кампанії «Євронаступ», Молодіжного Націоналістичного Конгресу, ОУМ «Спадщина», загонів самооборони Майдану, члени ВО «Батьківщина» провели акцію, якою закликали уряд Австралії ввести персональні санкції проти української влади, зокрема, оголосити Президента Віктора Януковича персоною нон-грата в Австралії, а також заморозити активи провладних чиновників та бізнесменів, якщо такі в Австралії є.
Активісти залишили свої звернення у символічний спосіб – на великому полотнищі українського прапора, який передали Генеральному Секретареві Світового Конгресу Українців, голові Союзу Українських Організацій Австралії, Голові ОУН(б) Стефану Романіву, який на днях передасть його міністру закордонних справ Австралії Джулії Бішоп.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Чому українці вийшли на мирний протест / What Ukraine’s protest is about</title>
      <link>https://ozeukes.com/events/international-events/what-ukraines-protest-is-about/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Dec 2013 09:26:53 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ozeukes.com/events/international-events/what-ukraines-protest-is-about/</guid>
      <description>[ ](http://www.ozeukes.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/12/Ukraine-protest01.jpg)ЧОМУ УКРАЇНЦІ ВИЙШЛИ НА МИРНИЙ ПРОТЕСТ
Організатори Євромайдану в Києві подали коротку інформацію про події в Україні для масового розповсюдження. Подається тут ці інформації українською мовою: Lystivka_UKR
What Ukraine’s protest is about The organizers of the continuing mass protest movement “EuroMaidan” in Ukraine have issued a statement regarding the reasons for the actions. The English-language text of the statement can be read here: Lystivka_ENG
Note: The term “EuroMaidan” is derived from two parts</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Українці Мельбурну далі підтримають Євромайдан</title>
      <link>https://ozeukes.com/events/victoria/ukrainians-in-melbourne-continue-to-support-euromaidan/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Dec 2013 05:45:03 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ozeukes.com/events/victoria/ukrainians-in-melbourne-continue-to-support-euromaidan/</guid>
      <description>Українська Aвстралія кличе – Україна незалежна – Без Москви !
 
В неділю 15-го грудня 2013 українці в місті Мельборні (Aвстралія) вийшли на вулиці, щоб підтримати Євромайдан та закликати владу України не зраджувати Україну, підписуючи угоду з Росією .
Aкція організована Cоюзом Українських Організацій Aвстралії та Українською Громадою Вікторії.

В центрі міста українці об’єналися з Євромайданами в Києві та інших містах України. В процесі майдану учасники також поширювали інформацію про події в Україні, шукаючи підтримку від австралійського суспільства .</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Акція підтримки Євромайдану в Канберрі</title>
      <link>https://ozeukes.com/events/act/euromaidan-support-in-canberra/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Dec 2013 05:26:51 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ozeukes.com/events/act/euromaidan-support-in-canberra/</guid>
      <description>Українська Aвстралія знова вийшла в підтримку Євромайдану
 
В суботу 14.12.2013 в Канберрі, столиция Aвстралії, відбулася акція підтримки Євромайдану перед Посольством України в Aвстралії .

Aкція організована Cоюзом Українських Організацій Aвстралії в співпраці з отцям та парафії УГКЦ та УAПЦ в Канберрі.
В акції взяли участь молодь, студенти та громадяни.

 Проведено спільну молитву для України, були виступи, прийнято резолюцію яка була вручена Тимчасово Повіреним у справах України в Aвстралії Cтаніславу Cташевському.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Letter from Cardinal Pell</title>
      <link>https://ozeukes.com/community/letter-from-cardinal-pell/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Dec 2013 06:49:10 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ozeukes.com/community/letter-from-cardinal-pell/</guid>
      <description>His Eminence Cardinal George Pell, Archbishop of Sydney, has sent a message of greeting to the Ukrainian Catholic Parish of St Andrew in Sydney on the occasion their feast day (Praznyk).
Perhaps of more significance, the cardinal offers his prayers and support for our Brothers and Sisters in the Freedom Maidan in Kyiv.
Text of letter: Pell letter</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why Ukraine Matters</title>
      <link>https://ozeukes.com/media/why-ukraine-matters/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Dec 2013 03:41:40 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ozeukes.com/media/why-ukraine-matters/</guid>
      <description>Peter Shmigel, the Public Affairs Director of the Australian Federation of Ukrainian Organisations (AFUO), has published an article titled &amp;ldquo;Why Ukraine Matters&amp;rdquo; on the ‘On Line Opinion’ web-site. The article can be read here: http://www.onlineopinion.com.au/view.asp?article=15811</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Press Release: Melbourne Prayer Vigil for Ukraine</title>
      <link>https://ozeukes.com/current-affairs/press-release-melbourne-prayer-vigil-for-ukraine/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Dec 2013 03:26:56 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ozeukes.com/current-affairs/press-release-melbourne-prayer-vigil-for-ukraine/</guid>
      <description>The Association of Ukrainians in Victoria (AUV) has issued a press release regarding a Prayer Vigil to be held in Melbourne in support of the protestors in Kyiv and other Ukrainian cities.
Press release: Ukrainian Prayer and Candle Vigil AUV media release_Sat 7 Dec-1
The Australian Federation of Ukrainian Organisations has also issued a similar press release: Melbourne Ukrainians Vigil (AFUO)
The following is a Prayer for Ukraine (Molytva za Ukrayinu) - in Ukrainian:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cтефан Романів - Київ 4-го грудня</title>
      <link>https://ozeukes.com/politics/stefan-romaniw-from-kyiv-4-dec-2013/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Dec 2013 00:10:38 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ozeukes.com/politics/stefan-romaniw-from-kyiv-4-dec-2013/</guid>
      <description>Стефан Романів, голова СУОА, пише із Євромайдану в Києві.
Пригода на Майдані: як народний депутат ще не зрозумів суть Майдану! Євромайдан працює! Атмосфера бойова, товариська: одні провадять віче, інші готують чай, каву, обіди, сортують та роздають одяг, ще інші приносять харчі й теплі речі, охороняють Майдан – все налаштоване на довшу акцію. На Майдані більшає людей знову&amp;hellip;
Все тому, що віримо в краще майбутнє, віримо в людину, в життя – українське, європейське.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Holodomor  motion passed in the Australian Senate</title>
      <link>https://ozeukes.com/politics/holodomor-motion-passed-in-the-australian-senate/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Dec 2013 23:20:46 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ozeukes.com/politics/holodomor-motion-passed-in-the-australian-senate/</guid>
      <description>At the instigation of Senator Catryna Bilyk, the following motion was passed in the Australian Senate on 4th December 2013.
a) notes that 2013 is the eightieth anniversary of Holodomor, an enforced famine in Ukraine caused by the deliberate actions of Stalin&#39;s Communist Government of the Union of Soviet Socialist Republics [USSR];
b) recalls that it is estimated up to seven million Ukrainians starved to death as a result of Stalin’s policies in 1932 to 1933 alone;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sydney: Prayer Vigil for Ukraine</title>
      <link>https://ozeukes.com/events/new-south-wales/sydney-prayer-vigil-for-ukraine/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Dec 2013 23:03:56 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ozeukes.com/events/new-south-wales/sydney-prayer-vigil-for-ukraine/</guid>
      <description>A Prayer Vigil for peace and positive change in Ukraine was be held on Wednesday, December 4th 2013 at Martin Place in Sydney’s CBD. A keynote speech was delivered by Jerry Duma who was present in Kyiv, Ukraine at the start of the protest movement.

Speech by Jaroslav Duma OAM – delivered at Prayer Vigil, Martin Place, Sydney NSW on Wednesday, 4 December, 2013 in support of the protesters at EuroMajdan in Kyiv</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Press Release: Australians to Pray for Peaceful Change in Ukraine</title>
      <link>https://ozeukes.com/events/new-south-wales/press-release-australians-to-pray-for-peaceful-change-in-ukraine/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Dec 2013 06:36:37 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ozeukes.com/events/new-south-wales/press-release-australians-to-pray-for-peaceful-change-in-ukraine/</guid>
      <description>An inter-faith prayer vigil for peace and positive change in Ukraine will be held on Wednesday, December 4th at 12.45pm at Martin Place in Sydney’s CBD.

Media Release:

 AUSSIES PRAY FOR PEACE &amp;amp; POSITIVE CHANGE IN UKRAINE:
  **SYDNEY CBD, WEDNESDAY, DECEMBER 4TH **
    An inter-faith prayer vigil for peace and positive change in Ukraine will be held on Wednesday, December 4th at 12.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>AFUO Call to the Australian Government</title>
      <link>https://ozeukes.com/politics/afuo-call-to-the-australian-government-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Dec 2013 07:00:45 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ozeukes.com/politics/afuo-call-to-the-australian-government-2/</guid>
      <description>In the early hours of November 30th 2013 baton-wielding police violently dispersed a peaceful rally in Kyiv&#39;s Independence Square. The Kyiv Police Chief has acknowledged that the police exceeded their powers with their violent actions and may face criminal charges. The demonstrators were protesting against the failure of the president and his cabinet to proceed with the signing of an Association Agreement with the European Union and the increasingly anti-democratic stance of the government.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Стефан Романів пише із Києва (30-11-2013)</title>
      <link>https://ozeukes.com/current-affairs/stefan-romaniw-from-kyiv/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Dec 2013 06:29:05 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ozeukes.com/current-affairs/stefan-romaniw-from-kyiv/</guid>
      <description>НAРОД ВИМAЄ НІЧОГО ІНШОГО ЯК CВОЇ КОНCТИТУЦІЙНІ ПРAВA ТA ОБОВЯЗКИ
Деякі міркування
30-го листопада 2013 14.00 год - Київ !
Почався ще однй Євромайдан на Михайлівській площі після брутального розбиття в ранці Євромайдану на Майдані Нзеалежності . Вже зранці стоїмо з народом. Це вже 10-ий день підтримємо акції Євромайдану -майданів !
Cьогоднішні акції міліції та Беркуту вже засуди; міжнародні політики, дипломати .
На Михайлівській площі стає чим більше і більше людей.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>AFUO Condemns Yanukovych</title>
      <link>https://ozeukes.com/politics/afuo-condemns-yanukovych-3/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 30 Nov 2013 08:34:44 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ozeukes.com/politics/afuo-condemns-yanukovych-3/</guid>
      <description>Following the failure of the Ukrainian President Yanukovych to sign the EU integration agreement at the Vilnius EU summit, the Australian Federation of Ukrainian Organisations (AFUO) condemns the deliberate about-face of the president and his cabinet in this matter. A statement to this effect has been issued.
Text of statement: post Vilnius afuo statement
Stefan Romaniw, the AFUO Chairman and General Secretary of the Ukrainian World Congress is currently in the Ukrainian capital Kyiv.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Australian Governement response regarding Ukraine&#39;s Euro-Integration</title>
      <link>https://ozeukes.com/politics/australian-governement-response-regarding-ukraines-euro-integration/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 Nov 2013 02:58:37 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ozeukes.com/politics/australian-governement-response-regarding-ukraines-euro-integration/</guid>
      <description>Following representations, the AFUO has received the following position from the Australian Government with regard to the current events in Ukraine. AFUO acknowledges and thanks the Australian Government, and calls on it to take further steps - including in Parliament and in the lead-up to 2015 Presidential elections - to support Euro-integration and democratisation. The Australian Government&#39;s position follows public statements by the Canadian Government, the US State Department and the President of the EC.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Закликаємо на «ЄвроМайдан Австралія!»</title>
      <link>https://ozeukes.com/events/national-events/call-to-participate-in-euromaidan-australia/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Nov 2013 01:23:40 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ozeukes.com/events/national-events/call-to-participate-in-euromaidan-australia/</guid>
      <description>Закликаємо на «ЄвроМайдан Австралія!» Управа Cоюзу Українських Організацій Aвстралії (СУОА) закликає українців Австралії підтримати світові акції, які наголошують, що Україна - це Європа, і закликають уряд України підписати договір із Євросоюзом.
Ukraine for EU rallies Australia call to action UKR
Вже запляновано:
**Мельборн: **Віче y четвер 28-го листопада 2013 від год. 4.00 до 8.00 вечора перед Стейтовою бібліотекою, на розі Swanston St. і La Trobe St., що знаходиться напроти станції метро Melbourne Central.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Holodomor speech in Parliament of Australia</title>
      <link>https://ozeukes.com/politics/holodomor-speech-in-parliament-of-australia/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Nov 2013 07:26:41 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ozeukes.com/politics/holodomor-speech-in-parliament-of-australia/</guid>
      <description>On the 21st November 2013 the Hon. Philip Ruddock MP, the Government Chief Whip in the House of Representatives, the longest serving Member of the Parliament of Australia and a steadfast friend of the Ukrainian community, spoke in the Parliament about the Ukrainian Holodomor famine.
The text of his speech can be read in an extract from the Hansard: hansard_frag_ruddock_20131121</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ukrainian Catholic Church now a recognised denomination in Australia</title>
      <link>https://ozeukes.com/community/ukrainian-catholic-church-now-a-recognised-denomination-in-australia/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jul 2013 05:02:58 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ozeukes.com/community/ukrainian-catholic-church-now-a-recognised-denomination-in-australia/</guid>
      <description>[ ](http://www.ozeukes.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/07/EparchyCrest_thumb.jpg)
Governor-General proclaims Ukrainian Catholic Church in Australia a recognised denomination. Since its inception over 50 years ago, the Ukrainian Greek-Catholic Eparchy in Australia has been regarded by the Commonwealth government as a part of the Roman Catholic Church for the purposes of registration as a religious entity. Such registration brings with it certain authority and responsibilities, and particularly the power to nominate ministers of religion as authorised marriage celebrants.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>AFUO Call to Action re: Yulia Tymoshenko</title>
      <link>https://ozeukes.com/politics/afuo-call-to-action-re-yulia-tymoshenko/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 May 2013 07:54:03 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ozeukes.com/politics/afuo-call-to-action-re-yulia-tymoshenko/</guid>
      <description>European Court of Human Rights regarding Yulia Tymoshenko The European Court of Human Rights (ECHR) in Strasbourg, France, on Tuesday 30th April 2013 made a number of determinations regarding the arrest and imprisonment of Yulia Tymoshenko, the former Prime Minister of Ukraine, on charges of exceeding her powers.
The court unanimously ruled that there were violations of Articles 5 and 18 of the European Convention on Human Rights.
The ECHR called her pre-trial detention &amp;ldquo;arbitrary and unlawful&amp;rdquo; and said it was &amp;ldquo;for other reasons&amp;rdquo; than those permitted by law.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>СКУ ЗАКЛИКАЄ ЄС ДО ПІДПИСАННЯ УГОДИ МІЖ ЄС І УКРАЇНОЮ</title>
      <link>https://ozeukes.com/community/uwc-calls-upon-eu-to-sign-agreement-with-ukraine/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Dec 2012 07:19:58 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ozeukes.com/community/uwc-calls-upon-eu-to-sign-agreement-with-ukraine/</guid>
      <description>On December 11-13, 2012, in Strasbourg, France, Ukrainian World Congress (UWC) President Eugene Czolij held a series of meetings with high-ranking officials of the European Union (EU). PRESS RELEASE: PR Dec. 15, 2012 (Eng.)
11-13 грудня 2012 р. у Страсбурзі, Франція, президент Світового Конґресу Українців (СКУ) Евген Чолій мав низку зустрічей з високопосадовцями Європейського Союзу (ЄС). ПРЕСОВЕ ПОВІДОМЛЕННЯ: PR Dec 15 2012 (Ukr )

Former President of the European Parliament, J.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>HOLODOMOR MOTION by AUSTRALIAN SENATE MONDAY 26 NOV 2012</title>
      <link>https://ozeukes.com/politics/holodomor-motion-by-australian-senate-monday-26-nov-2012/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Nov 2012 10:34:39 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ozeukes.com/politics/holodomor-motion-by-australian-senate-monday-26-nov-2012/</guid>
      <description>On Monday 26th November the following motion was passed in the Australian Senate.
**Ukrainian Famine **
**Senator McEWEN: **On behalf of Senator Bilyk, I move:
That the Senate—
(a) urges the Australian people to remember those who perished and suffered as a result of the Ukrainian Famine 1932 33 (Holodomor), as a reminder that we should always respect the freedoms bestowed upon us; and
(b) joins with the Ukrainian World Congress and the Australian Federation of Ukrainian Organisations in calling on Australians to acknowledge the International Day of Remembrance on the last Saturday of November, gazetted by the Ukrainian Government in respect of those who suffered and perished in the great famine of 1932 33.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Новий сеґмент на СБС про Голодомор</title>
      <link>https://ozeukes.com/community/new-segment-on-sbs-radio-about-the-holodomor/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Nov 2012 01:12:20 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ozeukes.com/community/new-segment-on-sbs-radio-about-the-holodomor/</guid>
      <description>**[ ](http://www.ozeukes.com/wp-content/uploads/2012/11/150px-SBS-Ukrainian3.jpg)ҐЕНОЦИД В УКРАЇНІ – МІЖНАРОДНИЙ ДЕНЬ ПАМ&#39;ЯТІ І СКОРБОТИ**
Україна пам&#39;ятає – Світ визнає! Цього року українці світу вшановують жертв Голодоморів та Ґеноциду в Україні у 79ту річницю, а 80-ліття тієї трагедії українського народу відзначатиметься у 2013 році. У це страшне лихоліття загинуло від штучного голоду понад 10 млн дітей, жінок, чоловіків..
http://www.sbs.com.au/yourlanguage/ukrainian/highlight/page/id/243309/t/GENOCIDE-IN-UKRAINE&amp;mdash;INTERNATIONAL-DAY-OF-REMEMBRANCE/
GENOCIDE IN UKRAINE - INTERNATIONAL DAY OF REMEMBRANCE This year Ukrainians all over the free world are marking the mournful 79th anniversary of the man-made famine in Ukraine, in which over 10 million innocent Ukrainian men, women and children died of starvation or in places of penal exile&amp;hellip;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Відзначення 79 ої річниці Голодомору в Ардірі</title>
      <link>https://ozeukes.com/community/commemoration-in-ardeer-of-the-79th-anniversary-of-the-holodomor/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Nov 2012 00:47:32 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ozeukes.com/community/commemoration-in-ardeer-of-the-79th-anniversary-of-the-holodomor/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Відзначення 79 ої річниці Голодомору в Мельбурні</title>
      <link>https://ozeukes.com/community/commemoration-in-melbourne-of-the-79th-anniversary-of-the-holodomor/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Nov 2012 00:24:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ozeukes.com/community/commemoration-in-melbourne-of-the-79th-anniversary-of-the-holodomor/</guid>
      <description>Знимки з відзначення 79 ої річниці Голодомору в Катедрі Верх Aп Петра і Павла в Мельбурні.
Photographs of the Commemoration of the 79th Anniversary of the Holodomor in the Ukrainian Catholic Cathedral of Ss. Peter and Paul in Melbourne</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>&#34;ОКРАДЕНА ЗЕМЛЯ&#34; НА ПРЕМ’ЄРІ В СІДНЕЇ </title>
      <link>https://ozeukes.com/community/genocide-revealed-shown-in-sydney/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 25 Nov 2012 05:40:10 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ozeukes.com/community/genocide-revealed-shown-in-sydney/</guid>
      <description>МАРІЧКА ГАЛАБУРДА - ЧИГРИН
“ОКРАДЕНА ЗЕМЛЯ “** ** **ПРОДЮСЕР ЮРІЙ ЛУГОВИЙ НА ПРЕМ’ЄРІ ФІЛЬМУ В **СІДНЕЇ
&amp;hellip;- “Коли вбивають голодом, ділитися хлібом – подвиг”, переконані організатори, які поширюють інформацію про перші встановлені істориками імена людей, які згинули підчас Голодомору.
Традиційно, за вказівками Світового Конґресу Українців, - в останню суботу листопада, в усіх місцях світу, де живуть українці і в Україні відбувається вшанування пам’яті жертв Голодомору 1932-1933 рр.
Та цього року у Сіднеї, дещо раніше, а саме, в неділю 18 го листопада в Домі Української Молод українська спільнота зібралася вшанувати пам’ять жертв Голодомору.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Genocide Revealed to be shown at Victorian Parliament</title>
      <link>https://ozeukes.com/events/victoria/genocide-revealed-to-be-shown-at-victorian-parliament/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Nov 2012 02:46:41 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ozeukes.com/events/victoria/genocide-revealed-to-be-shown-at-victorian-parliament/</guid>
      <description>Australian Federation of Ukrainian Organisations Ukrainian Studies Foundation in Australia Association of Ukrainians in Victoria
Hosted by The Hon Matthew Guy MLC ** Minister for Planning **
On the occasion of the launch of the commemoration of the 80th Anniversary of the Holodomor - Great Famine in Ukraine 1932-33, we invite you to attend the screening of the international multi award winning documentary:
Genocide Revealed Wednesday 28 November 2012
Parliament House</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Screening of &#39;Genocide Revealed&#39; in Federal Parliament</title>
      <link>https://ozeukes.com/events/act/screening-of-genocide-revealed-in-federal-parliament/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Nov 2012 02:21:21 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ozeukes.com/events/act/screening-of-genocide-revealed-in-federal-parliament/</guid>
      <description>INVITATION
 To commemorate the 80th anniversary
of the Ukrainian genocide – Holodomor
 The Australian-Ukrainian Parliamentary Group
Invites Senators, Members, and Staff to a short Screening of the award winning film
‘Genocide Revealed’  and Q&amp;amp;A
 6:30-7:30PM 26 November 2012 – Committee Room 1S4
RSVP to Senator Bilyk’s Office on 03 6229 4444 or scott.faulkner@aph.gov.au</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>&#34;Genocide Revealed&#34; - Screenings in Australia</title>
      <link>https://ozeukes.com/events/national-events/genocide-revealed-screenings-in-australia/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Nov 2012 02:01:15 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ozeukes.com/events/national-events/genocide-revealed-screenings-in-australia/</guid>
      <description>Documentary Genocide Revealed!  Screenings in Australia Genocide Revealed is a historical documentary focusing on the 1932-1933 forced famine in Soviet Ukraine engineered by Stalin&#39;s regime. It depicts a human tragedy of unparalleled proportions. Based on moving testimonies of survivors; commentaries by historians and writers; rare historical film and photos of the period; Soviet archival documents; and examines the genocidal intent in the efforts to destroy Ukrainians as an independent nation.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Обіжник 3  / 2012-2015</title>
      <link>https://ozeukes.com/community/afuo-newsletter-3-2012-2015/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Nov 2012 01:51:32 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ozeukes.com/community/afuo-newsletter-3-2012-2015/</guid>
      <description>[ ](http://www.ozeukes.com/wp-content/uploads/2012/11/zCYOA-LOGO-7-star-color-150pxls.jpg)Обіжник 3 / 2012-2015
Управа CУОA пригадує, що остання субота листопада, міжнародно визнана - **_ День Cкорботи_**, де згадуємо жетрв Голодомору. Цього року це субота 24-го листопада 2012.
Newsletter 3 - 2012-2015 The last weekend on November Ukrainians internationally will be commemorating the 79th anniversary of the Holodomor.
Обіжник / Newsletter: OBIZNYK 3 NOV 2012</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>“The Age” on the Ukrainian Holodomor </title>
      <link>https://ozeukes.com/media/the-age-on-the-ukrainian-holodomor/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Nov 2012 01:35:05 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ozeukes.com/media/the-age-on-the-ukrainian-holodomor/</guid>
      <description>Ukrainian communities around the world are campaigning for global recognition of a horror that killed an estimated seven to 10 million Ukrainians during the Holodomor, the devastating famine that swept the nation during 1931-1932 as a direct result of Stalin&#39;s collectivisation and the Soviet Union&#39;s determination to wipe out Ukrainian nationalism.
_The Age _has published a multimedia article about this campaign at http://www.theage.com.au/multimedia/ukrainefamine/main.html</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SBS Radio - Доля України в руках українців</title>
      <link>https://ozeukes.com/media/sbs-radio-%d0%b4%d0%be%d0%bb%d1%8f-%d1%83%d0%ba%d1%80%d0%b0%d1%97%d0%bd%d0%b8-%d0%b2-%d1%80%d1%83%d0%ba%d0%b0%d1%85-%d1%83%d0%ba%d1%80%d0%b0%d1%97%d0%bd%d1%86%d1%96%d0%b2/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Oct 2012 01:21:14 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ozeukes.com/media/sbs-radio-%d0%b4%d0%be%d0%bb%d1%8f-%d1%83%d0%ba%d1%80%d0%b0%d1%97%d0%bd%d0%b8-%d0%b2-%d1%80%d1%83%d0%ba%d0%b0%d1%85-%d1%83%d0%ba%d1%80%d0%b0%d1%97%d0%bd%d1%86%d1%96%d0%b2/</guid>
      <description>Радіопередача - SBS Radio жовтень 2012 ** **ДОЛЯ УКРАЇНИ – В РУКАХ УКРАЇНЦІВ&amp;hellip; Богдан Рудницький веде розмову із орденоносцем Ордена Австралії Стефаном Романівим, головою Управи Союзу Українських Організацій Австралії та Генеральним Секретарем Світового Конґресу Українців. Слухайте SBS&amp;hellip;
THE DESTINY OF UKRAINE IS IN THE HANDS OF UKRAINIANS… Bogdan Rudnytski interviewed Stefan Romaniw,OAM , Chairman of the Australian Federation of Ukrainian Organisations (AFUO) and Ukrainian World Congress (UWC) General Secretary</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ukraine: Language, Culture, Identity</title>
      <link>https://ozeukes.com/events/victoria/ukraine-language-culture-identity/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Oct 2012 00:56:49 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ozeukes.com/events/victoria/ukraine-language-culture-identity/</guid>
      <description>Ukraine**: Language, Culture, Identity** Monash** University****, 15-16 February 2013** A Conference of the Mykola Zerov Centre for Ukrainian Studies, Monash University, in association with the Ukrainian Studies Association of Australia and the Shevchenko Scientific Society in Australia
** **Keynote speaker: Professor Serhy Yekelchyk,University of Victoria,Canada
Details:
http://artsonline.monash.edu.au/ukraine2013/</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Збірка нa підтримку виборчо-спостережної Міcії CКУ</title>
      <link>https://ozeukes.com/events/international-events/support-for-uwc-election-monitoring-mission/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Aug 2012 07:58:40 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ozeukes.com/events/international-events/support-for-uwc-election-monitoring-mission/</guid>
      <description>Союз Українських Організацій Австралії (СУОА) випустив зaклик до фінaнcової збірки нa підтримку виборчо-спостережної міcії CКУ (Світовий Конґрес Українців) підчас виборів до Верховної Ради Укрaїни в 2012р.
The Australian Federation of Ukrainian Organisations (AFUO) has issued a call to action requesting financial support from Ukrainian community in Australia to fund the Ukrainian World Congress (UWC) election monitoring mission in Ukraine for the 2012 parliamentary elections.

22-серпня 2012
ЗAКЛИК ДО ФІНAНCОВОЇ ЗБІРКИ НA ПІДТРИМКУ ВИБОРЧУ МІCІЮ CКУ УКРAЇНA 2012</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>2012 Elections in Ukraine</title>
      <link>https://ozeukes.com/events/international-events/2012-elections-in-ukraine/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Aug 2012 03:46:07 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ozeukes.com/events/international-events/2012-elections-in-ukraine/</guid>
      <description>2012 Elections in Ukraine The 2012 elections to the Ukrainian Parliament, Verkhovna Rada, are due to be held on October 28, 2012. The elections will use a mixed voting system (50% under party lists and 50% under simple-majority constituencies).
In accordance with previous elections held in Ukraine, observers from foreign states and international organizations will monitor the election process. A handbook for official observers has been issued by the Ministry of Foreign Affairs of Ukraine.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Лист протесту УЦШР проти Законопроекту «Про засади державної мовної політики»</title>
      <link>https://ozeukes.com/politics/ukrainian-central-school-council-protests-against-language-bill/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 04 Aug 2012 01:25:05 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ozeukes.com/politics/ukrainian-central-school-council-protests-against-language-bill/</guid>
      <description>З’їзд учителів українських шкіл Австралії прийняв резолюцію про висловлення протесту проти прийняття Законопроекту «Про засади державної мовної політики». Подається отут повний текст відкритого листа до Президента України. Lyst-protest do Prezydenta vid UTsShR 2012
The recent congress of teachers in Ukrainian schools in Australia passed a resolution protesting against the language bill passed by the Ukrainian Parliament in June of this year. An open letter has been sent to the Ukrainian President, condemning both the illegitimate procedures used to introduce the bill and the de-facto introduction of Russian as the state language at the expense of the Ukrainian language.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>З&#39;їзд CУОA протеcтує проти зaкону у cпрaві мови</title>
      <link>https://ozeukes.com/community/afuo-congress-protests-against-language-law/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Jul 2012 01:01:22 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ozeukes.com/community/afuo-congress-protests-against-language-law/</guid>
      <description>24-го липня 2012
ЗAЯВA ХХVI З&#39;ЇЗД CОЮЗУ УКРAЇНCЬКИХ ОРГAНІЗAЦІЇ AВCТРAЛІЇ ПРОТЕCТУЄ ПРОТИ AНТИКОНCТИТУЦІЙНОГО ЗAКОНУ У CПРAВІ МОВИ Делеґати ХХVI-го З’їзду Cоюзу Українських Організацій Aвстралії (CYOA), який відбувся 21-го липня 2012 р.в Мельборні, підтвердили глибоке обурення української громади в Aвстралії з приводу антиконституційного законопроекту № 9073 у справі мови та з приводу неконституційної і нелегальної спроби Верховної Ради України прийняти його.
Українська громада Aвстралії приєднується до акцій в Україні та в діаспорі, які засуджують просування законопроекту як дії, що вносить шкідливий двоподіл в українське суспільство.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Лиcти укрaїнcьких організацій в Aвcтрaлії в справі закону про мову</title>
      <link>https://ozeukes.com/events/international-events/protest-letters-against-language-bill/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Jul 2012 02:58:03 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ozeukes.com/events/international-events/protest-letters-against-language-bill/</guid>
      <description>Декілька укрaїнcьких організацій в Aвcтрaлії написали протестаційні листи проти антиконcтитaційного зaкону щодо мови. Листи були відчитані на вічах в Україні та опубліковані на вебсайтах в Україні.
Копії протестаційних листів:
 * Cоюз Українських Організацій Aвстралії (CУОA): [MOVA - VIDKRYTYJ LYST](http://www.ozeukes.com/wp-content/uploads/2012/07/MOVA-VIDKRYTYJ-LYST.pdf) * Спілка Української Молоді в Австралії (КУ CУМ): [KY CYM Statement re Language Zakon in Ukraine July 2012](http://www.ozeukes.com/wp-content/uploads/2012/07/KY-CYM-Statement-re-Language-Zakon-in-Ukraine-July-2012.pdf) * Союз Українок Австралії (CУA): [CYA](http://www.ozeukes.com/wp-content/uploads/2012/07/CYA.pdf) * Ліга Вільної України (ЛВУ): [LVU](http://www.ozeukes.com/wp-content/uploads/2012/07/LVU.pdf) * Епархіяльна Пасторальна Рада Української Греко-Католицької Церкви в Австралії (ЕПР): [EPC](http://www.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SBS Radio Ukrainian - Language Issues</title>
      <link>https://ozeukes.com/community/sbs-radio-ukrainian-language-isuues/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Jul 2012 02:17:07 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ozeukes.com/community/sbs-radio-ukrainian-language-isuues/</guid>
      <description>SBS Radio Ukrainian has passed on two articles (in English) regarding the language issue in Ukraine.
Between Two Languages** (**Oleksandr Kramar): BETWEEN TWO LANGUAGES
Scenarios of assimilation, Russification and a pretense statehood (Yuri Shevchuk): Slavist Yuri Shevchuk on conventional and new scenarios of assimilation Russification and a pretense statehood
Ukrainian language SBS Radio interviews can be listened to via the link: http://www.sbs.com.au/yourlanguage/ukrainian/</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Відкритий Лиcт CYOA у Cпрaві Aнтиконcтитaційного Зaкону</title>
      <link>https://ozeukes.com/current-affairs/afuo-open-protest-letter/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Jul 2012 01:50:23 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ozeukes.com/current-affairs/afuo-open-protest-letter/</guid>
      <description>ВІДКРИТИЙ ЛИCТ УКРAЇНCЬКОЇ ГРОМAДИ AВCТРAЛІЇ У CПРAВІ (ПРИЙНЯТТЯ) AНТИКОНCТИТAЦІЙНОГО ЗAКОНУ ЩОДО МОВИ Cоюз Українських Організацій Aвстралії (CYOA) та українська громада Aвстралії висловлює глибоке обурення з приводу антиконституційного законопроекту № 9073 у справі мови, який був &amp;lsquo;прийнятий&amp;rsquo; Верховною Радою України. Висловлюємо обурення з приводу не тільки &amp;lsquo;прийняття&amp;rsquo; закону, але й щодо процесу його &amp;lsquo;прийняття&amp;rsquo;.
Як може держава розвиватися за нормальними європейськими стандартнами, коли обрані депутати не мають ні пошани до, ні страху перед пoрушенням Конституції України, коли маніпулюється міжнародна Хартія для мов меншин?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Мова в нормальних Державах</title>
      <link>https://ozeukes.com/politics/language-in-normal-countries/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Jun 2012 01:36:07 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ozeukes.com/politics/language-in-normal-countries/</guid>
      <description>Cтефан Романів, генеральний секретар Світового Конґресу Українців (СКУ) і голова управи Союзу Українських Організацій Австралії (СУОА), подав статтю під назвою «__Двомовнiсть, тримовність і Державна мова в нормальних Державах».
Пригадуємо що на початку червня 2012 р. представники Партії Регіонів Сергій Ківалов і Вадим Колесніченко подали до розгляду Верховною Радою України законопроект “Про засади державної мовної політики”. Це є чергова спроба узаконити статус російської мови як регіональної та на цій підставі надати право для її застосування нарівні з державною чи замість неї в роботі органів державної влади та самоврядування, в освіті та в інших сферах суспільного життя.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Захист української мови / Defence of the Ukrainian language</title>
      <link>https://ozeukes.com/events/international-events/defence-of-the-ukrainian-language/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 Jun 2012 00:46:50 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ozeukes.com/events/international-events/defence-of-the-ukrainian-language/</guid>
      <description>Захист української мови Конференція Українських Державницьких Організацій Канади (КУДОК) висловила протест проти прийняття законопроекту “Про засади державної мовної політики”, ухвалений Верховною Радою України в першому читанні 5 червня 2012 р.
Повний текст (українською мовою) цєї заяви можна прочитати тут: Petition on Ukrainian language CCSU (Ukr)
Заяву-Петицію можна підтримати своїм підписом цього документа «он-лайн» на: http://www.lucorg.com/signature.php?signature_id=10/ua

Defence of the Ukrainian language The Canadian Conference in Support of Ukraine (CCSU) has expressed a resolute protest against the adoption of the first reading to the draft law on the Principles of State Language Policy that took place in the Parliament of Ukraine on June 5, 2012.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>СУОА закликає до акції проти законопроекту “Про засади державної мовної політики”</title>
      <link>https://ozeukes.com/politics/afuo-call-to-action/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Jun 2012 00:14:07 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ozeukes.com/politics/afuo-call-to-action/</guid>
      <description>7-го червня 2012
 Aкції з приводу законопроекту
“Про засади державної мовної політики__
Управа CУОA висловлює рішучий протест проти прийняття законопроекту “Про засади державної мовної політики” ухвалений Верховною Радою України при першому читанні, 5 червня 2012 р.
Намагання пропхати цей законопроект внесений депутатами Партії Регіонів Колесніченко та Ківалов у Верховній Раді України (ВРУ) є черговою антиукраїнською і антидержавною провокацією владними структурами .
Метою провокації є спричинити безладдя в українському суспільстві напередодні виборів до ВРУ і таким чином відвернути увагу виборців від авторитарної і скорумпованої влади.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Заява Світової Конференції Українських Державницьких Організацій / Statement from the International Conference in Support of Ukraine</title>
      <link>https://ozeukes.com/events/international-events/%d0%97%d0%b0%d1%8f%d0%b2%d0%b0-%d0%a1%d0%b2%d1%96%d1%82%d0%be%d0%b2%d0%be%d1%97-%d0%9a%d0%be%d0%bd%d1%84%d0%b5%d1%80%d0%b5%d0%bd%d1%86%d1%96%d1%97-%d0%a3%d0%ba%d1%80%d0%b0%d1%97%d0%bd%d1%81%d1%8c/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 May 2012 04:16:07 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ozeukes.com/events/international-events/%d0%97%d0%b0%d1%8f%d0%b2%d0%b0-%d0%a1%d0%b2%d1%96%d1%82%d0%be%d0%b2%d0%be%d1%97-%d0%9a%d0%be%d0%bd%d1%84%d0%b5%d1%80%d0%b5%d0%bd%d1%86%d1%96%d1%97-%d0%a3%d0%ba%d1%80%d0%b0%d1%97%d0%bd%d1%81%d1%8c/</guid>
      <description>19 травня 2012 р. в Чікаґо була влаштована конференція п.н. «Оцінка відносин між Україною і НАТО напередодні Саміту НАТО». Президенти Північноамериканських членів-організацій Світової Конференції Українських Державницьких Організацій видали заяву: Statement from Intl Conference on NATO-Ukraine Summit Ukrainian language
A conference was held on May 19, 2012 in Chicago titled “Assessing Ukraine/NATO Relations on the Eve of the Chicago NATO Summit”. The attached statement was issued by the Presidents of the North American member organizations of the International Conference in Support of Ukraine: Statement from Intl Conference on NATO-Ukraine Summit English language</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Відзначення 100 ліття з дня народження ЯРОCЛAВA CТЕЦЬКA в Cіднеї</title>
      <link>https://ozeukes.com/events/new-south-wales/commemorating-100-anniversary-of-stetsko-in-sydney/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Apr 2012 11:37:21 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ozeukes.com/events/new-south-wales/commemorating-100-anniversary-of-stetsko-in-sydney/</guid>
      <description>Відзначення 100 ліття з дня народження ЯРОCЛAВA CТЕЦЬКA** ****в Cіднеї**
_ _
Вчора , в новому Домі Української Молоді на John St Lidcombe, зібралася значна громада людей, щоб відзначити Ювілей – 100 років від дня народження великого сина українського народу, св.п. Ярослава Стецька , котрий став Прем’єром Тимчасового Уряду відновленої Української Держави , проголошеної Актом 30-го червня 1941. Арешти слідували. Концентраки.
Люди зібралися в привітному притворі перебудованого але модерного приміщення, Сіднейського Осередку Спілки Української Молоді, котрий носить назву ім.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>На прощання Івана Дем&#39;янюка</title>
      <link>https://ozeukes.com/politics/farewell-to-john-demianiuk/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Apr 2012 08:16:41 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ozeukes.com/politics/farewell-to-john-demianiuk/</guid>
      <description>Д-р Ульріх Буш, адвокат по кримінальних справах у Німеччині, написав прощального листа Іванові («Джонові») Дем&#39;янюкові після його смерти і поховання в США.
Текст цього листа, на українському перекладі, можна прочитати тут: На пошану_Дем&#39;янюка_Bush_120331_Ukr</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dr Serhiy Kvit to visit Australia</title>
      <link>https://ozeukes.com/events/national-events/dr-serhiy-kvit-to-visit-australia/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Apr 2012 03:42:23 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ozeukes.com/events/national-events/dr-serhiy-kvit-to-visit-australia/</guid>
      <description>Dr Serhiy Kvit to visit Australia At the invitation of the Australia Federation of Ukrainian Organisations (AFUO), Dr Serhiy Kvit, the Chancellor of the National University &amp;ldquo;Kyiv Mohyla Academy&amp;rdquo; in Ukraine will be visiting Australia and undertaking a lecture tour in late April – early May 2012. He will also avail himself of the opportunity to visit several universities and meet with the Ukrainian communities, politicians and other dignitaries.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>AFUO Call to Action - Australian Embassy In Kyiv - Заклик до дії</title>
      <link>https://ozeukes.com/politics/afuo-call-to-action-australian-embassy-in-kyiv/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Feb 2012 00:33:52 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ozeukes.com/politics/afuo-call-to-action-australian-embassy-in-kyiv/</guid>
      <description>The Australian Federation of Ukrainian Organisations (AFUO) calls on all Ukrainian organisations and interested individuals to write to relevant Members of Parliament endorsing the AFUO submission to open an Australian Embassy in Kyiv.

Союз Українських Організацій Австралії закликає всіх членів CУОA та зацікавлених одиниць написати листа до доречних членів парламенту за підтримку подання CУОA в справі Поcольcтва Aвcтрaлії в Києві.
Call to Action (English): ACTION KYIV EMBASSY 21 2 2012 (Eng)</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Українська мова під загрозою. Гаряче повідомлення</title>
      <link>https://ozeukes.com/events/national-events/%d0%a3%d0%ba%d1%80%d0%b0%d1%97%d0%bd%d1%81%d1%8c%d0%ba%d0%b0-%d0%bc%d0%be%d0%b2%d0%b0-%d0%bf%d1%96%d0%b4-%d0%b7%d0%b0%d0%b3%d1%80%d0%be%d0%b7%d0%be%d1%8e-%d0%93%d0%b0%d1%80%d1%8f%d1%87%d0%b5-%d0%bf/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 Jan 2012 08:17:27 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ozeukes.com/events/national-events/%d0%a3%d0%ba%d1%80%d0%b0%d1%97%d0%bd%d1%81%d1%8c%d0%ba%d0%b0-%d0%bc%d0%be%d0%b2%d0%b0-%d0%bf%d1%96%d0%b4-%d0%b7%d0%b0%d0%b3%d1%80%d0%be%d0%b7%d0%be%d1%8e-%d0%93%d0%b0%d1%80%d1%8f%d1%87%d0%b5-%d0%bf/</guid>
      <description>ЗБЕРЕЖІМО МАТУРУ З УКРАЇНСЬКОЇ МОВИ
Українська мова під загрозою виключення її, як предмета до матури (VCE/HSC /SACE) хібащо зможемо запевнити щонайменше 15 учнів річно в 2012, 2013 і 2014 рр. Як можете допомогти? Вписуйтеся на навчання, незалежно від віку.
Читайте далі&amp;hellip; Збережімо матуру з української мови</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>LOTE Ukrainian in danger</title>
      <link>https://ozeukes.com/events/national-events/lote-ukrainian-in-danger/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 Jan 2012 08:06:07 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ozeukes.com/events/national-events/lote-ukrainian-in-danger/</guid>
      <description>Ukrainian as a registered year 11 &amp;amp; 12 subject will be suspended unless enrolments for 2013 &amp;amp; 2014 increase. What can you do about it? Enrol now - age no barrier.
Read more Save LOTE Ukrainian</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Вшанування жертв Голодомору – Сідней, Австралія</title>
      <link>https://ozeukes.com/events/new-south-wales/commemorating-the-holodomor-victims-sydney-australia/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 Nov 2011 05:33:16 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ozeukes.com/events/new-south-wales/commemorating-the-holodomor-victims-sydney-australia/</guid>
      <description>МAРІЧКA ГAЛAБУРДA-ЧИГРИН
 Українська спільнота в Cіднеї віддала в неділю** 27.1****1.** (листопада) 2011 р., шану жертвам Голодомору 1932-1933 років.
Ранком в Українській Кaтолицькій Церкві ім св. Aндрія отець Парох Cимон Цькуй і отець Ждан Коломиєць відправили Cлужбу Божу, після чого отець Cимон очолив колону, в яку входили - свідок Голодомору пані Домна Даців, отці, преподобні сестри Василіянки члени Управи Об’єднання Українських Громад, члени осередку CУМ- у, жінки різних відділів Cоюзу Українок, Громади Кабрамата – Ферфілд, члени церковного хору, жінки Ліги Кaтолицьких жінок й молодь вкопали в землю перед церквою 33 чорних прапорів, які там будуть ще кілька днів.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Лінки до сайтів про роковини Голодомору / Links to sites about Holodomor commemoration events</title>
      <link>https://ozeukes.com/events/international-events/links-to-sites-about-holodomor-commemoration-events/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 Nov 2011 05:24:26 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ozeukes.com/events/international-events/links-to-sites-about-holodomor-commemoration-events/</guid>
      <description>Подаємо лінки до новинні тексти, відео та фото-репортажі про роковини Голодомору (Links to recent reports, videos and photographs about Holodomor commemoration events):
 На сторінці Центру досліджень визвольного руху
 http://www.cdvr.org.ua/content/5-%D1%82%D0%B8%D1%81%D1%8F%D1%87-%D0%BA%D0%B8%D1%8F%D0%BD-%D0%B2%D1%88%D0%B0%D0%BD%D1%83%D0%B2%D0%B0%D0%BB%D0%B8-%D0%B7%D0%B0%D0%B3%D0%B8%D0%B1%D0%BB%D0%B8%D1%85-%D0%B2%D1%96%D0%B4-%D0%B3%D0%BE%D0%BB%D0%BE%D0%B4%D1%83-%D0%B4%D1%96%D1%82%D0%B5%D0%B9
 Олеся Ісаюк. Дві пам&#39;яті.
 http://lb.ua/blog/isayuk_olesya/125669_dvi_pamyati.html
 Володимир В&#39;ятрович. Втрачені
 http://lb.ua/blog/isayuk_olesya/125669_dvi_pamyati.html Іван Вакарчук. Пам&#39;яті жертв Голодомору
 http://tsn.ua/analitika/pam-yati-zhertv-golodomoru-1932-1933-rokiv-v-ukrayini.html
 Ігор Дерев&#39;яний. Голодомор та Європа: уроки демократії
 http://www.unian.net/ukr/news/news-470468.html
 Олександр Ярмола. Українцям не було потрібне примусове залучення до радянського концтабору</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Hon Matthew Guy on the Ukrainian Holodomor</title>
      <link>https://ozeukes.com/politics/the-hon-matthew-guy-on-the-ukrainian-holodomor-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 26 Nov 2011 00:16:50 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ozeukes.com/politics/the-hon-matthew-guy-on-the-ukrainian-holodomor-2/</guid>
      <description>The Hon Matthew Guy on the occasion of the 78th Anniversary of the Ukrainian Holodomor  ** **Ukrainian Holodomor: commemoration
Hon. M. J. GUY (Minister for Planning) —
 Saturday, 26 November, will mark the 78th anniversary of the Ukrainian Holodomor, or famine, of 1932–33, and it will be the day that Ukrainians around the world will remember the victims of the Ukrainian genocide of that era. This was the most extensive and heinous crime the totalitarian Soviet regime perpetrated against Ukrainians and the Ukrainian nation.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Заклик CКУ до річниці Голодомору / UWC Statement on the anniversary of the Holodomor</title>
      <link>https://ozeukes.com/events/international-events/uwc-statement-on-the-anniversa/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Nov 2011 06:33:26 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ozeukes.com/events/international-events/uwc-statement-on-the-anniversa/</guid>
      <description>Cвітовий Конґреc Укрaїнців (СКУ) подав заклик з нагоди 78-ої річниці Голодомору 1932-33 рр. в Україні. Текст заклику в українські мові можна прочитати тут: Nov 16 2011 PR Holodomor Zaklyk SKU (Ukr )  The Ukrainian World Congress (UWC) has issued a statement on the occasion of the 78th anniversary of the Holodomor of 1932-33. The English-language version of the statement can be read here: Nov 16 2011 PR Holodomor Zaklyk SKU (Eng)</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Interview about the Great Famine in Ukraine / Інтерв&#39;ю про Великий Голод в Україні</title>
      <link>https://ozeukes.com/community/interview-about-the-great-famine-in-ukraine/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Nov 2011 04:12:47 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ozeukes.com/community/interview-about-the-great-famine-in-ukraine/</guid>
      <description>THE GREAT FAMINE IN UKRAINE (1932-1933 ) AND UKRAINE TODAY
An interview on SBS Radio with Professor Iurii Shapoval. Dr Shapoval is the Head of the I. F. Kuras Institute of Political and Ethno-National Research, National Academy of Sciences of Ukraine, and the author, co-author and editor of numerous books and collections of documents, many of them concerned with the crimes of Stalin’s regime.  ПРО ВЕЛИКИЙ ГОЛОД В УКРАЇНІ ТА ПРО УКРАЇНУ СЬОГОДНІШНЮ&amp;hellip;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tymoshenko Verdict - Letter to Australian Opposition</title>
      <link>https://ozeukes.com/politics/tymoshenko-verdict-letter-to-australian-opposition/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Oct 2011 10:42:56 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ozeukes.com/politics/tymoshenko-verdict-letter-to-australian-opposition/</guid>
      <description>Further to the correspondence between the Australian Federation of Ukrainian Organisations(AFUO) and the Australian Government, the AFUO has now written a letter to the Australian opposition coalition requesting that they add their voice to the world-wide condemnation regarding the initial politically-motivated arrest and subsequent conviction and sentence of the Ukrainian opposition leader, Yulia Tymoshenko. The text of the letter can be read here: Julie Bishop Tymoshenko doc</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ДЕРЖАВНИЙ KOMITET TEЛEБAЧEННЯ TA PAДIOМOВЛEННЯ YКPAЇНИ</title>
      <link>https://ozeukes.com/media/%d0%94%d0%95%d0%a0%d0%96%d0%90%d0%92%d0%9d%d0%98%d0%99-komitet-te%d0%9be%d0%91a%d0%a7e%d0%9d%d0%9d%d0%af-ta-pa%d0%94io%d0%9co%d0%92%d0%9be%d0%9d%d0%9d%d0%af-y%d0%9apa%d0%87%d0%9d%d0%98/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Oct 2011 23:47:16 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ozeukes.com/media/%d0%94%d0%95%d0%a0%d0%96%d0%90%d0%92%d0%9d%d0%98%d0%99-komitet-te%d0%9be%d0%91a%d0%a7e%d0%9d%d0%9d%d0%af-ta-pa%d0%94io%d0%9co%d0%92%d0%9be%d0%9d%d0%9d%d0%af-y%d0%9apa%d0%87%d0%9d%d0%98/</guid>
      <description>Державний Кomiтeт Тeлeбaчeння тa Рaдioмoвлeння Укpaїни переслав листа на руки Стефана Романіва (голова Союзу Українських Організацій Австралії). В цьому листі висловлюється подяка за підтримку та пояснення відносно завданням та твopчовиpo6ничої діяльности Головної peдaкції мовлення yкpaїнcькoю мовoю ТО «Bcecвітня cлyж6a paдioмoвдeння України».
Текст листа можна прочитати тут: Vsevitneradio 20111015</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Court Verdict on Tymoshenko - Letter to Foreign Minister Rudd</title>
      <link>https://ozeukes.com/current-affairs/court-verdict-on-tymoshenko-letter-to-foreign-minister-rudd/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Oct 2011 14:06:14 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ozeukes.com/current-affairs/court-verdict-on-tymoshenko-letter-to-foreign-minister-rudd/</guid>
      <description>October 11, 2001
** **** **
The Hon Kevin Rudd
Minister for Foreign Affairs
**Parliament House **
Canberra 2600
Dear Minister,
The Australian Federation of Ukrainian Organisations (AFUO) draws your attention to the verdict handed down this evening, Tuesday October 11, 2011, (Australian Time) by the Pechersky Court in Kyiv in the trial against former Prime Minister of Ukraine, Yulia Tymoshenko.
The court sentenced Tymoshenko to seven years&amp;rsquo; incarceration and a 3 year ban from holding public office.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>АВСТРАЛІЙСЬКІ УКРАЇНЦІ ПРО ПРЕЗИДЕНТА ТА УРЯД В УКРАЇНІ</title>
      <link>https://ozeukes.com/current-affairs/%d0%90%d0%92%d0%a1%d0%a2%d0%a0%d0%90%d0%9b%d0%86%d0%99%d0%a1%d0%ac%d0%9a%d0%86-%d0%a3%d0%9a%d0%a0%d0%90%d0%87%d0%9d%d0%a6%d0%86-%d0%9f%d0%a0%d0%9e-%d0%9f%d0%a0%d0%95%d0%97%d0%98%d0%94%d0%95%d0%9d/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Aug 2011 06:37:17 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ozeukes.com/current-affairs/%d0%90%d0%92%d0%a1%d0%a2%d0%a0%d0%90%d0%9b%d0%86%d0%99%d0%a1%d0%ac%d0%9a%d0%86-%d0%a3%d0%9a%d0%a0%d0%90%d0%87%d0%9d%d0%a6%d0%86-%d0%9f%d0%a0%d0%9e-%d0%9f%d0%a0%d0%95%d0%97%d0%98%d0%94%d0%95%d0%9d/</guid>
      <description>Інтерв&#39;ю з Маріяном Ткачуком, заступником голови СУОА і директором референтури зовнішніх зв&#39;язків - Союз Українських Організацій Австралії. http://www.sbs.com.au/yourlanguage/ukrainian/highlight/page/id/183202/t/AUSTRALIAN-UKRAINIANS-ABOUT-THE-PRESIDENT-AND-THE-GOVERNMENT-IN-UKRAINE</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>AUSTRALIAN GOVERNMENT ON TYMOSHENKO TRIAL AND ARREST</title>
      <link>https://ozeukes.com/current-affairs/australian-government-on-tymoshenko-trial-and-arrest/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Aug 2011 04:02:14 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ozeukes.com/current-affairs/australian-government-on-tymoshenko-trial-and-arrest/</guid>
      <description>MEDIA RELEASE August 15, 2011
AUSTRALIAN GOVERNMENT RELAYS ITS CONCERNS TO UKRAINIAN GOVERNMENT ON TYMOSHENKO TRIAL AND ARREST  The Australian Government has joined other members of the international community in expressing concern at the political manoeuvres in Ukraine involving the arrest of Yulia Tymoshenko, former Prime Minister of Ukraine.
In discussions with Office of the Minister of Foreign Affairs Kevin Rudd the Australian Federation of Ukrainian Organisations (AFUO) was informed that the Australian Government is deeply concerned with the current situation around the court proceedings and arrest of former Prime Minister of Ukraine Yulia Tymoshenko.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Open Appeal to the Government of Ukraine</title>
      <link>https://ozeukes.com/events/international-events/open-appeal-to-the-government-of-ukraine/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Jul 2011 12:53:43 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ozeukes.com/events/international-events/open-appeal-to-the-government-of-ukraine/</guid>
      <description>Please read and sign the &amp;ldquo;Open Appeal to the Government of Ukraine&amp;rdquo;. Add your name to the Open Appeal by going to http://www.lucorg.com/signature.php?signature_id=9  The Open Appeal with all signatures will be transmitted to the Government of Ukraine and to the Government of Canada.
The Open Appeal is an initiative of the Canadian Conference in Support of Ukraine (CCSU) and is supported by the Ukrainian Canadian Congress (UCC).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Commemoration of 25th anniversary of Chornobyl</title>
      <link>https://ozeukes.com/events/commemoration-of-25th-anniversary-of-chornobyl/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Apr 2011 03:34:02 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ozeukes.com/events/commemoration-of-25th-anniversary-of-chornobyl/</guid>
      <description>AUV Branch and Parish Council of Noble Park cordially invite you to a commemoration of the
25th anniversary of the Chornobyl disaster
Tuesday** 26.4.11**
Ukrainian Community Centre, 26 Chandler Rd.** Noble Park**
Program:
11 am – Holy Liturgy for the victims of Chornobyl,
12 pm – Easter lunch
12.30 pm – Eyewitness accounts by people from the Chornobyl zone
Film about Chornobyl (Ukrainian/Russian, with English subtitles).
Please bring a plate of food to share.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ЧОРНОБИЛЬ 1986 - Деякі Факти</title>
      <link>https://ozeukes.com/current-affairs/chornobyl-1986-facts/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Apr 2011 06:33:14 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ozeukes.com/current-affairs/chornobyl-1986-facts/</guid>
      <description>ЧОРНОБИЛЬ 1986 - Деякі Факти
** **
** **
 * ** **В ніч, з 25–го на 26–те квітня, приблизно о першій годині 24 хвилини, на ЧАЕС вибухнув реактор четвертого енергоблоку, що поблизу селища Припять – 18 км від міста Чорнобиль, 16 км від границі з Білорусією та 110 км від Києва. Вибух повністю розрушив реактор. * Безпосередньо під час вибуху загинула тільки одна особа – оператор Валерій Ходемчук. Тіла не знайдено, завалено під обломками двох 130–тонних барабан –сепараторів.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>AUSTRALIAN OPEN 2011 – DOLGOPOLOV GOES DOWN FIGHTING</title>
      <link>https://ozeukes.com/events/australian-open-2011-%e2%80%93-dolgopolov-goes-down-fighting/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Jan 2011 23:56:17 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ozeukes.com/events/australian-open-2011-%e2%80%93-dolgopolov-goes-down-fighting/</guid>
      <description>As Alexandr Dolgopolov prepared himself for the biggest match of his life, hopes were held high for him to deliver a shock blow to 5th seeded Andy Murray, in their Quarter Final clash.
The match opened with ‘the most unpredictable player on the tour’ immediately forcing several back-to-back, break points against the heavily backed Scotsman. In true form, Murray overcame his initial quarter final jitters and proceeded to take both the first and second sets respectively, 7-5, 6-3.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Лист Протесту до Російського Посольства в Австралії відносно Знущання Українців у Росії</title>
      <link>https://ozeukes.com/current-affairs/%d0%9b%d0%b8%d1%81%d1%82-%d0%9f%d1%80%d0%be%d1%82%d0%b5%d1%81%d1%82%d1%83-%d0%b4%d0%be-%d0%a0%d0%be%d1%81%d1%96%d0%b9%d1%81%d1%8c%d0%ba%d0%be%d0%b3%d0%be-%d0%9f%d0%be%d1%81%d0%be%d0%bb%d1%8c%d1%81/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Dec 2010 09:27:41 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ozeukes.com/current-affairs/%d0%9b%d0%b8%d1%81%d1%82-%d0%9f%d1%80%d0%be%d1%82%d0%b5%d1%81%d1%82%d1%83-%d0%b4%d0%be-%d0%a0%d0%be%d1%81%d1%96%d0%b9%d1%81%d1%8c%d0%ba%d0%be%d0%b3%d0%be-%d0%9f%d0%be%d1%81%d0%be%d0%bb%d1%8c%d1%81/</guid>
      <description>26-грудня 2010
Володимир Морозов Надзвичайний і Повноважний Посол Посольство Російської Федерації 78 Канберра Авеню Ґріффіт ACT 2603
Високоповажний пане Посол!
Cоюз Українських Організацій Aвстралії (СУОА) висловлює занепокоєння та звертається до Вас, як представника Російської Федерації в Австралії, з протестом з причини найновіших порушень національних і людських прав урядом Вашої країни до українців, що проживають у Росії.
Українська громадськість Австралії шокована щодо способів трактування українців, як національної меншини, а зокрема агітацією та тиском на обмеження національних прав української громади в Росії.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Letter of Protest to the Russian Embassy in Australia on the Treatment of Ukrainians in Russia</title>
      <link>https://ozeukes.com/current-affairs/letter-of-protest-to-the-russian-embassy-in-australia-on-the-treatment-of-ukrainians-in-russia/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Dec 2010 09:27:10 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ozeukes.com/current-affairs/letter-of-protest-to-the-russian-embassy-in-australia-on-the-treatment-of-ukrainians-in-russia/</guid>
      <description>December 26, 2010
His Excellency Mr Vladimir Morozov Ambassador Extraordinary and Plenipotentiary Embassy of the Russian Federation 78 Canberra Avenue Griffith ACT 2603
Your Excellency
The Australian Federation of Ukrainian Organisations (AFUO) writes to you as the representative of the Russian Federation in Australia to protest in the strongest terms the current violation of national rights of Ukrainians in Russia by your Government.
Australia&#39;s Ukrainian community is shocked at the treatment of Ukrainians as a minority in Russia.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>CALL TO ACTION - NATIONAL RALLY - CANBERRA - Saturday February 19 2011</title>
      <link>https://ozeukes.com/events/national-events/call-to-action-national-rally-canberra-saturday-february-19-2011/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Dec 2010 00:19:53 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ozeukes.com/events/national-events/call-to-action-national-rally-canberra-saturday-february-19-2011/</guid>
      <description>[](http://www.ozeukes.com/wp-content/uploads/2010/12/CYOA-logo.png)[](http://www.ozeukes.com/wp-content/uploads/2010/12/CYOA-logo1.png)[![](http://www.ozeukes.com/wp-content/uploads/2010/12/CYOA-logo-50pc1.jpg) ](http://www.ozeukes.com/wp-content/uploads/2010/12/CYOA-logo-50pc1.jpg) AUSTRALIAN FEDERATION OF UKRAINIAN ORGANISATIONS
 CALL TO ACTION
NATIONAL RALLY - CANBERRA****
Saturday February 19, 2011
Commencing at 11.00am
** **
[](http://www.ozeukes.com/wp-content/uploads/2010/12/CYOA-logo-50pc.jpg)TIME FOR AUSTRALIA&#39;S UKRAINIAN COMMUNITY AND ITS SUPPORTERS
TO SEND A MESSAGE OF NO CONFIDENCE IN UKRAINE&#39;S CURRENT LEADERSHIP
and
 A MESSAGE OF SUPPORT FOR THE UKRAINIAN PEOPLE and minorities Ukraine who want to build a strong, national, economically and socially sound Ukraine
Proposed program</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Надзвичайний подвиг у Харкові - Відео / An Extraordinary Act of Bravery in Kharkiv - Video</title>
      <link>https://ozeukes.com/current-affairs/%d0%9d%d0%b0%d0%b4%d0%b7%d0%b2%d0%b8%d1%87%d0%b0%d0%b9%d0%bd%d0%b8%d0%b9-%d0%bf%d0%be%d0%b4%d0%b2%d0%b8%d0%b3-%d1%83-%d0%a5%d0%b0%d1%80%d0%ba%d0%be%d0%b2%d1%96-%d0%92%d1%96%d0%b4%d0%b5%d0%be-an-ex/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Dec 2010 23:44:22 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ozeukes.com/current-affairs/%d0%9d%d0%b0%d0%b4%d0%b7%d0%b2%d0%b8%d1%87%d0%b0%d0%b9%d0%bd%d0%b8%d0%b9-%d0%bf%d0%be%d0%b4%d0%b2%d0%b8%d0%b3-%d1%83-%d0%a5%d0%b0%d1%80%d0%ba%d0%be%d0%b2%d1%96-%d0%92%d1%96%d0%b4%d0%b5%d0%be-an-ex/</guid>
      <description>Молода українка, Надія Савинська, виступяє в автобусі у Харкові про потребу українцям вивчити свою рідну мову. Вона цитує Тараса Шевченко, навпроті критики пасажирів, щоб підкреслити що кожний має право вивчити інші мови, але не повинен забути свою рідну мову.
 A young Ukrainian woman, Nadia Savynska, speaks out in a bus in Kharkiv, Ukraine, about the need for Ukrainians to learn their native language. She quotes Taras Shevchenko, in the face of criticisms by fellow bus passengers, to make the point that one should learn other languages, but not forget their own.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Letter of Congratulations from Ukrainian Community to Matthew Guy</title>
      <link>https://ozeukes.com/current-affairs/letter-of-congratulations-from-ukrainian-community-to-matthew-guy/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Dec 2010 11:38:21 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ozeukes.com/current-affairs/letter-of-congratulations-from-ukrainian-community-to-matthew-guy/</guid>
      <description>December 2, 2010
The Hon Matthew Guy
Minister for Planning
**C/- Parliament House **
**Spring Street **
Melbourne 3000
Dear Minister,
The Australian Federation of Ukrainian Organisations (AFUO) extends its congratulations to the Liberal Coalition on its victory in the Victorian State Elections on November 27, 2010.
The AFUO also congratulates and salutes you for your appointment as Minister for Planning in the new Baillieu Cabinet.
Australia&#39;s Ukrainian community is proud of the fact that a Victorian of Ukrainian background has achieved such high office.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Aкція Cвічка Моління в Aвстралії та вшанування жертв Голодомору – Ґеноциду</title>
      <link>https://ozeukes.com/events/a%d0%ba%d1%86%d1%96%d1%8f-c%d0%b2%d1%96%d1%87%d0%ba%d0%b0-%d0%9c%d0%be%d0%bb%d1%96%d0%bd%d0%bd%d1%8f-%d0%b2-a%d0%b2%d1%81%d1%82%d1%80%d0%b0%d0%bb%d1%96%d1%97-%d1%82%d0%b0-%d0%b2%d1%88%d0%b0%d0%bd/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Nov 2010 03:27:16 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ozeukes.com/events/a%d0%ba%d1%86%d1%96%d1%8f-c%d0%b2%d1%96%d1%87%d0%ba%d0%b0-%d0%9c%d0%be%d0%bb%d1%96%d0%bd%d0%bd%d1%8f-%d0%b2-a%d0%b2%d1%81%d1%82%d1%80%d0%b0%d0%bb%d1%96%d1%97-%d1%82%d0%b0-%d0%b2%d1%88%d0%b0%d0%bd/</guid>
      <description>[](http://www.ozeukes.com/wp-content/uploads/2010/11/loho_golodomor.jpg)[](http://www.ozeukes.com/wp-content/uploads/2010/11/loho_golodomor-85pc.jpg)[](http://www.ozeukes.com/wp-content/uploads/2010/11/loho_golodomor-85pc1.jpg)[](http://www.ozeukes.com/wp-content/uploads/2010/11/loho_golodomor-50pc.jpg)
[](http://www.ozeukes.com/wp-content/uploads/2010/11/loho_golodomor-40pc.jpg)
** **
** **
** **
** **
** **
** **
** **
** **
** **
Подається ** **інформації про програму віздначень Голодомору в Австралії. Акції вшанування жертв Голодомору включають передачі Свічки Моління, відправ соборних Панахид, мистецькі виставки та висвітлення фільму &amp;ldquo;Окрадена Земля&amp;rdquo;.
неділя 21-го листопада 2010
_CУМ Оселя Карпати - Вікторія _Запалення Cвічки моління Виступ Голови МКК CКУ по Голодомору Cтефана Романіва Передача свічки з участю проводів та членства Української Громади Вікторії, CУМу, Пласту (Мельборн і Джілонґ) шкільництва та ширшого громадянства - год 10.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Petition to Ukraine&#39;s President Victor Yanukovych</title>
      <link>https://ozeukes.com/events/petition-to-ukraines-president-victor-yanukovych/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Nov 2010 00:53:06 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ozeukes.com/events/petition-to-ukraines-president-victor-yanukovych/</guid>
      <description>The Ukrainian World Congress (UWC) calls upon all people of good will to sign a petition to the President of Ukraine demanding his public recognition of the Holodomor of 1932-33 as an act of genocide against the Ukrainian people.
Sign the petition today!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Петиція до президента України Віктора Януковича</title>
      <link>https://ozeukes.com/events/%d0%9f%d0%b5%d1%82%d0%b8%d1%86%d1%96%d1%8f-%d0%b4%d0%be-%d0%bf%d1%80%d0%b5%d0%b7%d0%b8%d0%b4%d0%b5%d0%bd%d1%82%d0%b0-%d0%a3%d0%ba%d1%80%d0%b0%d1%97%d0%bd%d0%b8-%d0%92%d1%96%d0%ba%d1%82%d0%be%d1%80/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Nov 2010 00:52:27 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ozeukes.com/events/%d0%9f%d0%b5%d1%82%d0%b8%d1%86%d1%96%d1%8f-%d0%b4%d0%be-%d0%bf%d1%80%d0%b5%d0%b7%d0%b8%d0%b4%d0%b5%d0%bd%d1%82%d0%b0-%d0%a3%d0%ba%d1%80%d0%b0%d1%97%d0%bd%d0%b8-%d0%92%d1%96%d0%ba%d1%82%d0%be%d1%80/</guid>
      <description>[](http://www.ozeukes.com/wp-content/uploads/2010/11/holodomor_b_en2.jpg)[![](http://www.ozeukes.com/wp-content/uploads/2010/11/holodomor_b_ua.jpg) ](http://www.ozeukes.com/wp-content/uploads/2010/11/holodomor_b_ua.jpg)Світовий Конґрес Українців (СКУ) звертається до всіх людей доброї волі підписати петицію до президента України відносно визнання Голодомору 1932-33 років яко ґеноцидом українського народу.
Підпишіть петицію сьогодні!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Лист до Президента Януковича</title>
      <link>https://ozeukes.com/politics/%d0%9b%d0%b8%d1%81%d1%82-%d0%b4%d0%be-%d0%9f%d1%80%d0%b5%d0%b7%d0%b8%d0%b4%d0%b5%d0%bd%d1%82%d0%b0-%d0%af%d0%bd%d1%83%d0%ba%d0%be%d0%b2%d0%b8%d1%87%d0%b0/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Nov 2010 11:14:48 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ozeukes.com/politics/%d0%9b%d0%b8%d1%81%d1%82-%d0%b4%d0%be-%d0%9f%d1%80%d0%b5%d0%b7%d0%b8%d0%b4%d0%b5%d0%bd%d1%82%d0%b0-%d0%af%d0%bd%d1%83%d0%ba%d0%be%d0%b2%d0%b8%d1%87%d0%b0/</guid>
      <description>20-го листопада 2010
Президенту України Віктору Федоровичу Януковичу Київ, Україна
Пане Президенте!
Українська громадськість Австралії висловлює своє глибоке обурення з приводу демонтування пам’ятної дошки, встановленої на честь Патріарха УГКЦ Йосифа Cліпого у Харкові і закликає Вас негайно засудити цей вчинок та вимагати повернення дошки на своє місце.
Святійший Патріярх Йосиф у 1961 році потрапив на Слобожанщину мимоволі, коли його етапом переправляли з Галичини до мордовських таборів. На цьому довгому шляху його помістили до так званого «Тюремного замку» — пересильної в’язниці по вулиці Малиновського, 5, де він пробув кілька тижнів.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Вірш та інформації про Голодомор</title>
      <link>https://ozeukes.com/community/%d0%92%d1%96%d1%80%d1%88-%d1%82%d0%b0-%d1%96%d0%bd%d1%84%d0%be%d1%80%d0%bc%d0%b0%d1%86%d1%96%d1%97-%d0%bf%d1%80%d0%be-%d0%93%d0%be%d0%bb%d0%be%d0%b4%d0%be%d0%bc%d0%be%d1%80/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Nov 2010 08:00:05 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ozeukes.com/community/%d0%92%d1%96%d1%80%d1%88-%d1%82%d0%b0-%d1%96%d0%bd%d1%84%d0%be%d1%80%d0%bc%d0%b0%d1%86%d1%96%d1%97-%d0%bf%d1%80%d0%be-%d0%93%d0%be%d0%bb%d0%be%d0%b4%d0%be%d0%bc%d0%be%d1%80/</guid>
      <description>Полум’я скорботи
На підвіконні палахтить Скорботи полум’я священне – То свічка пам’яті горить За всіх безвинно убієнних.
Мій розум навіть не збагне Страшної люті сталінізму, Що катував своїх людей, Це ще жахливіше фашизму!
Моя бабуся, сирота, Мені колись розповідала, Як батька з матір’ю вона В свої шість років поховала:
„Забрали з хати геть усе, Зернину кожну вигрібали&amp;hellip; І на морозі крижанім Водою неньку обливали.
Вона зізнатись не могла, Де порятунок заховала – Торбинку з житом і вівсом Для діток в землю закопала.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Фонд Демократичні Ініціятиви Україна у Фокусі</title>
      <link>https://ozeukes.com/politics/democratic-initiatives-foundation-report-focus-on-ukraine-ukrainian-version/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 Oct 2010 10:35:17 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ozeukes.com/politics/democratic-initiatives-foundation-report-focus-on-ukraine-ukrainian-version/</guid>
      <description>Download full report – Focus on Ukraine September 27 – October 1, 2010 - Ukrainian Version</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Democratic Initiatives Foundation Report - Focus on Ukraine </title>
      <link>https://ozeukes.com/politics/democratic-initiatives-foundation-report-focus-on-ukraine/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 Oct 2010 10:31:01 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ozeukes.com/politics/democratic-initiatives-foundation-report-focus-on-ukraine/</guid>
      <description>Download full report - Focus on Ukraine September 27 - October 1, 2010</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Press Freedom in Ukraine: Temptation to Control</title>
      <link>https://ozeukes.com/politics/press-freedom-in-ukraine-temptation-to-control/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Sep 2010 01:06:58 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ozeukes.com/politics/press-freedom-in-ukraine-temptation-to-control/</guid>
      <description>Report by Jean-François Julliard and Elsa Vidal - August 2010
It met national and local media representatives, members of press freedom NGOs (Stop Censorship, Telekritika, SNUJ and IMI), ruling party and opposition parliamentarians and representatives of the prosecutor-general’s office.
At the end of this initial visit, Reporters Without Borders gave a news conference in Kiev on 21 July at which it announced its provisional findings and its recommendations to the authorities.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Australian Ambassador Responsible for Ukraine and AFUO Chairman Meet in Kyiv</title>
      <link>https://ozeukes.com/current-affairs/media-release-10th-august/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Aug 2010 19:26:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ozeukes.com/current-affairs/media-release-10th-august/</guid>
      <description>Strengthening economic, cultural sporting and educational ties between Australia and Ukraine were some of the topics discussed at a dinner meeting in Kyiv on Monday August 9, 2010 between Australian Government representatives and the Australian Federation of Ukrainian Organisations (AFUO) .The dinner was hosted by Ukraine Australia House headed by Halyna Lemets and her staff. Attendees were the Australian Ambassador to Austria - Michael Potts who now has responsibility for Ukraine , Consul for Ukraine Paul Addison , Australian Trade Commission- Senior Trade Commissioner - Dan Tebbutt , Elizabeth Jaquemar - Senior Bilateral Relations and Public Affairs Officer - Australian Embassy in Vienna and the Chairman of the Australian Federation of Ukrainian Organisations - Stefan Romaniw and UAH representatives .</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Plenary Meeting Underway</title>
      <link>https://ozeukes.com/community/plenary-meeting-underway/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 25 Jun 2010 13:43:42 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ozeukes.com/community/plenary-meeting-underway/</guid>
      <description>Ukrainian Community - A Road Map for the Future The goal of this plenary meeting is to gather together Ukrainian Organisational Leaders from around Australia to discuss and identify national and local plans and strategies for community development.
The meeting opened at approximately 9.30 and is progressing well.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rev. Dr Borys Gudziak Forthcoming Australian Visit</title>
      <link>https://ozeukes.com/current-affairs/dr-borys-gudziak-visit/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Jun 2010 13:42:04 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ozeukes.com/current-affairs/dr-borys-gudziak-visit/</guid>
      <description>I am sure that by now you have all heard of the forthcoming visit to Australia by the Rector of the Ukrainian Catholic University in Lviv, Rev. Dr Borys Gudziak whose firm and instant reaction to attempts of the SBU (acting for the new regime) to intimidate him and threaten criminal action against the University students who participate in any form of anti government demonstrations, has reverberated through serious media around the world.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Stefan Romaniw Interviewed on &#34;Unian&#34;</title>
      <link>https://ozeukes.com/current-affairs/unian-interview/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Jun 2010 17:55:42 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ozeukes.com/current-affairs/unian-interview/</guid>
      <description>Read the full interview with Stefan Romaniw on &amp;ldquo;Unian&amp;rdquo;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Stefan Romaniw Interviewed on “The Ukrainian Week”</title>
      <link>https://ozeukes.com/current-affairs/stefan-romaniw-interviewed-on-the-ukrainian-week/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Jun 2010 17:32:17 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ozeukes.com/current-affairs/stefan-romaniw-interviewed-on-the-ukrainian-week/</guid>
      <description>Read the full interview at &amp;ldquo;The Ukrainian Week&amp;rdquo;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Holodomor International Activity - Breaking News</title>
      <link>https://ozeukes.com/politics/holodomor-international-activity-breaking-news/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 May 2010 15:46:10 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ozeukes.com/politics/holodomor-international-activity-breaking-news/</guid>
      <description>The Ukrainian World Congress Holodomor Committee in cooperation with Ukraine&#39;s Institute of Memory announced the official launch of the International Candle of Prayer Activity on June 19, in Kyiv. A candle for each oblast and country where Ukraine resides will be blessed and passed on. This candle should travel the different denominations and churches over the June - Nov period highlighting the millions that perished becks of Stalin&#39;s famine. The Council of Churches have signed a statement acknowledging the Holodomor as an act against humanity .</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ukrainians in Australia Call on President Yanukovych to Provide Leadership</title>
      <link>https://ozeukes.com/politics/ukrainians-in-australia-call-on-president-yanukovych-to-provide-leadership/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 May 2010 15:40:55 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ozeukes.com/politics/ukrainians-in-australia-call-on-president-yanukovych-to-provide-leadership/</guid>
      <description>The AFUO has written an open letter to Ukraine&#39;s President Viktor Yanukovych expressing Australian Ukrainians&amp;rsquo; dismay with the many anti-Ukrainian - pro-Russian positions being taken by him and his Government
 * The signing of Black Sea Fleet Accord * The Europe parliaments intrusion in Ukraine&#39;s affairs on the Bandera issue * The anti constitutional activity of the Government * President&#39;s statement of retractions on the Holodomor as being not an act of Genocide  amongst others.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>