<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>#FreeSavchenko on AFUO - СУОА</title>
    <link>https://ozeukes.com/tags/#freesavchenko/</link>
    <description>Recent content in #FreeSavchenko on AFUO - СУОА</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 10 Mar 2016 05:19:19 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://ozeukes.com/tags/#freesavchenko/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Australian Labor Media Release - RUSSIA AND THE MINSK AGREEMENT</title>
      <link>https://ozeukes.com/politics/australian-labor-media-release-russia-and-the-minsk-agreement/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Mar 2016 05:19:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ozeukes.com/politics/australian-labor-media-release-russia-and-the-minsk-agreement/</guid>
      <description>THE HON BILL SHORTEN MP LEADER OF THE OPPOSITION MEMBER FOR MARIBYRNONG
** **THE HON TANYA PLIBERSEK MP DEPUTY LEADER OF THE OPPOSITION SHADOW MINISTER FOR FOREIGN AFFAIRS AND INTERNATIONAL DEVELOPMENT MEMBER FOR SYDNEY
RUSSIA AND THE MINSK AGREEMENT Labor is deeply troubled by Russia’s failure to release hostages and illegally detained people in accordance with the terms of the Minsk Agreement signed over a year ago.
This includes the prominent Ukrainian pilot and member of the Ukrainian Parliament, Nadiya Savchenko, who Russia has held without trial for more than 18 months.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ukrainian community to hold Flash Mob Rally at Russian Embassy in Canberra</title>
      <link>https://ozeukes.com/politics/ukrainian-community-to-hold-flash-mob-rally-at-russian-embassy-in-canberra/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Mar 2016 21:00:51 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ozeukes.com/politics/ukrainian-community-to-hold-flash-mob-rally-at-russian-embassy-in-canberra/</guid>
      <description>**March 9, 2016 **
MEDIA RELEASE Ukrainian community to hold Flash Mob Rally at Russian Embassy Canberra demanding the release of Nadiya Savchenko #FreeSavchenko
The Australian Federation of Ukrainian Organisations (AFUO) will coordinate a small **Flash Mob Rally outside the Russian Embassy in Canberra –Wednesday March 9, 2016 at 10.45am ** to demand the release of former Ukrainian Air Force pilot, Nadiya Savchenko
The AFUO Chairman Stefan Romaniw will also endeavour to hand the Russian Ambassador Mr Vladimir Moroz or his staff a protest letter demanding:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Надія є! #FreeSavchenko! Заява Проводу ОУН (б)</title>
      <link>https://ozeukes.com/politics/freesavchenko-statement-by-ounb/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Mar 2016 20:57:09 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ozeukes.com/politics/freesavchenko-statement-by-ounb/</guid>
      <description>**Надія є! ****#**FreeSavchenko!
Для країн Заходу людське життя є найвищою цінністю. Так, зокрема під час бойових дій американський, німецький чи ізраїльський уряди готові на відчайдушні кроки, щоб визволити бранців, що перебувають в руках ворога. Україна, яка перебуває в стані війни, має не один десяток осіб, що перебувають в полоні російсько-терористичного режиму та їх маріонеток «днр-лнр». Савченко, Сенцов, Карпюк… Список наших громадян, незаконно ув’язнених в Росії, є набагато більшим, а отже поточна ціль української держави – в будь який спосіб визволити їх.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ukrainian community of Australia implores PM to demand the release of Nadiya Savchenko</title>
      <link>https://ozeukes.com/politics/ukrainian-community-of-australia-implores-pm-to-demand-the-release-of-nadiya-savchenko/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Mar 2016 10:58:08 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ozeukes.com/politics/ukrainian-community-of-australia-implores-pm-to-demand-the-release-of-nadiya-savchenko/</guid>
      <description>8 March 2016
Ukrainian community of Australia implores PM to demand the release of Nadiya Savchenko #FreeSavchenko
The Australian Federation of Ukrainian Organisations (AFUO) calls on the Australian government to demand the release of former Ukrainian Air Force pilot, Nadiya Savchenko, who faces 23 years of political imprisonment if found guilty by a Russian court.
The 34 year-old Member of Ukrainian Parliament and delegate to the Parliamentary Assembly of the Council of Europe in absentia, has been awaiting trial since being kidnapped and transported to Russia in 2014 by pro-Russian rebels.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>AUSTRALIA’S UKRAINIAN COMMUNITY CALL TO ACTION #FreeSavchenko</title>
      <link>https://ozeukes.com/politics/australias-ukrainian-community-call-to-action-freesavchenko/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 Mar 2016 05:50:03 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ozeukes.com/politics/australias-ukrainian-community-call-to-action-freesavchenko/</guid>
      <description>March 7,2016
AUSTRALIA’S UKRAINIAN COMMUNITY CALL TO ACTION #FreeSavchenko The Australian Federation of Ukrainian Organisations urges the international community, including human rights organisations and women’s organisations to demand the immediate release by Russian authorities of former Ukrainian Air Force pilot, Member of Ukrainian Parliament and delegate to the Parliamentary Assembly of the Council of Europe, Lieutenant Nadiya Savchenko, who remains imprisoned for political considerations.
The AFUO has called on the Prime Minister of Australia to make representation to PM Putin and the Minister for Foreign Affairs to make representation to the Embassy of the Russian Federation on Canberra demanding Savchenko’s immediate release and condemn this act of violation of human rights.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>