<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Kirrily Manning on AFUO - СУОА</title>
    <link>https://ozeukes.com/tags/kirrily-manning/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Kirrily Manning on AFUO - СУОА</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 06 Oct 2019 04:48:52 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://ozeukes.com/tags/kirrily-manning/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Development of OT in Ukraine is now apart of the Ukrainian Crisis Аppeal</title>
      <link>https://ozeukes.com/community/occupational-therapy-ukraine-crisis-appeal/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Oct 2019 04:48:52 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ozeukes.com/community/occupational-therapy-ukraine-crisis-appeal/</guid>
      <description>A few months ago, we introduced you to Kirrily Manning, an Australian Occupational Therapist (OT) playing a key role working to develop the OT profession in Ukraine. You can read more about her story here in English and here in Ukrainian. 
Throughout the years that Go Global, Ukraine ran at Curtin University (2009-2013) led by Kirrily, over 70 students from occupational therapy, speech therapy, physiotherapy and nutrition travelled to Ukraine.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Meet Kirrily: An OT working to help kids in Ukraine</title>
      <link>https://ozeukes.com/community/kirrily-help-ukraine/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 May 2019 10:45:31 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ozeukes.com/community/kirrily-help-ukraine/</guid>
      <description>Kirrily Manning is an Occupational Therapist (OT) who graduated from the University of South Australia in 1994. Kirrily currently teaches at both an undergraduate and masters level at the school of Occupational Therapy, Social Work and Speech Therapy within Curtin University.
In 2005, Kirrily started volunteer work, assisting children with disabilities in orphanages in Ukraine, later setting up a student international placement program for Curtin University. Go Global Ukraine facilitated Australian occupational therapy, physiotherapy and speech therapy students to work in these same orphanages with a focus on upskilling staff in therapeutic care practices.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>